<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Introduction on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Introduction on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) General introduction to the Pāñcarātra and previous scholarship thereon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/1_i_General_introduction_to_the_pAncharA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/1_i_General_introduction_to_the_pAncharA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pañcarātra&#34;&gt;Pañcarātra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘Pañcarātra’ or ‘Pāñcarātra’ is the name of a religious tradition which worships Viṣṇu, or a deity assimilated to Viṣṇu (especially Nārāyaṇa or Vāsudeva), as the highest god.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saṃhitā&#34;&gt;saṃhitā&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The names &lt;em&gt;pañcarātra&lt;/em&gt;/ &lt;em&gt;pāñcarātra&lt;/em&gt; are also used to refer to the large scriptural corpus consisting of anonymously authored works in Sanskrit, ordinarily called &lt;em&gt;saṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (“compendium”), that were produced by the followers of this tradition. Although the individual Saṃhitās cannot be dated with any precision, most of them appear to have been composed between the ninth and the fourteenth century of the Common Era.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) The role of scripture in the Pāñcarātra Saṃhitās</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/2_ii_The_role_of_scripture_in_the_pAncha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/2_ii_The_role_of_scripture_in_the_pAncha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past quarter of a century or so, several scholarly works in the field of Indian religions (see e.g. the contributions in Levering 1989, Timm 1992, and Patton 1994; see also Flood 1999, 2006, 2006a) have sought to redress a perceived imbalance in the broader discipline of “religious studies” – namely, the tendency among scholars to downplay the importance of scriptural traditions within religions, and of textual [[13]] studies within the academic study of religion. This tendency had, arguably, characterised a good deal of scholarship over the previous half century, and might itself be usefully interpreted as a corrective to the well-documented overemphasis on scriptural traditions that was initiated primarily by Protestant philologists during the nineteenth century. Timm (1992: 2) has summarised this initial shift in focus: Stationing themselves within the discipline of the “history of religions,” scholars dissatisfied with the limitations of the “textual” approach to the study of religion shifted the primary focus onto the so-called primitive or archaic forms of religious expression, downplaying the importance of the scriptural and commentarial traditions in favor of uncovering foundational categories and motifs through which they hoped to reveal the universal patterns and qualities of human religious expression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Sources and methods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/3_iii_Sources_and_methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/2_Introduction/3_iii_Sources_and_methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In S. Parampurushdas and S. Shrutiprakashdas’ &lt;em&gt;Catalogue of Pañcarātra Saṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(2002), 460 Pāñcarātra titles are named, of which 313 are of texts which are listed or mentioned in the Saṃhitās, but of which there is otherwise no record. According to this catalogue, there are 147 extant Pāñcarātra works, of which 112 remain unpublished. Many of these are incomplete, and some exist only in fragmentary form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the 35 published Saṃhitās listed, the &lt;em&gt;Agastyasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; is certainly not a Pāñcarātra text, as Smith (1975: 3-4) has already correctly pointed out, though it has been wrongly identified as one in the colophons of some of its South Indian manuscripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
