<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१ अर्थानुशासन-विभागः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१ अर्थानुशासन-विभागः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>०० गुरुपरम्परा-सारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/00_guruparamparA-sAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/00_guruparamparA-sAraH/</guid>
      <description>०० गुरुपरम्परा-सारः
Guruparampara Sara
At the very commencement of this great work, we find a chapter devoted to the fact of deep devotion towards the preceptor. This section has the subject matter of T44TT 45174 or obeisance unto the line of teachers and in the conclusion it is mentioned &amp;lsquo;गुरुपरम्परासारः संपूर्णः ।&amp;rsquo; This chapter is not included in the 32 chapters that are components of Sri Rahasyatraya Sara. Therefore, a doubt is raised about the inclusion of this chapter in this great work of Rahasyatraya Sara.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०१ उपोद्घाताधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/01_upodghAtAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/01_upodghAtAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER - I
Upodghathadhikara (or Introduction to the subject of the work)
In the Upodghathadhikara or the introductory chapter to this classic, containing thirty-two chapters, Vedantha Desika has pointed out the prime subject matter of this work and the purpose it would serve. An introduction is necessary for all kinds of works for evincing the interest of the disciples regarding the study of that subject. This introduction is like a motivation for the readers to know what exactly is proposed to be expounded in the main work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०२ सार-निष्कर्षाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/02_sAra-niShkarShAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/02_sAra-niShkarShAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>०२ सार-निष्कर्षाधिकारः
Saranishkarsbadhikara
CHAPTER - II
Saranishkarshadhikara (Determining the essentials to be imbibed)
After giving a general introduction to the work proposed to be written, the celebrated author describes in this section, what an aspirant should determine as the most essential thing to be followed. One has to choose the most essential object to be followed without wasting time and choose that which is most beneficial to him, after due deliberation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०३ प्रधान-प्रतितन्त्राधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/03_pradhAna-pratitantrAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/03_pradhAna-pratitantrAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>०३ प्रधान-प्रतितन्त्राधिकारः
Pradhana P-athithanthradhikara
CHAPTER - III
Pradhana Prathithanthradhikara (The unique doctrine of this School of Thought)
In the Saranishkarshadhikara, it was taught that the three Rahasyas are enshrining the ultimate truths of tatva, hita and purushartha and that an aspirant should endeavour to understand these truths as the quintessence of all the shasthras. In the following sections, these truths are elaborately described. Eight chapters are meant for enlightening the essential nature of the spiritual aspirant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०४ अर्थपञ्चकाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/04_arthapanchakAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/04_arthapanchakAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>Artha Panchakadhikara
IC 1.
CHAPTER - NV
Artha Panchakadhikara After expounding the unique doctrine of Body-Soul Relationship that is taught by the Upanishads, as an essential prerequisite for the doctrine of the means of surrender at the feet of the Lord, the five essential truths that also must be necessarily known by all, are taught in this section.
Desika describes that these essentials are taught in the three Rahasyas. The scripture mentions the essentials to be known in different ways such as, Isvara and Isithavya, Bhoktha-Bhogya-Preritha, one Supreme Brahman characterised by all other entities, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०५ तत्त्व-त्रयाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/05_tattva-trayAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/05_tattva-trayAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>०५ तत्त्व-त्रयाधिकारः
Tatvatrayadhikara
CHAPTER - V
Tatvatrayadhikara
Our Masters of yore have classified the categories in various ways, for making the disciples understand the truth clearly without any confusion. The different kinds of categorisation are not contradicting one another.
Categories The oneness of Paramatman characterised by the orders of the chetana and the achetana i.e. ????? is admitted by all. The difference and distinction between Brahman and the other two orders, is also admitted by all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०६ परदेवता-पारमार्थ्याधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/06_paradevatA-pAramArthyAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/06_paradevatA-pAramArthyAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>०६ परदेवता-पारमार्थ्याधिकारः
Paradevata Paramarthyadhikara
CHAPTER - VI
Paradevata Paramarthyadhikara
After having taught the nature of the three entities viz. Matter, Jivatman and Paramatman, in a general way, Desika has established in this chapter i.e. Paradevata Paramarthyadhikara, the nature of the particular deity which is the supreme reality. According to the teaching of the scriptures, the Supreme Brahman described in the Upanishads is verily the same highest divinity of religion. The distinction made by Advaitins between Supreme Brahman and Iswara is not tenable because there are no valid &amp;lsquo;pramanas&amp;rsquo; for positing such a difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०७ मुमुक्षुत्वाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/07_mumuxutvAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/07_mumuxutvAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>Mumukshuthvadhikara
CHAPTER - VI
Mumukshuthvadhikara
It is rightly declared that three things are very rare to be obtained. Of these three, to be bom as a human being is very rare. When one is endowed with the body, indriyas, mind and knowledge, a person will do well to obtain knowledge of the Reality and make an attempt to save himself from samsara. To be born in this world again and again, is never the goal of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०८ अधिकारि-विभागाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/08_adhikAri-vibhAgAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/08_adhikAri-vibhAgAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>०८ अधिकारि-विभागाधिकारः
Adhikari Vibhagadhikara
CHAPTER - VIII
Adhikari Vibhagadhikara
After describing the essential requirements for becoming a genuine sceker of moksha or liberation, Desika has described in this section, that there are two kinds of aspirants after moksha. Adhikarin means one who is competent and fit for undertaking spiritual discipline for gaining moksha. These aspirants are of two kinds. Both these kinds of aspirants are engaged in Nivritti Dharma and they are (1) those who adopt self surrender directly for attainment of moksha and (2) those that surrender unto the Lord for gaining liberation through Bhakti Yoga or Upasana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०९ उपायविभागाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/09_upAyavibhAgAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/09_upAyavibhAgAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>Upayavibhagadhikara
101
CHAPTER - IX
Upayavibhagadhikara
SUI
After describing the different kinds of aspirants after liberation, that undertake the means of attainment of the Lord in general, in this chapter, the two significant means of attainment of paramatman are expounded. The two means are &amp;lsquo;Bhakti&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Prapatti&amp;rsquo;. &amp;ldquo;I can be attained through supreme devotion to me or surrender unto me; I cannot be attained by any other means&amp;rdquo; says the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१० प्रपत्ति-योग्याधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/10_prapatti-yogyAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/10_prapatti-yogyAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१० प्रपत्ति-योग्याधिकारः
Prapatti Yogyadhikara
113
CHAPTER - X
Prapatti Yogyadhikara
In this chapter, the eligibility of an aspirant for performing prapatti is described. This section along with the succeeding two sections, forms one unit. In the twelfth section, the mode of performance of prapatti, along with the accessories, is outlined. The earlier chapters from I to ll are expounding the prerequisites that are to be known for self-surrender to be actuated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>११ परिकर-विभागाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/11_parikara-vibhAgAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/11_parikara-vibhAgAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>११ परिकर-विभागाधिकारः
Parikara Vibhagadhikara
117
CHAPTER - XI
Parikara Vibhagadhikara
In the previous section, the essential nature of an aspirant, competent to adopt this means of self-surrender, was described. It was also pointed out that prapatti was a self-sufficient and adequate means for attainment of moksha. It was declared that prapatti does not require the very many accessories that are inevitable for Bhaktiyoga. Though this spiritual means does not require the accessories of Karmayoga or Jnanayoga, Astangayoga and others, it is necessarily having five accessories for becoming effective and these accessories have been prescribed in the shruties and the nature of these essentials of Prapatti are described in this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१२ साङ्ग-प्रपदनाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/12_sAnga-prapadanAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/12_sAnga-prapadanAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१२ साङ्ग-प्रपदनाधिकारः
Sangaprapadanadhikara
CHAPTER - XII
Sangaprapadanadhikara
Having discussed about the various requirements that are essential for surrendering oneself unto the Lord, in this section, the mode of self-surrender, which is of the form of entrusting the burden of the protection of one&amp;rsquo;s self to the Lord is described. This happens to be the prime factor in the process of surrender. Having qualified himself with an aspiration for liberation, having known in general terms the nature of the inseparable relationship with the Lord, and having known the several accessories that are essential for Prapatti, one becomes capable of performing Prapatti at the feet of the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१३ कृत-कृत्याधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/13_kRta-kRtyAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/13_kRta-kRtyAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१३ कृत-कृत्याधिकारः
Kritakricyadhikara
145
CHAPTER - XIII
Kritakrityadhikara
&amp;ldquo;When a spiritual aspirant has surrendered the burden of his protection to the Lord, who is omniscient and omnipotent, and a well wisher of all by his very nature, and when such a Lord has accepted the burden of protection, thus entrusted to Him, he has nothing more to do regarding that in this universe. He engages himself totally in the loving service of that Supreme Lord, who is an ocean of Supreme bliss, and becomes fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१४ स्वनिष्ठाभिज्ञानाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/14_svaniShThAbhijnAnAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/14_svaniShThAbhijnAnAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१४ स्वनिष्ठाभिज्ञानाधिकारः
Swanistabhijnanadhikara
CHAPTER - XIV
Swanistabhijnanadhikara
A prapanna is one who is steadfast in the awareness of his own essential nature, which is different from non-sentient matter on one hand and the Supreme Paramatman on the other hand, who is the &amp;lsquo;sarva-seshin&amp;rsquo;, the siddhopaya and the supreme object of attainment. The understanding of these three namely the tattva, the hita and the purushartha should be firm and unshakable by any kind of perverse arguments in a prapanna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१५ उत्तरकृत्याधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/15_uttarakRtyAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/15_uttarakRtyAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>161
CHAPTER - XV Uttarakrityadhikara
In this section, the duties that are to be performed by a prapanna, after prapatti, are pointed out for the guidance of those who have adopted the spiritual discipline of paraptti. A prapanna is bound to continue his life as destined by his past karma, and he has to follow a way of life that is in accordance with his nature. Just like a Jivanmuktha who is engaged in certain duties of life, so long as he is embodied, a prapanna also follows a course of action, which is befitting with his knowledge and aspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१६ पुरुषार्थकाष्ठाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/16_puruShArthakAShThAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/16_puruShArthakAShThAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>171
CHAPTER - XVI
Purushartakastadhikara
In this section, it is expounded that service unto the preceptors and the godly ones, the Bhagavantas, that is ordained in the shastras, is the culmination of &amp;lsquo;bhagavat kainkarya&amp;rsquo; or loving service unto the Supreme Lord. It is pointed out that his subservience to the Lord, results in his subservience to the devotees of the Lord also, on account of the very will of that Supreme Lord, who is the Master of all, and who is the one independent Reality who can ordain all others to follow his commandments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१७ शास्त्रीय-नियमनाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/17_shAstrIya-niyamanAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/17_shAstrIya-niyamanAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१७ शास्त्रीय-नियमनाधिकारः
177
CHAPTER - XVII
Shastriya Niyamanadhikara
It was said in the previous section that a Prapanna would abide by the Shastras that ordain certain duties. But, a number of doubts arise in this behalf. The Prapanna is not required to do the (duties of the) nitya and naimitthika karmas as an accessory to Bhakti-Yoga or Praptti, as he has performed what ought to be done and is similar to a Mukta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१८ अपराध-परिहाराधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/18_aparAdha-parihArAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/18_aparAdha-parihArAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>१८ अपराध-परिहाराधिकारः
CHAPTER - XVIII
Aparadhapariharadhikara
In this section, it is expounded that a Prapanna who commits some faults willingly, impelled by his past karmas or on account of certain spacial and temporal conditions or on account of his inadvertence, has to repent for his faults and pray forgiveness of the Lord, failing which, he would be subjected to some punishments by the Lord. A Prapanna is, therefore, warned to be very careful regarding his behaviour in this world, where he is destined to live till he is liberated from the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>१९ स्थानविशेषाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/19_sthAnavisheShAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/19_sthAnavisheShAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>Schana Visheshadhikara
193
CHAPTER - XCX
Sthana Visheshadhikara
It was expounded in the previous section viz., Aparadhapariharadhikara, that a Prapanna should engage himself in divine service to the Lord, untainted by any offence, so long as he is destined to live in this world. He would gain the eternal service of the Lord in the Supreme Abode of the Lord after casting his body. It is described in this section, whether a suitable place is available for such a person to live in and to spend his lifetime in activities that are free from offences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>२० निर्याणाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/20_niryANAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/20_niryANAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER - XX
Niryandhikara
The process of the jivas passing out of the body has been described in the Upanishads and the same has been expounded in the Brahmasutras (second quarter of the fourth chapter). In Chandogya Upanishad, it is said that when the &amp;lsquo;purusha&amp;rsquo; dies, his speech unites with mind, the mind gets into prana and the prana into tejas and the tejas becomes one with Supreme Deity (Chandogya 6-8-6).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>२१ गतिचिन्तनाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/21_gatichintanAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/21_gatichintanAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>Gatichintanadhikara
209
CHAPTER - XXI
Gatichintapadhikara
The Upanishads describe the path of &amp;lsquo;archiradi&amp;rsquo; and calls it &amp;lsquo;Devapatha&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Brahmapatha&amp;rsquo;. The various guides lead jivatman from one place to another place and a superhuman called &amp;lsquo;Amanava&amp;rsquo;, leads him to Supreme Brahman in the end. As a king fondles his son, the prince, who is obedient to him, the Lord himself makes this liberated soul led to his place by the various &amp;lsquo;ativahikas&amp;rsquo; such as Agni and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>२२ परिपूर्ण-ब्रह्मानुभवाधिकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/22_paripUrNa-brahmAnubhavAdhikAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/venkaTanAthaH/rahasya-traya-sAraH/nsa-summary/1_arthAnushAsana-vibhAgaH/22_paripUrNa-brahmAnubhavAdhikAraH/</guid>
      <description>२२ परिपूर्ण-ब्रह्मानुभवाधिकारः
Paripurna Brahmanubhava Adhikara
213
CHAPTER - XXII
Paripurna Brahmanubhava Adhikara
In this section. Dcsika describes the great benefit of obtaining the bliss of communion with Paramatman for all time to come, and the unique gain of similarity or &amp;lsquo;Paramasamya&amp;rsquo; with the Supreme Paramatman. In explaining this complete experience of the &amp;lsquo;Sarveswara&amp;rsquo;, the celebrated author is guided by the upanishadic statements, as well as the conclusions of the Brahmasutras, beginning with &amp;lsquo;Karyadhikarana&amp;rsquo; (in the third pada of the fourth chapter) and concluding with the declaration of the Sutrakara with the sutra &amp;lsquo;Anavritih Shabdar&amp;rsquo; (from Sutra 4-3-6 to 4-4-22).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
