<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ आदि on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ आदि on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>05 The Spiritual Masters</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu is none other than the combined form of Śrī Rādhā and Kṛṣṇa. He is the life of those devotees who strictly follow in the footsteps of Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī. Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī and Śrīla Sanātana Gosvāmī are the two principal followers of Śrīla Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī, who acted as the most confidential servitor of Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa Caitanya Mahāprabhu, known as Viśvambhara in His early life. A direct disciple of Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī was Śrīla Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī. The author of &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī, stands as the direct disciple of Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī and Śrīla Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Śri Caitanya Mahāprabhu, the Supreme Personality of Godhead</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter explains that Lord Caitanya is the Supreme Personality of Godhead Kṛṣṇa Himself. Therefore, the Brahman effulgence is the bodily luster of Lord Caitanya, and the localized Supersoul situated in the heart of every living entity is His partial representation. The &lt;em&gt;puruṣa-avatāras&lt;/em&gt; are also explained in this connection. Mahā-Viṣṇu is the reservoir of all conditioned souls, but, as confirmed in the authoritative scriptures, Lord Kṛṣṇa is the ultimate fountainhead, the source of numerous plenary expansions, including Nārāyaṇa, who is generally accepted by Māyāvādī philosophers to be the Absolute Truth. The Lord’s manifestation of &lt;em&gt;prābhava&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;vaibhava&lt;/em&gt; expansions, as well as partial incarnations and incarnations with delegated powers, are also explained. Lord Kṛṣṇa’s ages of boyhood and youth are discussed, and it is explained that His age at the beginning of youth is His eternal form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The External Reasons for the Appearance of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THREE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter the author has fully discussed the external reasons for the descent of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The Supreme Personality of Godhead, Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa, after displaying His pastimes as Lord Kṛṣṇa, thought it wise to make His advent in the form of a devotee to explain personally the transcendental mellows of reciprocal service and love exchanged between Himself and His servants, friends, parents and fiancées. According to the Vedic literature, the foremost occupational duty for humanity in this Age of Kali is &lt;em&gt;nāma-saṅkīrtana,&lt;/em&gt; or congregational chanting of the holy name of the Lord. The incarnation for this age especially preaches this process, but only Kṛṣṇa Himself can explain the confidential loving service performed in the four principal varieties of loving affairs between the Supreme Lord and His devotees. Lord Kṛṣṇa therefore personally appeared, with His plenary portions, as Lord Caitanya. As stated in this chapter, it was for this purpose that Lord Kṛṣṇa appeared personally in Navadvīpa in the form of Śrī Kṛṣṇa Caitanya Mahāprabhu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 The Confidential Reasons for the Appearance of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter of the epic &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-caritāmṛta,&lt;/em&gt; Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī has stressed that Lord Caitanya appeared for three principal purposes of His own. The first purpose was to relish the position of Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī, who is the prime reciprocator of transcendental love of Śrī Kṛṣṇa. Lord Kṛṣṇa is the reservoir of transcendental loving transactions with Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī. The subject of those loving transactions is the Lord Himself, and Rādhārāṇī is the object. Thus the subject, the Lord, wanted to relish the loving mellow in the position of the object, Rādhārāṇī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Glories Of Lord Nityānanda Balarāma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter is chiefly devoted to describing the essential nature and glories of Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu. Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa is the absolute Personality of Godhead, and His first expansion in a form for pastimes is Śrī Balarāma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the limitation of this material world is the spiritual sky, &lt;em&gt;paravyoma,&lt;/em&gt; which has many spiritual planets, the supreme of which is called Kṛṣṇaloka. Kṛṣṇaloka, the abode of Kṛṣṇa, has three divisions, which are known as Dvārakā, Mathurā and Gokula. In that abode the Personality of Godhead expands Himself into four plenary portions — Kṛṣṇa, Balarāma, Pradyumna (the transcendental Cupid) and Aniruddha. They are known as the original quadruple forms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Glories of Śrī Advaita Ācārya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truth of Advaita Ācārya has been described in two verses. It is said that material nature has two features, namely the material cause and the efficient cause. The efficient causal activities are caused by Mahā-Viṣṇu, and the material causal activities are caused by another form of Mahā-Viṣṇu, known as Advaita. That Advaita, the superintendent of the cosmic manifestation, has descended in the form of Advaita Ācārya to associate with Lord Caitanya. When He is addressed as the servitor of Lord Caitanya, His glories are magnified because unless one is invigorated by this mentality of servitorship one cannot understand the mellows derived from devotional service to the Supreme Lord, Kṛṣṇa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Lord Caitanya in Five Features</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-1&#34;&gt;Text 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bengali&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अगत्येकगतिं नत्वा हीनार्थाधिकसाधकम्‌ ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;श्रीचैतन्यं लिख्यतेऽस्य प्रेमभक्तिवदान्यता ॥ १ ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-text&#34;&gt;Verse text&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;agaty-eka-gatiṁ natvā&lt;br&gt;&#xA;hīnārthādhika-sādhakam&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śrī-caitanyaṁ likhyate ’sya&lt;br&gt;&#xA;prema-bhakti-vadānyatā&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synonyms&#34;&gt;Synonyms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;agati&lt;/em&gt; — of the most fallen; &lt;em&gt;eka&lt;/em&gt; — the only one; &lt;em&gt;gatim&lt;/em&gt; — destination; &lt;em&gt;natvā&lt;/em&gt; — after offering obeisances; &lt;em&gt;hīna&lt;/em&gt; — inferior; &lt;em&gt;artha&lt;/em&gt; — interest; &lt;em&gt;adhika&lt;/em&gt; — greater than that; &lt;em&gt;sādhakam&lt;/em&gt; — who can render; &lt;em&gt;śrī&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;caitanyam&lt;/em&gt; — unto Lord Śrī Caitanya; &lt;em&gt;likhyate&lt;/em&gt; — is being written; &lt;em&gt;asya&lt;/em&gt; — of the Lord, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu; &lt;em&gt;prema&lt;/em&gt; — love; &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; — devotional service; &lt;em&gt;vadānyatā&lt;/em&gt; — magnanimity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Author Receives the Orders of Kṛṣṇa and Guru</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The eighth chapter of &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt; is summarized by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; In this chapter the glories of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Nityānanda are described, and it is also stated that one who commits offenses in chanting the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mantra&lt;/em&gt; does not achieve love of Godhead, even after chanting for many years. In this connection, Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura warns against artificial displays of the bodily symptoms called &lt;em&gt;aṣṭa-sāttvika-vikāra.&lt;/em&gt; That is also an offense. One should seriously and sincerely continue to chant the Pañca-tattva names &lt;em&gt;śrī-kṛṣṇa-caitanya prabhu-nityānanda śrī-advaita gadādhara śrīvāsādi-gaura-bhakta-vṛnda.&lt;/em&gt; All these &lt;em&gt;ācāryas&lt;/em&gt; will bestow their causeless mercy upon a devotee and gradually purify his heart. When he is actually purified, automatically he will experience ecstasy in chanting the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mahā-mantra.&lt;/em&gt; Previous to the composition of &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Vṛndāvana dāsa Ṭhākura wrote a book called &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-bhāgavata.&lt;/em&gt; Only those subjects which were not discussed by Śrīla Vṛndāvana dāsa Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-bhāgavata&lt;/em&gt; have been taken up by Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī to be depicted in &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta.&lt;/em&gt; In his very old age, Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī went to Vṛndāvana, and by the order of Śrī Madana-mohanajī he wrote &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta.&lt;/em&gt; Thus we are now able to relish its transcendental bliss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Desire Tree of Devotional Service</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of chapter nine has been given as follows by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; In this chapter the author of &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt; has devised a figurative example by describing “the desire tree of &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt;.” He considers Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu, who is known as Viśvambhara, to be the gardener of this tree because He is the main personality who has taken charge of it. As the supreme enjoyer, He enjoyed the fruits Himself and distributed them as well. The seed of the tree was first sown in Navadvīpa, the birth site of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and then the tree was brought to Puruṣottama-kṣetra (Jagannātha Purī), and then to Vṛndāvana. The seed fructified first in Śrīla Mādhavendra Purī, and then in his disciple Śrī Īśvara Purī. It is figuratively described that both the tree itself and the trunk of the tree are Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Paramānanda Purī and eight other great &lt;em&gt;sannyāsīs&lt;/em&gt; are like the spreading roots of the tree. From the main trunk there extend two special branches, Advaita Prabhu and Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu, and from those branches grow other branches and twigs. The tree surrounds the entire world, and the fruits of the tree are to be distributed to everyone. In this way the tree of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu intoxicates the entire world. It should be noted that this is a figurative example meant to explain the mission of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Trunk, Branches and Subbranches of the Caitanya Tree</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter describes the branches of the tree named Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-1&#34;&gt;Text 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bengali&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीचैतन्यपदाम्भोज–मधुपेभ्यो नमो नमः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कथञ्चिदाश्रय़ाद्‌ येषां श्वापि तद्‌गन्धभाग्‌भवेत् ॥ १ ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-text&#34;&gt;Verse text&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;śrī-caitanya-padāmbhoja-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;madhupebhyo namo namaḥ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;kathañcid āśrayād yeṣāṁ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śvāpi tad-gandha-bhāg bhavet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synonyms&#34;&gt;Synonyms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;śrī&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;caitanya&lt;/em&gt; — Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu; &lt;em&gt;pada&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ambhoja&lt;/em&gt; — the lotus feet; &lt;em&gt;madhu&lt;/em&gt; — honey; &lt;em&gt;pebhyaḥ&lt;/em&gt; — unto those who drink; &lt;em&gt;namaḥ&lt;/em&gt; — respectful obeisances; &lt;em&gt;namaḥ&lt;/em&gt; — respectful obeisances; &lt;em&gt;kathañcit&lt;/em&gt; — a little of it; &lt;em&gt;āśrayāt&lt;/em&gt; — taking shelter of; &lt;em&gt;yeṣām&lt;/em&gt; — of whom; &lt;em&gt;śvā&lt;/em&gt; — dog; &lt;em&gt;api&lt;/em&gt; — also; &lt;em&gt;tat&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;gandha&lt;/em&gt; — the aroma of the lotus flower; &lt;em&gt;bhāk&lt;/em&gt; — shareholder; &lt;em&gt;bhavet&lt;/em&gt; — may become.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Expansions of Lord Nityānanda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the branches and subbranches of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu were described in the tenth chapter, in this eleventh chapter the branches and subbranches of Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu are similarly listed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-1&#34;&gt;Text 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bengali&#34;&gt;Bengali&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;नित्यानन्दपदाम्भोज–भृङ्गान् प्रेममधून्मदान् ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;नत्वाखिलान् तेषु मुख्या लिख्यन्ते कतिचिन्मय़ा ॥ १ ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-text&#34;&gt;Verse text&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nityānanda-padāmbhoja-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;bhṛṅgān prema-madhūnmadān&lt;br&gt;&#xA;natvākhilān teṣu mukhyā&lt;br&gt;&#xA;likhyante katicin mayā&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synonyms&#34;&gt;Synonyms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nityānanda&lt;/em&gt; — of Lord Śrī Nityānanda; &lt;em&gt;pada&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ambhoja&lt;/em&gt; — lotus feet; &lt;em&gt;bhṛṅgān&lt;/em&gt; — the bumblebees; &lt;em&gt;prema&lt;/em&gt; — of love of Godhead; &lt;em&gt;madhu&lt;/em&gt; — by the honey; &lt;em&gt;unmadān&lt;/em&gt; — maddened; &lt;em&gt;natvā&lt;/em&gt; — offering obeisances; &lt;em&gt;akhilān&lt;/em&gt; — to all of them; &lt;em&gt;teṣu&lt;/em&gt; — out of them; &lt;em&gt;mukhyāḥ&lt;/em&gt; — the chief; &lt;em&gt;likhyante&lt;/em&gt; — being described; &lt;em&gt;katicit&lt;/em&gt; — a few of them; &lt;em&gt;mayā&lt;/em&gt; — by me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The Expansions of Advaita Ācārya and Gadādhara Paṇḍita</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives a summary of the twelfth chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; The twelfth chapter describes the followers of Advaita Prabhu, among whom the followers of Acyutānanda, the son of Advaita Ācārya, are understood to be the pure followers who received the cream of the philosophy Śrī Advaita Ācārya enunciated. Other so-called descendants and followers of Advaita Ācārya are not to be recognized. This chapter also includes narrations concerning the son of Advaita Ācārya named Gopāla Miśra and Advaita Ācārya’s servant named Kamalākānta Viśvāsa. In his early life Gopāla fainted during the cleansing of the Guṇḍicā-mandira at Jagannātha Purī and thus became a recipient of the mercy of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The story of Kamalākānta Viśvāsa concerns his borrowing three hundred rupees from Pratāparudra Mahārāja to clear a debt of Advaita Ācārya’s, for which Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu chastised him when He came to know of it. Kamalākānta Viśvāsa was then purified by the request of Śrī Advaita Ācārya. After describing the descendants of Advaita Ācārya, the chapter concludes by describing the followers of Gadādhara Paṇḍita Gosvāmī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The Advent of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thirteenth chapter describes Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s appearance. The entire &lt;em&gt;Ādi-līlā&lt;/em&gt; describes Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s household life, and similarly the &lt;em&gt;Antya-līlā&lt;/em&gt; describes His life in the &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; order. Within the Lord’s &lt;em&gt;antya-līlā,&lt;/em&gt; the first six years of His &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; life are called the &lt;em&gt;madhya-līlā.&lt;/em&gt; During this time, Caitanya Mahāprabhu toured southern India, went to Vṛndāvana, returned from Vṛndāvana and preached the &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana&lt;/em&gt; movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A learned &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; named Upendra Miśra, who resided in the district of Śrīhaṭṭa, was the father of Jagannātha Miśra, who came to Navadvīpa to study under the direction of Nīlāmbara Cakravartī and then settled there after marrying Nīlāmbara Cakravartī’s daughter, Śacīdevī. Śrī Śacīdevī gave birth to eight children, all daughters, who died one after another immediately after birth. After her ninth pregnancy she gave birth to a son, who was named Viśvarūpa. Then, in 1407 Śaka Era (A.D. 1486), in the full-moon evening of the month of Phālguna, with the constellation of Siṁha (Leo) on the horizon, Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu appeared as the son of Śrī Śacīdevī and Jagannātha Miśra. After hearing of the birth of Caitanya Mahāprabhu, learned scholars and &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas,&lt;/em&gt; bringing many gifts, came to see the newborn baby. Nīlāmbara Cakravartī, who was a great astrologer, immediately prepared a horoscope, and by astrological calculation he saw that the child was a great personality. This chapter describes the symptoms of this great personality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Lord Caitanya’s Childhood Pastimes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura has given a summary of this chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya:&lt;/em&gt; “In the fourteenth chapter there is a description of how Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu enjoyed His childhood pastimes — crawling, crying, eating dirt and giving intelligence to His mother, favoring a &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; guest, riding on the shoulders of two thieves and misleading them to His own house, and, on the plea of being diseased, taking &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; in the house of Hiraṇya and Jagadīśa on the Ekādaśī day. The chapter further describes how He displayed Himself as a naughty boy, how when His mother fainted He brought a coconut to her on His head, how He joked with girls of the same age on the banks of the Ganges, how He accepted worshipful paraphernalia from Śrīmatī Lakṣmīdevī, how He sat down in a garbage pit and instructed His mother in transcendental knowledge, how He left the pit on the order of His mother, and how He dealt with His father with full affection.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The Lord’s Paugaṇḍa-līlā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A synopsis of the fifteenth chapter is as follows. The Lord took lessons in grammar from Gaṅgādāsa Paṇḍita and became very expert in commenting upon grammar. He forbade His mother to take grains on the Ekādaśī day. He narrated a story that Viśvarūpa, after accepting the &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; order, invited Him in a dream to accept &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; also*,* but the Lord refused and was therefore sent back home. When Jagannātha Miśra passed away, the Lord married the daughter of Vallabhācārya, whose name was Lakṣmī. All these events are summarized in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The Pastimes of the Lord in His Childhood and Youth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter fully describes Lord Caitanya’s &lt;em&gt;kaiśora-līlā,&lt;/em&gt; or the activities He performed just before attaining youth. During this time He studied deeply and was victorious over greatly learned scholars. During His &lt;em&gt;kaiśora-līlā&lt;/em&gt; the Lord also sported in the water. He went to East Bengal to secure financial assistance, cultivate knowledge and introduce the &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana&lt;/em&gt; movement, and there He met Tapana Miśra, whom He instructed about spiritual advancement and ordered to go to Vārāṇasī. While Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu was touring East Bengal, His wife, Lakṣmīdevī, was bitten by a serpent or by the serpent of separation, and thus she left this world. When the Lord returned home, He saw that His mother was overwhelmed with grief because of Lakṣmīdevī’s death. Therefore at her request He later married His second wife, Viṣṇupriyā-devī. This chapter also describes the Lord’s argument with Keśava Kāśmīrī, the celebrated scholar, and the Lord’s criticism of his prayer glorifying mother Ganges. In this prayer the Lord found five kinds of literary ornaments and five kinds of literary faults, thus defeating the &lt;em&gt;paṇḍita.&lt;/em&gt; Later the Kāśmīrī Paṇḍita, who was known to have been victorious all over the country, submitted himself to the goddess of learning, and by her order he met Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu on the morning of the next day and surrendered unto Him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 The Pastimes of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu in His Youth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVENTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The seventeenth chapter, as summarized by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya,&lt;/em&gt; describes Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s pastimes from His sixteenth year until the time He accepted the renounced order of life. Śrīla Vṛndāvana dāsa Ṭhākura has already vividly described these pastimes in the &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-bhāgavata;&lt;/em&gt; therefore Kṛṣṇa dāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī describes them only briefly. Vivid descriptions of some portions of His pastimes are seen in this chapter, however, because Vṛndāvana dāsa Ṭhākura has not elaborately described them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Madhya-līlā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/01_Adi/18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;CHAPTER ONE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWO&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;CHAPTER THREE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-four&#34;&gt;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-five&#34;&gt;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-six&#34;&gt;CHAPTER SIX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-seven&#34;&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-eight&#34;&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-nine&#34;&gt;CHAPTER NINE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-ten&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-eleven&#34;&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twelve&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-thirteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-fourteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-fifteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-sixteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-seventeen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER SEVENTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-eighteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER EIGHTEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-nineteen&#34;&gt;CHAPTER NINETEEN&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty-one&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-ONE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty-two&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-TWO&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty-three&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-THREE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty-four&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FOUR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-twenty-five&#34;&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FIVE&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
