<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;5 MERGING IDENTITIES: INTEGRATING TRADITIONS on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;5 MERGING IDENTITIES: INTEGRATING TRADITIONS on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/1_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/1_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the last chapter I suggested that, in the minds of the authors of the AS, the identity of the Pāñcarātra tradition was “open to revision and reinvention”. In the previous two chapters, I discussed similar processes of adaptation and innovation in the form of the “Vedification” of the Pāñcarātra, and the invention of the Ekāyanaveda. In each case I have focussed on these developments as they occurred in South India in the early centuries of the second millennium, undoubtedly a period of great growth and productivity for these traditions. However, as we have seen, the desire of Pāñcarātrikas to allign themselves with the Veda, and the appeal to the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; as a legitimating source for the establishment of a universal Vaiṣṇava religion, are evident already in North Indian literature of the preceding centuries. In each of the cases I have addressed in Part Two, Pāñcarātrika authors have attempted to construct or to reconstruct the identity of their own textual tradition by extending its canonical boundaries. Each of these attempts seeks legitimacy through identification with another textual tradition. Of the different authorities appealed to by Pāñcarātrikas, however, only the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; is innately responsive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
