<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 The Secret Dimension of the Vishnu-house on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 The Secret Dimension of the Vishnu-house on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>05 The Temple Mandala and the Bottom-floor Sanctum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/05_The_Temple_Mandala_and_the_Bottom-flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/05_The_Temple_Mandala_and_the_Bottom-flo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-temple-mandala&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Temple Mandala&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In concept, the plan of the Emperor’s Vishnu-house is a square, its outer boundary marked by a high stone wall. The acharya who guided the royal architect in constructing it followed a mandala. A mandala is a map; it begins with a central point and moves outward toward the four cardinal directions in a sequence of squares and circles. The entire mandala arena of the Vishnu-house is most likely a built form of the &lt;em&gt;chakrabjamandala&lt;/em&gt; important to Pancharatra ceremonies; it is composed of a wheel (&lt;em&gt;chakra&lt;/em&gt;) with an eight-petal lotus blossom born of water (&lt;em&gt;abja&lt;/em&gt;) at its center. The example shown in the frontispiece comes from the &lt;em&gt;Padma-samhita&lt;/em&gt;. These colors have many specific meanings, but according to the &lt;em&gt;Padma-samhita&lt;/em&gt;, a specific color is identified with each of the cardinal directions that the sides of this mandala face, and they also correspond to the formations or vyuhas God makes; the square sanctum on the vimana’s bottom floor depicts the vyuhas as icons (&lt;em&gt;archa&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Middle-floor Sanctum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/06_The_Middle-floor_Sanctum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/06_The_Middle-floor_Sanctum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sculpted Program of the Northern Path&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us now turn to the sanctum on the middle floor of the Vishnu-house. To gain access, visitors climb the southern staircase inside the vimana leading into its small porch; they descend by way of the corresponding northern staircase. The porch doorway opens into an open-air verandah formed by the roof of the much larger porch below. The sides of the vimana below extend upward to create a low wall enclosing the entire middle story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Northern Panels of the Northern Path</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/07_Northern_Panels_of_the_Northern_Path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/07_Northern_Panels_of_the_Northern_Path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transforming Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the poet Kalikanri refers to this side of the sanctum in his poem about the temple, he captures the entire wall by recording its first and last panels. The rescue of the elephant Gajendra begins the sequence, and Krishna dancing on the snake Kaliya ends it: “The elephant’s arm is a hollow tube / And his leg is thick and sturdy, / But it hurt badly until / He cured it, He who / Plunged one day into / A pool of blooming flowers / To scare the snake in its water, / He whose place is beautiful Kacci / Encircled by cooling ponds, // There in the Emperor’s Vishnu-house / Built by the Sovereign of Pallavas / after the day he marched / at the head of battle / with Cobra in hand / to astonish the Southern King / of fragrant groves / and rampart walls high as mountains” (&lt;em&gt;PT&lt;/em&gt; 2.9.5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Northern Panels of the Northern Path</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/08_Northern_Panels_of_the_Northern_Path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/08_Northern_Panels_of_the_Northern_Path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortifying Omniscience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;blazing-omniscient-knowledge&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blazing Omniscient Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first three panels (5–7) on the north wall, discussed in the last chapter, represent Hari’s indefatigable churning power (&lt;em&gt;bala&lt;/em&gt;) in the Plower formation; the second three panels (8–10), which we will look at here, represent his brilliantly blazing omniscient knowledge (&lt;em&gt;jnana&lt;/em&gt;). The story of Man-as-Lion (Nrisimha or Narasimha) is the subject of the first two of these three panels; the third depicts the story of Krishna banishing the snake Kaliya from a Yamuna River pool. The first panel’s location adjacent to the central window, its large size, and its distinctive frame tie it to the preceding panel with the same characteristics. But transformation gives way to purification as we move eastward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Middle-Floor Sanctum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/09_The_Middle-Floor_Sanctum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/09_The_Middle-Floor_Sanctum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sculpted Program of the Southern Path&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The southern sequence of the middle-floor sanctum begins on the west, at the southwest corner of the porch facing south. It moves counterclockwise to the eastern side, ending with the panel adjacent to its central window. Figure 6.3 identifies its twelve panels (13–24). As in the case of the northern sequence, we shall discuss this sculpted program beginning with the western side (panels 13–16), moving directly to the eastern side (panels 23–24). The southern side (panels 17–22) will be discussed in chapter 10.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Southern Panels of the Southern Pat</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/10_The_Southern_Panels_of_the_Southern_P/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/02_The_Secret_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-ho/10_The_Southern_Panels_of_the_Southern_P/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Path of the Southern Doctrine”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like the panels of the northern sequence, the six panels of the southern sequence, facing south, move sequentially west to east, which in this case is counterclockwise, a normally inauspicious rotation. They likewise explain the connection of the corner panel on the south that faces west to the corner panel on the south that faces east, in terms of a consecrated ruler following a sadhana for the sake of bhukti, or worldly prosperity, which may also include mukti, or emancipation from samsara. This sequence probably illustrates what Prahlada calls “The Path of the Southern Doctrine.”1 How does a consecrated Shudra king, who rules like Bali under Narayana’s protection, have his sense of “This is mine” destroyed, and then its root sense of “This am I” torn apart? These six panels represent the answer as stages in a sadhana that appears to draw upon rites found in the &lt;em&gt;Jayakha-samhita&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ahirbudnya-samhita&lt;/em&gt; of the Pancharatra Agama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
