<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/01/</guid>
      <description>THIRD PĀDA. What is understood from all the Vedānta-texts (is one), on account of the non-difference of injunction and the rest. The Sūtras have stated whatever has to be stated to the end of rousing the desire of meditation-concluding with the fact that Brahman bestows rewards. Next the question is introduced whether the vidyās (i.e. the different forms of meditation on Brahman which the Vedānta-texts enjoin) are different or non-different, on the decision of which question it will depend whether the qualities attributed to Brahman in those vidyās are to be comprised in one act of meditation or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/02/</guid>
      <description>If it be said (that the vidyās are not one) on account of difference, we deny this, since even in one (vidyā there may be repetition). If it be said that there is no oneness of vidyā, because the fact of the same matter being stated again without difference, and being met with in a different chapter, proves the object of injunction to be different; we reply that even in one and the same vidyā some matter may be repeated without any change, and under a new heading (in a different chapter); if, namely, there is difference of cognising subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/03/</guid>
      <description>For (the śirovrata) concerns the mode of the study of the Veda; also on account of (that rite) being a heading in the samācāra; and the restriction is like that of the libations. What the text says as to a restriction connected with the &amp;lsquo;vow of the head,&amp;rsquo; does not intimate a difference of vidyās. For that vow does not form part of the vidyā. The restriction refers only to a peculiarity of the study of the Veda on the part of the Ātharvaṇikas, being meant to establish that they should possess that special qualification which the rite produces; but it does not affect the vidyā itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/04/</guid>
      <description>Scripture also declares this. Scripture also shows that (identical) meditation is what all the Vedānta-texts intimate. The Cḥāndogya (VIII, 1, 1 ff.) declares that that which is within the small space in the heart is to be enquired into, and then in reply to the
question what the thing to be enquired into is, says that it is the highest Self possessing the eight attributes, freedom from all evil and the rest, which is to be meditated upon within the heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/05/</guid>
      <description>(Meditation) thus being equal, there is combination (of guṇas); on account of non-difference of purport in the case of what subserves injunction. The meditation in all Vedānta-texts thus being the same, the qualities mentioned in one text are to be combined with those mentioned in another; &amp;lsquo;on account of non-difference of purport in the case of what subserves injunction.&amp;rsquo; We find that in connexion with certain injunctions of meditation&amp;ndash;such as the meditation on Vaiśvānara, or the small ether within the heart&amp;ndash;the text of some individual Vedānta-book mentions certain secondary matters (qualities, guṇa) which subserve that meditation; and as these guṇas are connected with the meditation they are to be comprised in it, so that they may accomplish their aim, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/06/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that there is difference on account of the text; we say no; on account of non-difference. So far it has been shown that the non-difference of injunction,
and so on, establishes the unity of meditations, and that owing to the latter the special features of meditation enjoined in different texts have to be combined. Next, an enquiry is entered upon whether in the case of certain particular meditations there actually exists, or not, that non-difference of injunction which is the cause of meditations being recognised as identical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/07/</guid>
      <description>Or not, on account of difference of subject-matter; as in the case of the attribute of being higher than the high, and so on. There is no unity of the two vidyās, since the subject-matter of the two differs. For the tale in the Cḥāndogya-text, which begins &amp;lsquo;when the Devas and the Asuras struggled together,&amp;rsquo; connects itself with the praṇava (the syllable Om) which is introduced as the object of meditation in Cḥánd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/08/</guid>
      <description>If that be declared on account of name; (we object, since) that is also (where the objects of injunction differ). If the oneness of the vidyās be maintained on the ground that both have the same name, viz. udgītha-vidyā, we point out that oneness is found also where the objects enjoined are different. The term agnihotra is applied equally to the permanent agnihotra and to that agnihotra which forms part of the sacrifice called &amp;lsquo;Kuṇḍapāyinām ayanam&amp;rsquo;; and the term udgītha is applied equally to the many different meditations described in the first prapāṭḥaka of the Cḥāndogya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/09/</guid>
      <description>And (this is) appropriate, on account of the extension. Since the praṇava, which is a part of the udgītha, is introduced as the subject of meditation in the first prapāṭḥaka of the Cḥāndogya, and extends over the later vidyās also, it is appropriate to assume that also in the clause &amp;rsquo;the gods took the udgītha&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which stands in the middle&amp;ndash;the term udgītha denotes the praṇava. Expressions such as &amp;rsquo;the cloth is burned&amp;rsquo; show that frequently the whole denotes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/10/</guid>
      <description>On account of non-difference of everything, those elsewhere. The Cḥāndogya and the Vajasaneyaka alike record a meditation on Praṇa; the object of meditation being Praṇa as possessing the qualities of being the oldest and the best, and also as possessing certain other qualities such as being the richest, and so on (Cḥ. Up. V, 1; Br̥. Up. VI, 1). In the text of the Kaushītakins, on the other hand, there is a meditation on Prāṇa which mentions the former qualities (&amp;lsquo;being the best&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;being the oldest&amp;rsquo;), but not the latter (&amp;lsquo;being the richest,&amp;rsquo; and so on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/11/</guid>
      <description>Bliss and other qualities, as belonging to the subject of the qualities. The point to be decided here is whether, or not, the essential qualities of Brahman are to be included in all meditations on the highest Brahman.&amp;ndash;Since there is no valid reason for including in a meditation those qualities which are not expressly mentioned in the section containing that meditation, only those qualities which are thus expressly mentioned should be included!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/12/</guid>
      <description>Such qualities as having joy for its head, and so on, are not established, for if there were difference (of members) there would be increase and decrease. The declaration that the essential qualities of Brahman are established for all meditations, does not imply that such attributes as &amp;lsquo;having joy for its head&amp;rsquo; are equally established. For the latter are not qualities of Brahman, since they are mere elements in a figurative representation of Brahman under the form of an animal body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/13/</guid>
      <description>But the others, on account of equality with the thing. Those other qualities which are &amp;rsquo;equal to the thing,&amp;rsquo; i. e. which are attributes determining the essential character of the thing, and therefore necessarily entering into the idea of the thing, must be included in all meditations, no less than the thing itself. To this class belong qualities such as true being, knowledge, bliss, purity, infinity, and so on. For of Brahman&amp;ndash;which by texts such as &amp;rsquo;that from which all these beings,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/14/</guid>
      <description>For meditation, owing to the absence of purpose. As no other purpose can be assigned, the text must be supposed to represent Brahman as having joy for its head, and so on, for the purpose of meditation. In order to accomplish the meditation on Brahman which is enjoined in the text &amp;lsquo;he who knows (i.e. meditates on) Brahman reaches the Highest,&amp;rsquo; the text represents the Brahman consisting of bliss as made up of joy, satisfaction, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/15/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the term &amp;lsquo;Self.&amp;rsquo; That this is so further follows from the fact that in the clause &amp;lsquo;different from this is the inner Self consisting of bliss&amp;rsquo; the term &amp;lsquo;Self is used. For as the Self cannot really possess a head, wings, and tail, its having joy for its head, and so on, can only be meant in a metaphorical sense, for the sake of easier comprehension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/16/</guid>
      <description>There is reference to the Self, as in other places; on account of the subsequent passage. In the clause,&amp;lsquo;different from that is the Self of bliss,&amp;rsquo; the term Self can refer to the highest Self only; &amp;lsquo;as in other cases,&amp;rsquo; i.e. as in other passages&amp;ndash;&amp;rsquo;the Self only was this in the beginning; it thought, let me send forth the worlds,&amp;rsquo; and similar ones&amp;ndash;the term &amp;lsquo;Self denotes the highest Self only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/17/</guid>
      <description>If it be said &amp;lsquo;on account of connexion&amp;rsquo;; it may be so, on account of ascertainment. But as in the preceding sections the term Self is seen to be connected with what is not of the nature of the Self, such as the Self of breath, and so on, it is not possible to draw a valid conclusion from the subsequent passage!&amp;ndash;It iś possible, the Sūtra replies, &amp;lsquo;on account of ascertainment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/18/</guid>
      <description>The new (thing is enjoined); on account of the statement of what has to be done. The Sūtra discusses an additional question connected with the meditation on breath. Both texts&amp;ndash;the Cḥāndogya as well as the Vājasaneyaka-declare that water constitutes a dress for praṇa, and refer to the rinsing of the mouth
with water. The doubt here arises whether what the texts mean to enjoin is the rinsing of the mouth, or a meditation on prāṇa as having water for its dress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/19/</guid>
      <description>And (the qualities) thus being equal, on account of non-difference. In the book of the Vājasaneyaka, called Agnirahasya, we meet with a meditation on Brahman called Śāṇḍilyavidyā; and there is also a Śāṇḍilya-vidyā in the Br̥hadāraṇyaka . The Pūrvapakshin holds that these two meditations are different since the latter text mentions qualities&amp;ndash;such as Brahman being the lord of all&amp;ndash;which are not mentioned in the former; the objects of meditation thus being different, the meditations themselves are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/20/</guid>
      <description>On account of connexion, thus elsewhere also. In the Br̥had-āraṇyaka (V, 5) it is said that Brahman is to be meditated upon as abiding within the orb of the sun and within the right eye; and then the text mentions two secret names of Brahman&amp;ndash;aham and ahar. Here the Pūrvapakshin holds that both these names are to be comprehended in each of the two meditations &amp;lsquo;On account of connexion,&amp;rsquo; i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/21/</guid>
      <description>Or not so, on account of difference. This is not so, for as Brahman is to be meditated upon in two different abodes, the meditations are separate. In both the Śāṇḍilya-vidyās, on the other hand, Brahman is to be meditated upon as abiding within the heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/22/</guid>
      <description>The text also declares this. That the qualities of that which abides within the sun and that which abides in the eye are not to be combined, the text itself moreover shows by specially stating that the characteristics of the one are those of the other. For such a special transfer of qualities is needed only where the qualities are not of themselves established, i.e. where the two things are naturally different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/23/</guid>
      <description>And for the same reason the holding together and the pervading the sky. In the Taittiriyaka and in the khilas of the Rāṇāyanīyas we have the following passage: &amp;lsquo;Gathered together are the powers among which Brahman is the oldest; Brahman as the oldest in the beginning stretched out the sky. Brahman was born as the first of all beings; who may rival that Brahman?&amp;rsquo; which declares that Brahman gathered together all the most ancient powers, that it pervades the sky, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/24/</guid>
      <description>And although (they both be) meditations on man; on account of others not being recorded. In the Taittiriyaka as well as the Cḥāndogya we meet with a meditation on man (purusha-vidyā), in which parts of the sacrifice are fancifully identified with the parts of
the human body.&amp;ndash;Here the Pūrvapakshin maintains that these two meditations are identical; for, he says, both meditations have the same name (purusha-vidyā), and the same character as stated above; and as the Taittirīyaka mentions no fruit of the meditation, the fruit declared in the Cḥāndogya holds good for the Taittirīyaka also, and thus there is no difference of fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/25/</guid>
      <description>On account of the difference of sense of piercing and so on. The text of the Ātharvaṇikas exhibits at the beginning of their Upanishad some mantras, &amp;lsquo;Pierce the śukra, pierce the heart.&amp;rsquo; The followers of the Sāma-veda read at the beginning of their rahasya-brāhmaṇa &amp;lsquo;O God Savitr̥, promote the sacrifice.&amp;rsquo; The Kāṭḥakas and the Taittirīyakas have &amp;lsquo;May Mitra be propitious to us, may Varuṇa be propitious.&amp;rsquo; The Sāṭyāyanins have &amp;lsquo;Thou art a white horse, a tawny and a black one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/26/</guid>
      <description>But in the case of the getting rid of (it has to be combined with the obtaining), as it is supplementary to statements of obtaining; as in the case of the kuśas, the metres, the praise, and the singing. This has been explained.
The Cḥandogas read in their text &amp;lsquo;Shaking off all evil as a horse shakes his hair, and shaking off the body as the moon frees herself from the mouth of Rāhu, I obtain the world of Brahman &amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/27/</guid>
      <description>At departing; there being nothing to be reached. For thus others (also declare). The further question arises whether the putting off of all good and evil deeds takes place only at the time when the soul leaves the body, or also after it has departed and is on its journey to the world of Brahman. The Pūrvapakshin holds the latter view, for, he says, the texts declare both. The Kaushītakins say that the soul shakes off its good and evil deeds when it crosses the river Virajā in the world of Brahman; while the Tāṇdins say &amp;lsquo;Shaking off all evil, and shaking off the body,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/28/</guid>
      <description>As it is desired; on account of there being no contradiction of either. The time when good and evil deeds are left behind thus having been determined on the basis of the reason of the thing, the several words of the passages must be construed as it is desired, i.e. so as not to contradict either, i.e. either the declaration of scripture or the reason of the thing. Thus in the text of the Kaushītakins the later clause, &amp;lsquo;he shakes off his good and evil deeds,&amp;rsquo; must be taken as coming before the earlier passage &amp;lsquo;having entered on that path of the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/29/</guid>
      <description>There is meaning of the soul&amp;rsquo;s going (only) on the twofold hypothesis; for otherwise there is contradiction. It is only on the hypothesis of a part of the good and evil works being left behind at the time of the soul&amp;rsquo;s departure from the body, and another part later on, and the effacement of works thus taking place in a double way, that a sense can be found in the scriptural declaration of the soul proceeding on the path of the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/30/</guid>
      <description>(That assumption) is justified; on account of the perception of things which are marks of that; as in ordinary experience. The assumption of all the works perishing at the time of &amp;lsquo;departure&amp;rsquo; involves no contradiction; since we perceive, in the sacred texts, matters which are marks of connexion with a body even on the part of the soul which has divested itself of all its works and become manifest in its true nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/31/</guid>
      <description>Of those who have a certain office there is subsistence (of their works) as long as the office lasts. We do not maintain that all those who have reached true knowledge divest themselves at the time of death of all their good and evil works; we limit our view to those who immediately after death attain to moving on the path, the first stage of which is light. Persons like Vasishṭḥa, on the other hand, who are entrusted with certain offices, do not immediately after death attain to moving on the path beginning with light, since the duties undertaken by them are not completely accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/32/</guid>
      <description>There is no restriction (since) all (have to go on that path). (Thus) there is non-contradiction of sacred text and Smr̥ti. The question here is whether Brahman is to be reached on the path of the gods by those only who take their stand on those meditations which, like the Upakośala-vidyā, describe that path, or by all who practise any of the meditations on Brahman. The Pūrvapakshin holds the former view, since there is no proof to show that in other vidyās the going on that path is not mentioned, and since those other vidyās-such as the texts &amp;lsquo;and those who in the forest meditate on faith and austerities,&amp;lsquo;and&amp;rsquo; those who in the forest worship faith, the True&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/33/</guid>
      <description>But the conceptions of the Imperishable are to be comprised (in all meditations). There being equality (of the Brahman to be meditated on) and (those conceptions) existing (in Brahman); as in the case of what belongs to the upasad. This has been explained. We read in the Br̥had-āraṇyaka (III, 8, 9),&amp;lsquo;O Gārgī, the Brāhmaṇas call that the Akshara. It is neither coarse nor fine,&amp;rsquo; and so on. And in the Atharvaṇa (Mu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/34/</guid>
      <description>So much; on account of reflection. Only so much, i.e. only those qualities which have to be included in all meditations on Brahman, without which the essential special nature of Brahman cannot be conceived, i.e. bliss, knowledge, and so on, characterised by absence of grossness and the like. Other qualities, such as doing all works and the like, although indeed following their substrate, are explicitly to be meditated on in special meditations only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/35/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that (the former reply refers) to that Self to which the aggregate of material things belongs (since) otherwise the difference (of the two replies) could not be accounted for; we say&amp;ndash;no; as in the case of instruction In the Br̥had-araṇyaka (III, 4; 5) the same question is asked twice in succession (&amp;lsquo;Tell me the Brahman which is visible, not invisible, the Self who is within all&amp;rsquo;), while Yājñavalkya gives a different answer to each (&amp;lsquo;He who breathes in the upbreathing,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/36/</guid>
      <description>There is interchange (of ideas), for the texts distinguish; as in other cases. There is no difference of vidyā because both questions and answers have one subject-matter, and because the one word that possesses enjoining power proves the connexion of the two sections. Both questions have for their topic Brahman viewed as the inner Self of all; and in the second question the word &amp;rsquo;eva&amp;rsquo; (&amp;lsquo;just,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;very&amp;rsquo;) in &amp;lsquo;Tell me just that Brahman,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/37/</guid>
      <description>For one and the same (highest divinity), called the &amp;rsquo;truly being,&amp;rsquo; and so on (is the subject of that meditation). For the highest divinity, called there that which is&amp;ndash;
which was introduced in the clause &amp;rsquo;that divinity thought,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.&amp;ndash;is intimated by all the following sections of that chapter. This is proved by the fact that the attributes&amp;ndash;&amp;rsquo;that which truly is&amp;rsquo; and so on&amp;ndash;which were mentioned in the first section and confirmed in the subsequent ones, are finally summed up in the statement, &amp;lsquo;in that all this has its Self, that is the True, that is the Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/38/</guid>
      <description>Wishes and the rest, here and there; (as is known from the abode, and so on). We read in the Cḥāndogya (VIII, I, 1), &amp;lsquo;There is that city of Brahman, and in it the palace, the small lotus, and in it that small ether,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.; and in the Vājasaneyaka, &amp;lsquo;He is that great unborn Self who consists of knowledge,&amp;rsquo; and so on. A doubt here arises whether the two texts constitute one meditation or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/39/</guid>
      <description>On account of emphasis there is non-omission. Attributes, such as having the power of immediately realising one&amp;rsquo;s purposes, and so on, which are not by other means known to constitute attributes of Brahman, and are in the two texts under discussion, as well as in other texts, emphatically declared to be attributes of Brahman, as constituting the object of meditations undertaken with a view to final release, cannot be omitted from those meditations, but must be comprised within them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/40/</guid>
      <description>In the case of him who has approached (Brahman); just on that account, this being declared by the text. When the soul, released from all bonds and manifesting itself in its true nature, has approached, i.e. attained to Brahman; then just on that account, i.e. on account of such approach, the text declares it to possess the power of moving about at will in all worlds. &amp;lsquo;Having approached the highest light he manifests himself in his true form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/41/</guid>
      <description>There is non-restriction of determination, because this is seen; for there is a separate fruit, viz. non-obstruction. There are certain meditations connected with elements of sacrificial actions; as e.g. &amp;lsquo;Let a man meditate on the syllable Om as udgītha.&amp;rsquo; These meditations are subordinate elements of the sacrificial acts with which they connect themselves through the udgītha and so on, in the same way as the quality of being made of parṇa wood connects itself with the sacrifice through the ladle (made of parṇa wood), and are to be undertaken on that very account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/42/</guid>
      <description>Just as in the case of the offerings. This has been explained. In the daharavidyā (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 1 ff.) the text, &amp;rsquo;those who depart having known here the Self, and those true desires,&amp;rsquo; declares at first a meditation on the small ether, i.e. the highest Self, and separately therefrom a meditation on its qualities, viz. true desires, and so on. The doubt here arises whether, in the meditation on those qualities, the meditation on the highest Self&amp;ndash;as that to which the qualities belong&amp;ndash;is to be repeated or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/43/</guid>
      <description>On account of the plurality of indicatory marks; for that (proof) is stronger. This also is declared (in the Pūrva Mīmāmsā). The Taittirīyaka contains another daharavidyā, &amp;lsquo;The thousand-headed god, the all-eyed one,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Mahānār. Up. XI). Here the doubt arises whether this vidyā, as being one with the previously introduced vidyā, states qualities to be included in the meditation enjoined in that vidyā, or qualities to be included in the meditations on the highest Self as enjoined in all the Vedānta-texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/44/</guid>
      <description>There is option with regard to what precedes (i.e. the altar made of bricks) on account of subject-matter, and hence there is action; as in the case of the mānasa cup. In the Vājasaneyaka, in the Agnirahasya chapter, there are references to certain altars built of mind, &amp;lsquo;built of mind, built of speech,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. The doubt here arises whether those structures of mind, and so on, which metaphorically are called fire-altars, should be considered as being of the nature of action, on account of their connexion with a performance which itself is of the nature of action; or merely of the nature of meditation, as being connected with an activity of the nature of meditation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/45/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the transfer. That the altar built of thought is an optional substitute for the altar built of bricks, and of the nature of an action, appears therefrom also that the clause &amp;lsquo;of these each one is as great as that previous one,&amp;rsquo; explicitly transfers to the altars of mind, and so on, the powers of the previous altar made of bricks. All those altars thus having equal effects there is choice between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/46/</guid>
      <description>But it is a meditation only, on account of assertion and what is seen. The altars built of mind, and so on, are not of the nature of action, but of meditation only, i.e. they belong to a performance which is of the nature of meditation only. For this is what the text asserts, viz. in the clauses &amp;rsquo;they are built of knowledge only,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;by knowledge they are built for him who thus knows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/47/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the greater strength of direct statement, and so on, there is no refutation. The weaker means of proof, constituted by so-called leading subject-matter, cannot refute what is established by three stronger means of proof&amp;ndash;direct statement, inferential mark, and syntactical connexion&amp;ndash;viz. that there is an independent purely mental performance, and that the altars made of mind are parts of the latter. The direct statement is contained in the following passage, &amp;lsquo;Those fire-altars indeed are built of knowledge,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which is further explained in the subsequent passage, &amp;lsquo;by knowledge alone these altars are built for him who knows this&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the sense of which is: the structures of mind, and so on, are built in connexion with a performance which consists of knowledge (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/48/</guid>
      <description>On account of connexions and the rest, as in the case of the separateness of other cognitions. And this is seen (elsewhere also); as declared (in the Pūrva Mīmāṁsā). That the text enjoins a meditative performance different from the actual performance of which the brick-altar is a constituent element, follows from the reasons proving separation, viz. the connexions. i.e. the things connected with the sacrifice, such as the Soma cups, the hymns, the recitations, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/49/</guid>
      <description>Not so, on account of this being observed on account of similarity also; as in the case of Death; for (the person in yonder orb) does not occupy the worlds (of Death). From a transfer or assimilation of this kind it does not necessarily follow that things of different operation are equal, and that hence those altars of mind, and so on, must connect themselves with an actual outward performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/50/</guid>
      <description>And by a subsequent (Brāhmaṇa) also the &amp;lsquo;being of such a kind&amp;rsquo; of the word (is proved). But the connexion is on account of plurality. The subsequent Brāhmaṇa (Śat. Br. X, 5, 4) also proves that the text treating of the altars made of mind, and so on, enjoins a meditation only. For that Brāhmaṇa (which begins &amp;lsquo;This brick-built fire-altar is this world; the waters are its enclosing-stones,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.) declares further on &amp;lsquo;whosoever knows this thus comes to be that whole Agni who is the space-filler,&amp;rsquo; and from this it appears that what is enjoined there is a meditation with a special result of its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>51</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/51/</guid>
      <description>Some, on account of the existence of a Self within a body. In all meditations on the highest Self the nature of the meditating subject has to be ascertained no less than the nature of the object of meditation and of the mode of meditation. The question then arises whether the meditating Self is to be viewed as the knowing, doing, and enjoying Self, subject to transmigration; or as that Self which Prajāpati describes (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/52/</guid>
      <description>But this is not so, (but rather) difference; since it is of the being of that; as in the case of intuition. It is not true that the meditating subject must be conceived as having the ordinary characteristics of knowing, acting, &amp;amp;c.; it rather possesses those characteristic properties&amp;ndash;freedom from evil, and so on&amp;ndash;which distinguish the state of Release from the Saṁsāra state. At the time of meditation the Self of the devotee is of exactly the same nature as the released Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>53</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/53/</guid>
      <description>But those (meditations) which are connected with members (of sacrifices) are not (restricted) to (particular) śākhās, but rather (belong) to all śākhās. There are certain meditations connected with certain constituent elements of sacrifices-as e.g. &amp;lsquo;Let a man meditate on the syllable Om (as) the Udgītha &amp;lsquo;(Kh. Up. I, 1, 1); &amp;lsquo;Let a man meditate on the fivefold Saman as the five worlds&amp;rsquo; (Kh. Up. II, 2, 1), &amp;amp;c. The question here arises whether those meditations are restricted to the members of those śākhās in whose texts they are mentioned; or to be connected with the Udgītha, and so on, in all śākhās.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>54</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/54/</guid>
      <description>Or there is no contradiction as in the case of mantras and the rest. The &amp;lsquo;or&amp;rsquo; here has the sense of &amp;lsquo;and.&amp;rsquo; The &amp;lsquo;and the rest&amp;rsquo; comprises generic characteristics, qualities, number, similarity, order of succession, substances, and actions. As there is nothing contrary to reason in mantras and the rest, although mentioned in the text of one śākhā only, finding, on the basis of such means of proof as direct statement, and so on, their application in all śākhās, since the sacrifice to which they belong is one and the same in all śākhās; so there is likewise no contradiction in the meditations under discussion being undertaken by members of all śākhās.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>55</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/55/</guid>
      <description>There is pre-eminence of plenitude, as in the case of the sacrifice; for thus Scripture shows. The sacred text (Cḥ. Up. V, 12 ff.) enjoins a meditation on Vaiśvānara, the object of which is the highest Self, as having for its body the entire threefold world, and for its limbs the heavenly world, the sun, the wind, and so on. The doubt here arises whether separate meditations have to be performed on the highest Being in its separate aspects, or in its aggregate as well as in its distributed aspect, or in its aggregate aspect only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>56</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/56/</guid>
      <description>(The meditations are) separate, on account of the difference of words, and so on. The instances coming under this head of discussion are all those meditations on Brahman which have for their only result final Release, which consists in attaining to Brahman&amp;ndash;such as the meditation on that which is, the meditation on the bhūman, the meditation on the small space within the heart, the Upakośala meditation, the Śāṇḍilya meditation, the meditation on Vaiśvānara, the meditation on the Self of bliss, the meditation on the Imperishable, and others&amp;ndash;whether they be recorded in one śākhā only or in several śākhās.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>57</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/57/</guid>
      <description>Option, on account of the non-difference of result. It has been proved that the meditation on that which truly is, the meditation on the small ether within the heart, and so on&amp;ndash;all of which have for their result the attainment to Brahman&amp;ndash;are separate meditations. The question now arises whether all these meditations should be combined by each meditating devotee, on account of such combination being useful to him; or whether, in the absence of any use of such combination, they should be</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>59</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/59/</guid>
      <description>They belong to the constituent members, as the bases. A doubt arises whether meditations such as the one enjoined in the text, &amp;lsquo;Let him meditate on the syllable Om as the Udgītha,&amp;rsquo; which are connected with constituent elements of the sacrifice such as the Udgītha, contribute towards the accomplishment of the sacrifice, and hence must be performed at the sacrifice as part of it; or whether they, like the godohana vessel, benefit the agent apart from the sacrifice, and therefore may be undertaken according to desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/60/</guid>
      <description>And on account of injunction. The above conclusion is further confirmed by the fact of injunction, i.e. thereby that clauses such as &amp;lsquo;he is to meditate on the Udgītha&amp;rsquo; enjoin the meditation as standing to the Udgītha in the relation of a subordinate member. Injunctions of this kind differ from injunctions such as &amp;lsquo;he is to bring water in the godohana vessel for him who desires cattle&amp;rsquo;; for the latter state a special qualification on the part of him who performs the action, while the former do not, and hence cannot claim independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>61</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/61/</guid>
      <description>On account of rectification. The text &amp;lsquo;from the seat of the Hotr̥ he sets right the wrong Udgīha&amp;rsquo; shows that the meditation is necessarily required for the purpose of correcting whatever mistake may be made in the Udgītha. This also proves that the meditation is an integral part of the sacrificial performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>62</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/62/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/62/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the declaration of a quality being common (to all the Vedas). The text &amp;lsquo;By means of that syllable the threefold knowledge proceeds. With Oṁ the Adhvaryu gives orders,
with Oṁ the Hotr̥ recites, with Oṁ the Udgātr̥ sings,&amp;rsquo; which declares the praṇava&amp;ndash;which is a &amp;lsquo;quality&amp;rsquo; of the meditation, in so far as it is its basis&amp;ndash;to be common to the three Vedas, further shows that the meditation has to be employed in connexion with the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>63</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/63/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/63/</guid>
      <description>Rather not, as the text does not declare their going together. It is not true that the meditations on the Udgītha and the rest are bound to the sacrifices in the same way as the Udgītha, and so on, themselves are; for Scripture does not declare that they go together with, i.e. are subordinate constituents of the Udgītha, and so on. The clause &amp;lsquo;Let him meditate on the Udgītha&amp;rsquo; does not indeed itself state another qualification on the part of the agent (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>64</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/3/64/</guid>
      <description>And because (Scripture) shows it. A scriptural text, moreover, shows that the meditation is necessary for, and restricted to, the sacrificial performance. For the text &amp;lsquo;A Brahman priest who knows this saves the sacrifice, the sacrificcr, and all the officiating priests&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which declares that all priests are saved through the knowledge of the Brahman&amp;ndash;has sense only on the understanding that that knowledge is not restricted to the Udjātr̥, and so on (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
