<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/01/</guid>
      <description>FOURTH PĀDA. Thus the prāṇas. After having taught that Ether and all the other elements are effects, and hence have originated, the Sūtras had shown that the individual soul, although likewise an effect, does not originate in the sense of undergoing a change of essential nature; and had in connexion therewith clearly set forth wherein the essential nature of the soul consists. They now proceed to elucidate the question as to the origination of the instruments of the individual soul, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/02/</guid>
      <description>(The scriptural statement of the plural) is secondary, on account of impossibility; and since (the highest Self) is declared before that. The plural form exhibited by the text must be taken (not in its literal, but) in a secondary figurative sense, since there is no room there for a plurality of things. For Scripture
declares that previous to creation the highest Self only exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/03/</guid>
      <description>On account of speech having for its antecedent that. For the following reason also the word &amp;lsquo;prāṇa,&amp;rsquo; in the text quoted, can denote Brahman only. Speech, i.e. the names which have for their object all things apart from Brahman, presupposes the existence of the entire universe of things&amp;ndash;ether, and so on&amp;ndash;which is the object of speech. But, as according to the text &amp;rsquo;this was then non-differentiated; it was thereupon differentiated by names and forms,&amp;rsquo; then (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/04/</guid>
      <description>(They are seven) on account of the going of the seven and of specification. The question here arises whether those organs are seven only, or eleven&amp;ndash;the doubt on this point being due to the conflicting nature of scriptural texts.&amp;ndash;The Pūrvapakshin maintains the former alternative.&amp;ndash;On what grounds?&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;On account of going, and of specification.&amp;rsquo; For the text refers to the &amp;lsquo;going,&amp;rsquo; i.e. to the moving about in the different worlds, together with the soul when being born or dying, of seven prāṇas only, &amp;lsquo;seven are these worlds in which the prāṇas move which rest in the cave, being placed there as seven and seven&amp;rsquo; (Mu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/05/</guid>
      <description>But the hands and so on also; (since they assist the soul) abiding (in the body). Hence (it is) not so. The organs are not seven only, but eleven, since the hands and the rest also contribute towards the experience and fruition of that which abides in the body, i.e. the soul, and have their separate offices, such as seizing, and so on. Hence it is not so, i.e. it must not be thought that the hands and the rest are not organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/06/</guid>
      <description>And (they are) minute. As the text &amp;rsquo;these are all alike, all infinite&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. I, 5, 13), declares speech, mind, and breath to be infinite, we conclude that the prāṇas are all-pervading.&amp;ndash;To this the Sūtra replies, that they are minute; for the text &amp;lsquo;when the vital breath passes out of the body, all the prāṇas pass out after it&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. V, 4, 2), proves those prāṇas to be of limited size, and as when passing out they are not perceived by bystanders, they must be of minute size&amp;ndash;The text which speaks of them as infinite is a text enjoining meditation (&amp;lsquo;he who meditates on them as infinite&amp;rsquo;), and infinity there means only that abundance of activities which is an attribute of the prāṇa to be meditated on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/07/</guid>
      <description>And the best. By &amp;rsquo;the best&amp;rsquo; we have to understand the chief vital air (mukhya prāṇa), which, in the colloquy of the prāṇas, is determined to be the best because it is the cause of the preservation of the body. This chief vital air the Pūrvapakshin maintains to be something non-created, since Scripture (R̥. Saṁh. V, 129, 2), &amp;lsquo;By its own law the One was breathing without wind,&amp;rsquo; shows that an effect of it, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/08/</guid>
      <description>Neither air nor function, on account of its being stated separately. Is this main vital breath nothing else but air, the second of the elements? Or is it a certain motion of the air? Or is it air that has assumed some special condition?&amp;ndash;The first alternative may be adopted, on account of the text &amp;lsquo;prāṇa is air.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Or, since mere air is not called breath, while this term is generally applied to that motion of air which consists in inhalation and exhalation, we may hold that breath is a motion of air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/09/</guid>
      <description>But like the eye and the rest, on account of being taught with them, and for other reasons. Breath is not an element, but like sight and the rest, a special instrument of the soul. This appears from the fact that the texts mention it together with the recognised organs of the soul, the eye, and so on; so e.g. in the colloquy of the prāṇas. And such common mention is suitable in the case of such things only as belong to one class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/10/</guid>
      <description>And there is no objection on account of its not having an activity (karaṇa); for (Scripture) thus declares. The karaṇa of the Sūtra means kriyā, action. The objection raised on the ground that the principal breath does not exercise any form of activity helpful to the soul, is without force, since as a matter of fact Scripture declares that there is such an activity, in so far as the vital breath supports the body with all its organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/11/</guid>
      <description>It is designated as having five functions like mind. As desire, and so on, are not principles different from mind, although they are different functions and produce different effects&amp;ndash;according to the text, &amp;lsquo;Desire, purpose, doubt, faith, want of faith, firmness, absence of firmness, shame, reflection, fear&amp;ndash;all this is mind&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. I,,5, 3); so, on the ground of the text, &amp;lsquo;prāṇa, apāna, vyāna, udāna, samāna&amp;ndash;all this is prāṇa&amp;rsquo; (ibid.), apāna and the rest must be held to be different functions of prāṇa only, not independent principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/12/</guid>
      <description>And (it is) minute. This prāṇa also is minute, since as before (i.e. as in the case of the organs) the text declares it to pass out of the body, to move, and so on, &amp;lsquo;him when he passes out the prāṇa follows after&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. V, 4, 2). A further doubt arises, in the case of prāṇa, owing to the fact that in other texts it is spoken of as of large extent, &amp;lsquo;It is equal to these three worlds, equal to this Universe&amp;rsquo; (Br̥.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/13/</guid>
      <description>But the rule (over the prāṇas) on the part of Fire and the rest, together with him to whom the prāṇa belong (i.e. the soul), is owing to the thinking of that (viz. the highest Self); on account of scriptural statement. It has been shown that the prāṇas, together with the main prāṇa, originate from Brahman, and have a limited size. That the prāṇas are guided by Agni and other divine beings has also been explained on a previous occasion, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/14/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the eternity of this. As the quality, inhering in all things, of being ruled by the highest Self, is eternal and definitely fixed by being connected with his essential nature, it is an unavoidable conclusion that the rule of the soul and of the divinities over the organs depends on the will of the highest Self. The text, &amp;lsquo;Having sent forth this he entered into it, having entered into it he became sat and tyat&amp;rsquo; (Taitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/15/</guid>
      <description>They, with the exception of the best, are organs, on account of being so designated. Are all principles called prāṇas to be considered as &amp;lsquo;organs&amp;rsquo; (indriyāṇi), or is the &amp;lsquo;best,&amp;rsquo; i.e. the chief prāṇa, to be excepted?&amp;ndash;All of them, without exception, are organs; for they all are called prāṇas equally, and they all are instruments of the soul.&amp;ndash;Not so, the Sūtra replies. The &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; one is to be excepted, since only the prawas other than the best are designated as organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/16/</guid>
      <description>On account of scriptural statement of difference, and on account of difference of characteristics. Texts such as &amp;lsquo;from him is born prāṇa, and the internal organ, and all organs&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. II, 1, 3) mention the vital breath separately from the organs, and this shows that the breath is not one of the organs. The passage indeed mentions the internal organ (manas) also as something separate; but in other passages the manas is formally included in the organs, &amp;rsquo;the (five) organs with mind as the sixth&amp;rsquo; (Bha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/17/</guid>
      <description>But the making of names and forms (belongs) to him who renders tripartite, on account of scriptural teaching. The Sūtras have shown that the creation of the elements and organs in their collective aspect (samashṭi) and the activity of the individual souls proceed from the highest Self; and they have also further confirmed the view that the rule which the souls exercise over their organs depends on the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/18/</guid>
      <description>Flesh is of earthy nature; in the case of the two others also according to the text. The view that the description of tripartition, given in the passage &amp;rsquo;each of these he made tripartite,&amp;rsquo; refers to a time subsequent to the creation of the mundane egg and to the gods created by Brahmā, cannot be upheld. For from it there would follow that, as in the passage &amp;rsquo;earth when eaten is disposed of in three ways,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/4/19/</guid>
      <description>But on account of their distinctive nature there is that designation, that designation. Each element indeed is of a threefold nature, owing to the primary tripartition; but as in each mixed element one definite element prevails&amp;ndash;so that each element has a distinctive character of its own&amp;ndash;a definite designation is given to each.&amp;ndash;The repetition (of &amp;rsquo;that designation&amp;rsquo;) in the Sūtra indicates the completion of the adhyāya.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;the fashioning of names and forms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
