<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 The Āgamasiddhānta in the Pāñcarātrarakṣā on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 The Āgamasiddhānta in the Pāñcarātrarakṣā on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) What became of the Āgamasiddhāntins?: A short summary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/1_i_What_became_of_the_AgamasiddhAntins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/1_i_What_became_of_the_AgamasiddhAntins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have argued in the first three chapters that the idea of the supremacy of the JS, SS and PauṣS appears to have emerged, probably no earlier than the twelfth century, within the South Indian Pāñcarātra tradition which called itself the Āgamasiddhānta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tradition associated itself with the so-called Ekāyanaveda, an apparently mythical Urtext which in reality may have been represented by the &lt;em&gt;Jayākhyasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (JS), *Sātvatasaṃhitā *(SS) and *Pauṣkarasaṃhitā *(PauṣS). This is suggested, at least, by the *Śrīpraśnasaṃhitā *(ŚrīprśS 49.471c-473), and by the much later commentator Alaśiṅgabhaṭṭa in his *Sātvatārthaprakāśikā *(on &lt;em&gt;Īśvarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; 1.64-67). The idea of there being four Pāñcarātra Siddhāntas may also have emerged among Āgamasiddhāntins or Ekāyanas, since its earliest articulation is probably that found in the PauṣS (38.293-307b), and the majority of extant lists of the four Siddhāntas name the Āgamasiddhānta as the highest of the four.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) Vedāntadeśika’s defence of the Āgamasiddhānta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/2_ii_vedAntadeshika-s_defence_of_the_Aga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/2_ii_vedAntadeshika-s_defence_of_the_Aga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the PārS and the &lt;em&gt;Kōyiloḷuku&lt;/em&gt;, the Śrīraṅgam temple chronicle, provide ample evidence (see Rastelli 2006: 243-244) that the Ekāyanas were active in Śrīraṅgam in the 12th and (probably early) 13th centuries, there is not, to my knowledge, a comparable body of evidence which can demonstrate that they remained active there as late as the early fourteenth century i.e. when Vedāntadeśika composed the PRR and was &lt;em&gt;ācārya&lt;/em&gt; at the Raṅganāthasvāmin temple. However, the PRR itself contains several passages which suggest that this very probably &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the case. For it is difficult to overlook the fact that in his defence of the Pāñcarātra, Vedāntadeśika lends his support in particular to the Āgamasiddhānta. Thus, in the opening section of the PRR’s first chapter, Vedāntadeśika establishes that the Āgamasiddhānta is the [[231]] primary Siddhānta. In support of this he quotes (at PRR 6.4 &lt;em&gt;ff&lt;/em&gt;) PauṣS 38.293c-305, and (at 8.5-8) the *Hayagrīvasaṃhitā *(otherwise known as the &lt;em&gt;Hayaśīrṣapañcarātra&lt;/em&gt;), both of which list the Āgamasiddhānta at the top of the Siddhānta hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/3_iii_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/4_The_AgamasiddhAnta_in_the_pAncharAtrar/3_iii_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vedāntadeśika’s defence of the Āgamasiddhānta appears to indicate that this tradition was especially subject to external criticism. This criticism may have come from within the Vaikhānasa tradition. We know that Vaikhānasas were present in Śrīraṅgam. In my view it is unlikely, however, that criticism from this source would have had a significant impact on the decline of the Āgamasiddhānta. If I am correct in proposing that the Āgamasiddhānta was integrated into other Pāñcarātra traditions, then an important question remains. Why did this happen? Why, for example, did it not happen the other way round? The fact that Āgamasiddhāntins appear to have been a minority within the South Indian Pāñcarātra may have been a partial cause of the direction that this integrative process appears to have taken, but it is not an explanation. Why, then, were Āgamasiddhāntins a minority? [[238]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
