<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;सत्यनारायणः - सिद्धान्त-सम्प्रदायौ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;सत्यनारायणः - सिद्धान्त-सम्प्रदायौ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TODO: परिष्कार्यम्&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्री विखनस आश्रमम्, तिरुमल,&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिध्दान्त विवर्धिनी सभा&#xA;वैखानस सिद्धान्त और सम्प्रदाय&#xA;प्रथम भाग&#xA;रचयिता :&#xA;दे. सत्यनारायण&#xA;Shayar&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिद्धान्त विवर्द्धिनी सभा&#xA;तिरुमल,&#xA;२०००.&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला संख्या : ११.&#xA;ఏ వైఖానస&#xA;प्रधान सम्पादक :&#xA;दीवि विखनसाचार्य&#xA;తిరుమల&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिद्धान्त विवर्द्धिनी सभा तिरुमल,&#xA;२०००.&#xA;© लेखक : दे. सत्यनारायण&#xA;This book is published with the Financial Assistance of TIRUMALA TIRUPATI DEVASTHANAMS, TIRUPATI.&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला संख्या : ११&#xA;प्रतियां : १,०००.&#xA;मूल्य : पचास रुपये.&#xA;Copies can be had from: THE SECRETARY, S.V.D.S.V.Sabha,&#xA;Sri Vikhanasa Ashramam, Ring Road, TIRUMALA.(A.P.) Pin: 517 504&#xA;Copies can be had from:&#xA;SRI VAIKHANASA SAMAJAM, 29-1-19, Seshadri Sastry St., Governorpet, VIJAYAWADA. (A.P.) Pin: 520 002.&#xA;डि.टि.पि.: : 30807&#xA;श्री सत्यसाई ग्राफिक्स,&#xA;के. टि. रोड, तिरुपति.&#xA;Printers: 435393 THE VANI PRESS, VIJAYAWADA.&#xA;OM NAMO VENKATESAYA OM VIKHANASAYA NAMAHA&#xA;Foreward&#xA;This is a book which represents our efforts to introduce the Vaikhanasa religion and philosophy to the people. This is not ob- scure in the sense that there is no material but is less known to com- mon man. Even the scholars are not fully aware of the contribution of the Vaikhanasa system in the totality of the indological literature particularly the religious one. The Vaikhanasa system has an unbro- ken continuity from the times immemorial. During the middle ages also the Archakas following the Vaikhanasa religion were adminis- tering the temple services particularly in the South. Vedic traditions were kept alive throughout that turpulents period. This small com- munity of the Vaikhanas is responsible for keeping the institution of puja in all the temples throughout India by using Vedic mantras. Vernacularism in the temple administration was not allowed to re- place the Devavani. Tradition of temple worship as an institution was strengthened in spite of onslaught by muslim invaders and per- sonal rivalry of the kings or chieftains of the small principalities patronising a particular religious teacher.&#xA;Vaikhanasa Agama deals with worship in Vishnu temples according to Vedic tradion. Sage Sri Vikhanasacharya is the founder teacher of this system. He came to Naimisaranya and taught this Agama to four disciples. They are Sages Bhrugu, Mareechi, Atri and Kasyapa. These sages have written twenty eight books and they are known as Vaikhanasa Bhagavat Sastra or Sri Sastra. These texts explain in detail about the construction of temples, preparation of Icons, installation of Icons, Daily worship and Utsavas etc. They also explain Ashtanga Yoga and Archana i.e. Bhakti Marga.&#xA;The author Sri Devarakonda Satyanarayana garu of Tirupati has taken great pains to compile a book of this nature. The book has been written through a historical perceptive. This is the first&#xA;attempt to write any book on this subject in Hindi. We are very much thankful to the author.&#xA;The book presses into service the available literature in the field and draws from Bhuddism, Nath system and many other small religious groups who do not claim to have any text except folk reli- gion living only in tradition without any written document.&#xA;The author has made special studies of early and medieval Vaisnavism and his labours are before the scholars to judge.&#xA;When we intend to publish this book, we have approached T.T. Devasthanams for financial aid. They have supported our re- quest and granted the aid. We are thankful to Sri I.V. Subba Rao, L.A.S., Executive Officer, for this timely help and support. We are also thnakful to Sri N.S. Rama Murthy, M.A., Editor, T.T. Devasthanams for his timely action and good offices to get the fi- nancial aid granted.&#xA;We are also thankful to Sri Vaikhanasa Samaj, Vijayawada for their voluntary co-operation to involve in this project. We can- not forget the help given by Sri Suresh Kumar Gupta, S/o Sri Hari Ram Gupta, New Delhi who are very generous in supplying the paper required for this project with the good offices of Dr. Brijendra Kumar Sharma, New Delhi.&#xA;Last but not least, we thank M/s. Sri Satya Sai Graphics, Tirupati for DTP composing of the book neatly within the time. We also thank M/s. The Vani Press, Vijayawada for printing the&#xA;book.&#xA;Tirumala, 21-6-2000.&#xA;D. Vikhanasa Chary,&#xA;Secretary&#xA;S.V.D.S.V.Sabha, Tirumala.&#xA;वैखानस सिद्धान्त और सम्प्रदाय&#xA;विषयसूची&#xA;१. आमुख&#xA;२.&#xA;अध्याय एक&#xA;जीवनके प्रति दृष्टिकोण - 11, मोक्ष - 14,&#xA;साधना की एकता- 17, संस्कार - 21,&#xA;व्यूह - 19, ऋत - 31, समाज सेवा - 35,&#xA;1&#xA;11-61&#xA;समन्वय 40, इतिहास - 52, वैखानस प्रशंसा 54.&#xA;३.&#xA;अध्याय दो&#xA;62-75&#xA;काल - 62, देश - 70, वेङ्ग - 73.&#xA;४.&#xA;अध्याय तीन&#xA;76-132&#xA;५.&#xA;६.&#xA;विखनस ऋषि - 76, वैखानस वेद - 82, वैखानस सूत्र - 83,&#xA;आगम - 87, वैखानस वाङ्मय वैखानस की प्राचीनता - 88, उख - 97, वैखानस - 97, वाजसनेय - 101,&#xA;पेखानस के उपभेद - 114, रामायण - 116,&#xA;एहाभारत -118, पुराण -123, बालखिल्य - 131.&#xA;अध्याय चार&#xA;अत्रि - 133, कश्यप - 137, भृगु - 142, मरीचि - 145.&#xA;अध्याय पांच&#xA;वैखानस दर्शन - 150, वैखानस सम्प्रदाय में लक्ष्मी - 153 मोक्ष - 160, मुक्ति - 163, प्रपत्ति - 169, लक्ष्मी - 173, वेद में स्त्री देवता - 186, अवतार - 189, अर्चावतार - 194, अवतारों की संख्या - 195.&#xA;SO&#xA;133-149&#xA;150-198&#xA;वैखानस सिद्धान्त और सम्प्रदाय प्रथम खण्ड&#xA;आमुख&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/articles/satyanArAyaNaH_siddhAnta-sampradAyau/2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TODO: परिष्कार्यम्&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;वैखानस सिध्दान्त और सम्प्रदाय&#xA;व्दितीय भाग&#xA;रचयिताः दे. सत्यनारायण&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिध्दान्त विवर्धिनी सभा&#xA;तिरुमल&#xA;૨૦૦૨&#xA;श्री विखनस आश्रमम्, तिरुमल,&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिध्दान्त विवर्धिनी सभा&#xA;वैखानस सिध्दान्त और सम्प्रदाय&#xA;व्दितीय भाग&#xA;रचयिताः&#xA;दे. सत्यनारायण&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिध्दान्त विवर्धिनी सभा&#xA;तिरुमल&#xA;૨૦૦૨&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला संख्या : २२.&#xA;प्रधान सम्पादक :&#xA;दीवि श्रीनिवास दीक्षित्&#xA;దివ&#xA;తిరుమల&#xA;श्री वैखानस दिव्य सिध्दान्त विवर्धिनी सभा&#xA;तिरुमल&#xA;૨૦૦૨&#xA;o लेखक : दे. सत्यनारायण&#xA;This book is published with the Financial Assistance of TIRUMALA TIRUPATHI DEVASTHANAMS, TIRUPATI.&#xA;मरीचि ग्रन्थमाला संख्या : १२.&#xA;प्रतियां - १,०००.&#xA;मूल्य: पचास रुपये.&#xA;Copies can be had from: THE SECRETARY, S.V.D.S.V. Sabha,&#xA;Sri Vikhanasa Ashramam, Ring Road, TIRUMALA.(A.P.) Pin: 517504.&#xA;Copies can be had from: SRI VAIKHANASA SAMAJAM, A2, Dee-Vee Apartments, Navodaya Colony, VIJAYAWADA.(A.P.) Pin: 520 010.&#xA;डि.टि.पि. : 30807. श्री सत्यसाई ग्राफिक्स,&#xA;के.टि. रोड, तिरुपति.&#xA;Printers: 435393 THE VANI PRESS, VIJAYAWADA&#xA;Foreward&#xA;The second part of the Vaikhanasa Siddhantha and Sampradaya is now in the hands of the readers. As the title states the book with the Siddhantha and the Sampradaya of Sri Vaikhanasas i.e., the basic priciples of the Philosophy of the Vaikhanasa sect and Sampradaya the institutions that have been created to propagate the religion and the institutions that help to foster the religious functions of the sect.&#xA;The second part has five chapters, the 6th Chapter deals with the religious institutions pooja and the necessary details sectarian and comparative, the 7th Chapter deals with the Vaikhanasa Society, the institution that created to safeguards the character of the society, structure of the society, the marriage, education and goal of life, activities to achieve the same incidentally the use of metals, jewels, the concepts of ornamentation of the utensils of daily use as also the facilitating pots in the process of pooja are also enumerated. The 8th Chapter has two topics, the Idol and the Temple. History of Idol worship, Idol as a symbol of reverence and bestower of Grace, the history of Idol worship in India, its ramifications, temple its place in the Society impact on the human society and how it develop a human being into a more human soul. The 9th Chapter deals with Kriyayoga and instrumentality of Yoga system and deviation from the classical yoga system of Patanjali. The 10th Chapter gives summary of the contribution of the Vaikhanasa as a philosophy, religion and the society in the wider Indian Context.&#xA;The comparative study of social structure as given in Manu and Vaikhanasa system, the comparative study of the Yoga system and the Yoga principles as presented in Marichi are given to elaborate the religious functions of the same and special contibution of the Sect to the world literature on religious practices.&#xA;We thank the Author Sri Devarakonda Sathyanarayana Garu for the labours he undertook in writing the book giving the&#xA;institutions developed by the Vaikhanasa Sect and in turn the institutions thus developed help the Vaikahnasa Sampradaya to develop. There is much material available in Vaikhanasa literature on architecture, sculpture, Iconography and allied topics and much material on puja, its contents, serial order, the number of such actions, the relationship of such actions and other topics important for puja ceremony.&#xA;During the printing of the book our Sabha Secretary late Sri D.Vikhanasa Charyulu expired before he could see the printed book. We regret his demise.&#xA;We are very greatful to the T.T.D. authorities in particular to the Executive Officer, Dr. P.Krishnaiah, I.A.S., as well Dr. I.V. Subbarao, I.A.S. who took interest in this publication. We appreciate the efforts of Dr. N.S.Rama Murthy, the Editor, T.T.D Publications.&#xA;We are thankful to Sri G.Prabhakara Charyulu for his untiring and enthusiastic assistance in this project which has a special contribution to the religious literature of India. So far known only to the followers of the Vaikhanasa Sect now in Hindi will help particularlythe North Indians for whom it is primarily intended.&#xA;We are thankful to Sri Vaikhanasa Samajam, Vijayawada for their consistent and continued help and assistance in the publication of the Vaikhanasa Literature.&#xA;We are thankful to Sri Sathya Sai Graphics, Tirupathi for D.T.P.execution neatly and qualitative style and M/s. Vani Press, Vijayawada for printing this bopok, nicely and in time.&#xA;Tirumala&#xA;Date:22nd Aug 2002.&#xA;D.S. Deekshitulu,&#xA;SECRETARY,&#xA;S.V.D.S.V. Sabha,&#xA;Tirumala.&#xA;॥ श्रीः ॥&#xA;श्रीमदाचार्यवंशतिः&#xA;अथ नैमिशभूविभूषणं मुनिसन्दोहमहप्रवर्धनम् । मम लोचनगोचरीभवत्वखिलाचार्य तवाद्भुतं वपुः कुशसंस्तरवर्ति रौरवाजिनसम्भावितपद्मकासनम् । उपकण्ठलसत्कमण्डलु ज्वलितं ब्रह्ममयेन तेजसा&#xA;नखरप्रतिबिम्वितानतत्रिदश श्रेणिविशेषशोभिना । जगदुद्धरणोरुविक्रमक्रमवत्पादयुगेन शोभितम्&#xA;अधिकायतबाहुकन्दलीमृदुलस्पर्शसुखं समीयुषा ।&#xA;॥ १ ॥&#xA;॥ २ ॥&#xA;॥ ३ ॥&#xA;॥ ५ ॥&#xA;कनकच्छविना बलीयसा महता जानुयुगेन लक्षितम् ॥ ४ करिहस्तमनोहराकृति स्विकया मुग्धरुचाऽवजानता । क्रमवृत्तकृशेन मांसलस्फुरदुरुद्वितयेन योजितम् परिणद्धमहार्घविस्फुरद्घनपीताम्बरकान्तिशोभिना । रथचक्रविशालमञ्जुना कटिभागेन समुत्कटश्रियम् सदसद्विशयार्थचुम्बिना स्मरनाराचसमानजन्मना । उदरेण परिष्कृतं श्रुतिस्मृतिजाताधिकभारवाहिना&#xA;नियतोर्ध्ववसारिसद्धृणारसरोचिर्नतरोमराजिकम् । घुसरिन्द्रमविभ्रमास्पदस्थितिमद्गह्नरनिम्ननाभिकम् जगदुद्भववृत्तिसंहृतक्षमनारायणभव्यधर्मणा । सतताध्युषितेन योजितं हृदयेन स्वगुणैरहापितैः&#xA;सदृशेन पयोधिकन्यकाकमितुर्भव्यविहारसङ्गतेः ।&#xA;॥ ६&#xA;|| 19 |&#xA;॥ ८ ॥&#xA;॥ ९ ॥&#xA;फणितल्परुचिं विलुम्पता परिघाऽपोवरवक्षसाऽन्वितम् ॥ १० ॥&#xA;कलधौतमयप्रविस्फुरद्गलितान्तस्तिमिरोपवीतवत् ।&#xA;तुलसीपरिवासितं लसद्वनमालामणिहारराजितम्&#xA;वरदानचणाभयादराम्बुजदण्डत्रयमञ्जुदर्शनैः । प्रणताहितपश्यतोहरैः युगसङ्घयैरुपलक्षित करेः करुणारसपुष्टकन्धरं करिदन्ताभकपोलमण्डलम् । अरुणाधरमञ्चितं दृढः समतिग्मैरतिशोभनैः रदैः अभिराममपास्तदोषया सततं रेचकपूरकादिभिः । सुमनोवरचित्तचोरया कमनीयाकृतिभासिनासया&#xA;भुजगाभभुजाग्रनर्तनस्मयवत्कुण्डलमण्डितश्रुति । समयोन्मिषिताम्बुजच्छदप्रतिमासेचनकायतेक्षणम्&#xA;स्तिमितासितपक्ष्म भास्वरारुणनेत्रान्तविनीलतारकम् ।&#xA;पृथुकूर्चकपार्श्वव्रिस्फुरत्कुटिलभूलतिकाविराजितम्&#xA;निशया परिशोभितान्तरस्थलदीव्यद्धवलोर्ध्वपुण्ड्रकम् । सुविशालललाटसुन्दरं शरदिन्दुद्युतितस्कराननम्&#xA;॥ ११ ॥&#xA;॥ १२ ॥&#xA;॥ १३ ॥&#xA;॥ १४ ॥&#xA;M १५&#xA;॥ १६ ॥&#xA;॥ १७॥&#xA;मुनिमण्डलसार्वभौमतां सहसा व्यञ्जयता निरङ्कुशाम् । मुनिवेषविलक्षणेन सन्मकुटेन ज्वलितेन भूषितम् ॥ १८ ॥ वपुरित्थमुपघ्नतां भजत्तव देवावतु मामनारतम् । अशुचिं श्रुतवृत्तदुर्विधं भगवन्निग्रहपात्रमर्धकम्&#xA;अभवाय मनोभवाय ते जलजातोदरसम्भवाय च ।&#xA;॥ १९&#xA;जगत प्रभवाय साक्षिणे विखनस्ते भगवन् नमो नमः ॥२०॥&#xA;पार्थसारथिःअध्याय छह&#xA;धर्म और दर्शन&#xA;धर्म मानवीय अनुभव है। अन्य शास्त्रों के समान तर्क की सीमा में नियन्त्रित किया जा सकता है इस पर भारत में मतैक्य नहीं है। यह अनुभव इन्द्रियातीत है अतः भौतिक वस्तुओं पर लागू नियम अतीन्द्रिय क्षेत्र में प्रवृत्त नहीं हो सकते&#xA;दर्शन ज्ञान का या ज्ञान की प्राप्ति का पर्याय है। ज्ञान का अर्थ इन्द्रियद्वारा प्राप्त ज्ञान और अतीन्द्रिय ज्ञान दोनों हैं। दर्शन वस्तुओं के तर्क संगत निर्धारण और इन पदार्थों के बीच स्थित सम्बन्ध को व्यक्त करता है। ज्ञानार्जन या ज्ञान प्रक्रियाकी पद्धति का विश्लेषण और ज्ञान के स्वरूप का निर्धारण है।&#xA;धर्म हृदय को सन्तोष देता है जबकि दर्शन बुद्धि को. परमसत्य की खोज उभयत्र अभिप्रेत है।&#xA;मानव अनुभव लौकिक और अलौकिक सभी अवस्थाओं में तर्कसंगत हो ऐसा नहीं है। अर्तात् ज्ञात तर्क के नियमों का समस्त अनुभवों में अव्यभिचरित रूप से प्रयोग या प्रक्रिया युक्त हो ऐसा नहीं है। सौन्दर्यानुभूति की प्रक्रिया और गणितीय प्रक्रिया में लौकिकज्ञान-सम्पादन में भी अन्तर है । इस अर्थ में हृदय का तर्क और बुद्धिका तर्क ऐसी दो विभिन्न प्रणालियों को मानना होगा।&#xA;मोक्षप्राप्ति श्रेष्ठ है यह धर्मका विषय है क्यों श्रेष्ठ है यह बताना दर्शन का काम है। परमपुरुषार्थ अन्य पुरुषार्थों से क्यों श्रेयस्कर है यह दर्शन बतायेगा । श्रेयस् का अर्थ क्या है इसके प्रति प्रयत्न क्यों करना चाहिए यह दर्शन बतायेगा। दिव्य अनुभव से परम आनन्द की प्राप्ति होती हैं अतः प्रयत्न करना धर्म का विषय है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
