<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;सत्य-नारायणः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;सत्य-नारायणः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>१ तत्त्व-सन्दर्भः १९९५</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/1_tattva-sandarbhaH_1995/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/1_tattva-sandarbhaH_1995/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ŚRI&#xA;TATTVA SANDARBHA&#xA;of&#xA;ŚRILA JIVA GOSVĀMĪ&#xA;The First Book of the&#xA;ŚRI-SAT-SANDARBHA&#xA;Translation &amp;amp; Commentary Satya Nārāyaṇa Dāsa Kundali Dāsa&#xA;Śrila Prabhupada has often glorified Śrila Jiva Gosvāmi for his wonderful accomplishment-Śrī-Sad-Sandarbha (The Six Essences) In the Caitanya-caritāmṛta he writes:&#xA;False devotees, lacking the conclusion of tran- scendental knowledge, think that artificially shedding tears will deliver them. Similarly, other false devotees think that studying books of the previous ācāryas is unadvisable, like studying dry empiric philosophies. But Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmi, following the previous ācāryas, has inculcated the conclusions of the scriptures in the six theses called the Sat-sandarbhas. False devotees who have very little knowledge of such conclusions fail to achieve pure devotion for want of zeal in accepting the favorable di- rections for devotional service given by self- realized devotees. Such false devotees are like impersonalists, who also consider devotional service no better than ordinary fruitive actions.&#xA;Here Śrila Prabhupada asserts that the conclusions of the scriptures are in the Sat-Sandarbhas. Devotees eager to be fortified with these conclusions will there- fore pay close attention to the presentation of the Sandarbhas in English, complete with illuminating com- mentary on the words of Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmi. Such scrutinizing study is especially cherished by devotees who are dedicated to the preaching mission of Lord Caitanya Mahaprabhu. Today, sadly, even among those in the direct line of Jīva Gosvāmī, study of the Sandarbhas is neglected. Śrila Prabhupada, however, before embarking on his mission to bring Kṛṣṇa con- sciousness to the Western world, prepared himself by studying the Sat-Sandarbhas and has encouraged his followers to do the same.&#xA;Śri Tattva-Sandarbha is the first of the Six Sandarbhas. For ease of com- prehension these six treatises may be listed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१ तत्त्व-सन्दर्भः २०१५</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/1_tattva-sandarbhaH_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/1_tattva-sandarbhaH_2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;ŚRĪ TATTVA SANDARBHA&#xA;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;ŚRĪ TATTVA&#xA;SANDARBHA&#xA;Vaiṣṇava Epistemology and Ontology&#xA;Translation &amp;amp; Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;तत्त्वं यज्ज्ञानमद्वयम्&#xA;hastamalakavat-tattvam śrīmad-bhagavatasya yaḥ&#xA;darśayämäsa jivebhyas tam śri-jiva-prabhuṁ numaḥ&#xA;We bow down to Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī Prabhupada who revealed the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam to the people of the world just as plainly as one would display an amalaki fruit kept on one&amp;rsquo;s palm.&#xA;sandarbha yena nadhitäs tasya bhagavate śramaḥ sandarbha yena cãdhitä nästi bhagavate bhramaḥ&#xA;One who has not undergone comprehensive study of Sat Sandarbhas must struggle to assimilate the message of Srimad Bhagavatam. One who has studied Sat Sandarbhas, however, will have no misgivings about the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam.&#xA;SAT SANDARBHA&#xA;Tattva Sandarbha Bhagavat Sandarbha Paramātma Sandarbha&#xA;Kṛṣṇa Sandarbha Bhakti Sandarbha&#xA;Priti Sandarbha&#xA;श्रीश्रीगौरगदाधरौ विजयेताम्&#xA;ŚRĪ TATTVA SANDARBHA&#xA;Vaiṣṇava Epistemology and Ontology&#xA;Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;Sanskrit Text with English Translation and Jiva-toṣaṇī Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;JIVA&#xA;Jiva Institute of&#xA;Vaishnava Studies&#xA;VrindavanTattva Sandarbha: Vaisnava Epistemology and Ontology. Translation and Commentary Satyanarayana Dasa&#xA;This book is published and distributed by Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies. For further information on Jiva books, please contact&#xA;Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Sheetal Chaya 1, Raman Reti&#xA;Vrindavan, UP 281121&#xA;India&#xA;or visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jiva.org&#34;&gt;www.jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;To learn more about Sat Sandarbha, please go to sandarbhas.jiva.org&#xA;To report errors, please send a note to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@jiva.org&#34;&gt;contact@jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>२ भगवत्-सन्दर्भः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/2_bhagavat-sandarbhaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/2_bhagavat-sandarbhaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;श्रीश्रीगौरगदाधरौ विजयेताम्&#xA;buse aveney to suntant&#xA;ŚRĪ BHAGAVAT SANDARBHA&#xA;—&#xA;His Qualities, Abode and Associates by&#xA;Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;Sanskrit Text with English Translation Sri Bho and Jiva-toşani Commentary&#xA;dius SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;Glo&#xA;Ne&#xA;JIVA sro Men&#xA;Jiva Institute of&#xA;Vaishnava Studies&#xA;oghoudhurVrindavan gigs on insist th&#xA;ANDARBHA&#xA;श्री भागवन सन्दर्भ&#xA;hastamalakavat-tattvaṁ śrimad-bhāgavatasya yaḥ darśayāmāsa jivebhyas tam śri-jiva-prabhuṁ numaḥ&#xA;We bow down to Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmi Prabhupada who revealed the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam to the people of the world just as plainly as one would display an amalaki fruit kept on one&amp;rsquo;s palm.&#xA;sandarbha yena nadhītās tasya bhagavate śramaḥ sandarbha yena cãdhītā nāsti bhagavate bhramaḥ&#xA;One who has not undergone comprehensive study of Sat Sandarbhas must struggle to assimilate the message of Srimad Bhagavatam. One who has studied Sat Sandarbhas, however, will have no misgivings about the essential meaning of Srimad Bhāgavatam.&#xA;Contents at a Glance&#xA;atusluoto sidst&#xA;Introduction&#xA;Dedication..&#xA;I Śrī Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;Mangalācaraṇa&#xA;Anucchedas 1-102..&#xA;XV&#xA;xxvii&#xA;1&#xA;3&#xA;5&#xA;II References&#xA;1041&#xA;Editors&amp;rsquo; Notes&#xA;1043&#xA;The Language of Transcendence - Key Terms and&#xA;Concepts..&#xA;1045&#xA;Glossary&#xA;1059&#xA;72&#xA;Abbreviations&#xA;1078&#xA;Subject Index.&#xA;1079&#xA;Verse Index &amp;hellip;&#xA;Bibliography&#xA;1115&#xA;9910v90 ad lo&#xA;1149&#xA;siamex3nA&#xA;Acknowledgements&#xA;1158&#xA;egada to zattalustada&#xA;vii&#xA;Table of Contents&#xA;90 6 16 290&#xA;YIntroduction ..&#xA;fiv Dedication..&#xA;XV&#xA;Houtbexxvii&#xA;I Śrī Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;sildrebne vegera m&#xA;1&#xA;Mangalācaraṇa&#xA;3&#xA;1 Absolute Reality Manifests in Three Different&#xA;Ways&amp;hellip;&#xA;5&#xA;TAC2&#xA;Distinction Between Brahman and Bhagavan.&#xA;9&#xA;E3&#xA;Bhagavan as the Qualified Absolute.&#xA;17&#xA;4 Bhagavan Is Nārāyaṇa.&#xA;35&#xA;5&#xA;Absolute Reality Manifests in Three Aspects&#xA;46&#xA;6&#xA;The Person Eligible for Brahman Realization.&#xA;51&#xA;enoitRivenddA&#xA;7&#xA;The Manifestation of Brahman&amp;hellip;&#xA;65&#xA;72&#xA;viii&#xA;8 Devotion Is the Means to Bhagavan Realization.oldu&#xA;6&#xA;10&#xA;11&#xA;Bhagavan Manifests According to the Moodul&#xA;of the Devotee&#xA;An Example of Bhagavan Realization&#xA;The Characteristics of Bhagavan Are Inherent&amp;hellip;..&#xA;121&#xA;74&#xA;222&#xA;77&#xA;12&#xA;STE&#xA;I&amp;hellip;..&#xA;Bhagavan Is the Refuge of Mutually Conflicting Potencies&#xA;TE&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;126&#xA;13&#xA;SE 14&#xA;Bhagavan Is the Refuge of Mutually Conflicting Potencies - II &amp;hellip;..&#xA;Bhagavan Is the Refuge of Mutually Conflicting Potencies&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;129&#xA;III.&#xA;132&#xA;15&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Potencies Are Inconceivable&#xA;134&#xA;16&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Energies Are Intrinsic&#xA;138&#xA;SEE&#xA;17&#xA;Bhagavan Has Both Conscious and Inert Potencies..&#xA;165&#xA;18 Maya&amp;rsquo;s Two Divisions.&#xA;172&#xA;19&#xA;The Internal Energy Is the Source of All Action &amp;hellip;.&#xA;187&#xA;20&#xA;The Jiva Is Dependent on Bhagavan for His Power of Cognition.&#xA;198&#xA;288&#xA;223&#xA;21 Māyā Is under Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Control&#xA;206&#xA;Māyā Is Activated by Bhagavan&#xA;209&#xA;Threefold Māyā Is Real&#xA;213&#xA;24&#xA;The Qualities of Bhagavan Are Intrinsic to His Nature&amp;hellip;&#xA;guor&#xA;231&#xA;25 Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Attributes Constitute His Essential&#xA;Nature..&#xA;TA&#xA;243&#xA;26&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Attributes Are Eternal&#xA;27&#xA;Bhagavan Is Transcendental to Māyā&#xA;28&#xA;012&#xA;29&#xA;248&#xA;252&#xA;Māyā Feels Shy to Appear before Bhagavān. ..&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Part of His Essential Nature . . .&#xA;30 Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Transcendental.&#xA;255&#xA;259&#xA;268&#xA;31&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Body Is All-pervading.&#xA;284&#xA;08032 Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Form Is Unlimited&#xA;&amp;hellip;. 300&#xA;ix&#xA;FEL&#xA;Śrī Krsna Is the Ultimate Cause&#xA;aer&#xA;38&#xA;Various Avataras of Bhagavan&#xA;39&#xA;40&#xA;33 Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Form Is Not Limited by Materialngada&#xA;Elements &amp;hellip;.&#xA;34&#xA;35&#xA;w w w w w&#xA;Bhagavan Is Both within and without el navsgads the Universe..&#xA;The Universe Is within the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Belly&#xA;Kṛṣṇa&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Advaya-brahma&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Form Is Unlimited 708 H navegada&#xA;Unlimited Forms of Bhagavan Exist within One Form&#xA;312&#xA;EZ&#xA;&amp;hellip; 316&#xA;321&#xA;326&#xA;2009&#xA;21&#xA;332&#xA;337&#xA;340&#xA;343&#xA;41&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Body Contains Everything&#xA;PL&#xA;359&#xA;42&#xA;Kṛṣṇa&amp;rsquo;s Form Can Manifest&#xA;Bot&#xA;in Innumerable&#xA;OS&#xA;Places Simultaneously..&#xA;nonin&#xA;Ingoto&#xA;370&#xA;43&#xA;Śrī Kṛṣṇa Is the Paramatmada istinu at EYEM&#xA;378&#xA;POS&#xA;44&#xA;Śrī Kṛṣṇa Is the Paramātmā - II.&#xA;15A LEVEM&#xA;385&#xA;45&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Eternal and All-pervading&amp;hellip;..&#xA;46 Though Invisible, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Body Can Be Seen&#xA;by His Mercy&#xA;392&#xA;405&#xA;47&#xA;EAC&#xA;His Name, Form, Actions and Attributes Are Transcendental&#xA;vegada&#xA;413&#xA;48&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Senses Are Transcendental&#xA;476&#xA;49&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Bodily Limbs Are Non-Materials&#xA;da&#xA;488&#xA;50 Contradictory Statements Reconciled..&#xA;497&#xA;51&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Form Is the Supreme Absolute Reality&amp;hellip;&#xA;510&#xA;52&#xA;Śrī Ṛṣabhadeva&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Transcendental.&#xA;521&#xA;48&#xA;53&#xA;DOP&#xA;Kṛṣṇa&amp;rsquo;s Body Is Transcendental and Most Beautiful&#xA;&amp;hellip;.. 530&#xA;X&#xA;54&#xA;Devaki&amp;rsquo;s Prayer to Śrī Kṛṣṇa.&#xA;534&#xA;55&#xA;The Partial Expansions of Śrī Kṛṣṇa Are Also&#xA;Transcendental&#xA;539&#xA;56&#xA;Krsna&amp;rsquo;s Form Is the Ultimate of All That Is to Be&#xA;FOT&#xA;Attained&amp;hellip;&#xA;546&#xA;57&#xA;Kṛṣṇa Is Sabdabrahman&#xA;554&#xA;58&#xA;Kṛṣṇa&amp;rsquo;s Body Is the Complete Form of Bhagavan..&#xA;557&#xA;59&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Attire and Ornaments Are Part&#xA;of His Svarupa&#xA;574&#xA;60&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Weapons Belong to His Svarupa.&#xA;579&#xA;215&#xA;61&#xA;Vaikuntha Is Also Part of Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Svarupa&#xA;586&#xA;62&#xA;596&#xA;63&#xA;No One Falls from Vaikuntha.&#xA;600&#xA;Ber&#xA;308&#xA;Vaikuntha Is beyond the Material World.&#xA;64 Vaikuntha Is Both beyond Matter and a Place&#xA;of No Falldown.&#xA;65&#xA;Only Those Free from the Gunas of Nature Attain Vaikuntha&#xA;66 Vaikuntha Is the Shelter of the Nirguna State&#xA;81867 Vaikuntha Is Eternal.&#xA;68 Vaikuntha Surpasses Liberation..&#xA;69 Vaikuntha Is Sat-cit-ananda - I&amp;hellip;&#xA;70 Vaikuntha Is Sat-cit-ananda - II ..&#xA;636&#xA;639&#xA;641&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;644&#xA;646&#xA;652&#xA;657&#xA;71 Vaikuntha Is Not Known to Ritualistic Performers. . 662&#xA;72&#xA;Dhruvaloka Is Also Transcendental Vaikuntha &amp;hellip;. 666&#xA;73 Vaikuntha Has Numerous Manifestations&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.. 689&#xA;1874 Vaikuntha Self-Manifests like the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Body&amp;hellip;.. 692&#xA;xi&#xA;E275&#xA;Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s Associates Are Transcendental lave like Him&#xA;42&#xA;08276&#xA;696&#xA;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Associates Are like the Lord&amp;hellip; 700&#xA;77&#xA;A Devotee&amp;rsquo;s Highest Aspiration: To Be in the Company of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Associates&amp;hellip;.&#xA;haust.. 703&#xA;78&#xA;The Residents of Vaikuntha Are Transcendental to the Material World&amp;hellip;.&#xA;706&#xA;79&#xA;The Threefold Spiritual Manifestation Is Part of the Internal Potency..&#xA;Rada&#xA;721&#xA;80 The Lord Is the Embodiment of All Human&#xA;682&#xA;81&#xA;Attainments.&#xA;782&#xA;Ja me cela al adinulin&#xA;Bhagavan Is the Most Complete Manifestation of Brahman&#xA;00&#xA;82&#xA;83&#xA;ara&#xA;PES&#xA;785&#xA;Ātmārāmas Render Service to Bhagavan.&#xA;vice to Bhagavān.&#xA;зло ой&#xA;798&#xA;AO&#xA;Io lo&#xA;802&#xA;आ&#xA;по&#xA;20&#xA;DALEY HIGHA&#xA;Brahma-jñāna&#xA;815&#xA;Bhagavan Realization Is the Highest Rung on the Ladder of Transcendence.&#xA;84 Śrī Kṛṣṇa Advises Uddhava to Transcend&#xA;85 Dhruva Mahārāja Accepts Bhagavan as Superior&#xA;to Brahman&amp;hellip;&#xA;Devotees Do Not Desire Liberation.&#xA;Brahman Is Not Independent of Bhagavan&amp;hellip;..!!!&#xA;2086&#xA;2987&#xA;88&#xA;Brahman Is Part of Bhagavan&#xA;V. 818&#xA;80821&#xA;824&#xA;831&#xA;89&#xA;Brahman Is the Attributeless Magnificence of Bhagavan..&#xA;835&#xA;98.90&#xA;Brahman Is the Opulence of Bhagavān&#xA;Se 91 Brahman Is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Bodily Effulgence..&#xA;838&#xA;841&#xA;xii&#xA;92 Scriptures Describe Bhagavan As&#xA;beyond Brahman.&#xA;93 Bhagavan Is the Shelter of Everything,&#xA;Including Brahman&amp;hellip;&#xA;95&#xA;96&#xA;The Primary Meaning of the Word Brahma Is Bhagavan&amp;hellip;&#xA;Śrīmad Bhāgavatam Is the Complete Scripture&#xA;The Conclusion of the Catuḥ-śloki of Bhāgavatam Is Bhagavan ..&#xA;843&#xA;848&#xA;868&#xA;&amp;hellip; 885&#xA;898&#xA;97&#xA;All Scriptures Are Reconciled in Bhagavan&#xA;931&#xA;98&#xA;The Vedic Sound Reveals Bhagavān..&#xA;937&#xA;99 Laksmi Is the Energy of the Lord&#xA;996&#xA;100 Lakṣmi Is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Eternal Consort.&#xA;1019&#xA;101 Bhagavan Can Be Known Only through the Vedas .. 1026&#xA;102 Bhagavan Can Be Realized through Devotion Alone. 1032&#xA;II References&#xA;1041&#xA;Editors&amp;rsquo; Notes ..&#xA;1043&#xA;The Language of Transcendence - Key Terms and&#xA;Concepts.&#xA;1045&#xA;Glossary&#xA;1059&#xA;Abbreviations&#xA;Subject Index.&#xA;1078&#xA;1079&#xA;Verse Index.&#xA;Bibliography&#xA;1115&#xA;1149&#xA;Acknowledgments.&#xA;1158&#xA;xiii&#xA;troffs zhhbang&#xA;to Indy&#xA;hom&#xA;ud von lastedg&#xA;Introduction&#xA;X&#xA;sirevorg auds some way of would&#xA;mud&#xA;103&#xA;6&#xA;śri-bhagavan uvāca&#xA;idam tu te guhyatamam pravakṣyamy anasuyave jñānam vijñāna-sahitam yaj jñätvä mokṣyase&amp;rsquo;subhat&#xA;Śrī Bhagavan said: &amp;ldquo;I shall teach you, who are devoid of envy, this most secret knowledge [of devotion] along with the means of its realization, knowing which, you will become free from the inauspiciousness of conditional existence.&amp;rdquo; (GITĀ 9.1)&#xA;25&#xA;THE REAL GOAL OF LIFE IS HAPPINESS. In whatever we do, our ulti- mate goal is to be happy. Happiness can be attained in two ways: by pleasing our own senses or by pleasing the Supreme Person (Bha- gavan), directly or indirectly. Those who seek their own happiness independent of Bhagavan ultimately remain unhappy. The reason is that we cannot truly please ourselves while we are confused about who we actually are.&#xA;A human being is a conscious self, animating a physical body, ego, mind and discriminating intellect. As such, the conscious self is our true identity, whereas the other four instruments are acquired, temporary and superficial dimensions of embodied life. Because we mistake the body, ego, mind and intellect to be the most important dimensions of our being, we fail to achieve happiness and try in vain to please our senses. When one recognizes oneself as a conscious being, as a part of Bhagavan distinct from the body-mind-complex, one will understand how to attain true happiness. Vedic literature teaches that the basic cause of suffering is ignorance about our real&#xA;XVIntroduction&#xA;self. The Vedic seers thus provided authentic knowledge to enable humanity to overcome this ignorance. They considered this effort to be the highest welfare for society. Keeping the ultimate goal of enlightenment in mind, they devised four pursuits (puruṣārthas) for human life. They did not teach us to neglect our physical needs, but to satisfy them in a way that we remain aligned with the ultimate goal, which is to realize our real identity. Vedic society thus con- ceived of four human pursuits corresponding to the four aspects of a human being. The basic need of an individual is survival, which is directly related to the physical body. This primarily entails food, clothing and shelter. To acquire these necessities, there is a need for wealth (artha), because not everyone can produce all the require- ments for their own survival. Consequently, there arises the need to exchange commodities or for a means of commerce.&#xA;Once the basic means for survival have been provided for, there is a natural tendency to seek pleasure or happiness (kama), which is related to the mind. Wealth is also needed to fulfill a person&amp;rsquo;s desires for happiness. To procure wealth and mental pleasure, there is a need for social organization. This necessitates striving not only for one&amp;rsquo;s own economic welfare and sense pleasure but doing it in such a way that one does not impede the goals of other members of society. Therefore, some order and discipline is required to maintain balance in society, and this integral system of morals is termed dharma. V&#xA;The previous three objectives follow a single line of evolution, but the fourth goal arises to correct the ineffectiveness of all the previ- ous goals. No matter how well defined and refined our ethics, how equitable and stable our financial base, and how opulent our stan- dard of living, still we remain unfulfilled. Our reaction to this persis- tent dissatisfaction is to seek mokṣa - &amp;ldquo;freedom.&amp;rdquo; This begins with the simple desire to be disentangled from money and social restric- tions, and culminates in the aspiration to be freed from all limita- tions imposed by finite existence within a relativistic universe. All four goals, however, are related only to the body, ego, mind and intel- lect, which together form the external covering of the self. Although the fourth goal extricates the self from the mire of the body-mind- complex, it does not deliver any positive happiness to the self.&#xA;xvi&#xA;Introduction&#xA;bal Perceiving that sense gratification provides but limited and self- ish satisfaction, people propose that seeing to the wants and needs of others, rather than our own, will bring true happiness. Cer- tainly this comes closer to the mark, yet a feeling of emptiness per- sists within, because such acts of welfare are not aimed at the ulti- mate goal. Rather than catering to one&amp;rsquo;s own misidentification with the body-mind-complex, they cater to that same misidentification within others.vikute ardaligidan&#xA;Why is this so? Because such acts do not take the root of the prob- lem into consideration. True altruism lies not in merely taking care of the external persona of a living being; it lies in alleviating the ignorance that is the root of everyone&amp;rsquo;s disability in finding happi- ness - ignorance of one&amp;rsquo;s true identity in relation to Bhagavan. To enlighten the ignorant and conditioned self to its true identity solves the eternal problem of happiness at its very root. Śrī Kṛṣṇa says in Bhagavad Gita that one of the basic godly characteristics is to be compassionate towards others, and that this compassion releases us from our beginningless suffering? The core mission of the Vedas is to provide knowledge about the self and its relation to the Supreme Self, enabling true altruism and compassion.&#xA;The great seers of India illustrated this transcendental altruism by striving tirelessly to enlighten the masses. Among such luminar- ies, Śrī Jīva Gosvāmi is a brilliant moon who performed unparalleled welfare to humanity by presenting the essence of Vedic literature in the form of the Sat Sandarbhas. Without the detailed guidance of a work like the Sat Sandarbhas, a seeker of knowledge can easily get lost in the dense forest of Vedic literature, not knowing where to begin and how to pursue his spiritual life. to gbolwork bilav&#xA;Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi, who had studied the entire gamut of Vedic liter- ature, including the Vedas, Purāņas, Agamas, six darśanas and their various branches, came to the conclusion that in the present age, the&#xA;daya bhūtesu 512&#xA;1&#xA;GĪTĀ 16.2s vid&#xA;2&#xA;daivi sampad vimokṣāya&#xA;GĪTĀ 16.5&#xA;3 vedais ca sarvair aham eva vedyaḥ&#xA;GĪTĀ 15.159 by all of notater ved galworl&#xA;xvii&#xA;Introduction&#xA;easiest and best way to know our relation to Bhagavan is revealed in Srimad Bhagavatam, the final work of Śrī Vedavyāsa. He consid- ered the study of Srimad Bhagavatam an integral process of realizing that relationship and thus finally attaining the ultimate goal of life: unadulterated joy. To grant humanity a thorough, systematic under- standing of Srimad Bhagavata Purana, Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi wrote Bhāga- vata Sandarbha, &amp;ldquo;A Compilation of the Bhagavata&amp;rdquo; (also known as Ṣat Sandarbha, &amp;ldquo;Six Compilations,&amp;rdquo; because it has six divisions: Tattva, Bhagavat, Paramātma, Kṛṣṇa, Bhakti, and Priti Sandarbha).&#xA;Overview of the Six Sandarbhas&#xA;Sat Sandarbha is a systematically organized compilation of essential verses from Srimad Bhagavatam, thoroughly revealing its essential message. According to Jīva Gosvāmi, Śrīmad Bhagavatam describes three basic subjects: (1) our identity in relation to the Absolute (sambandha-jñāna), (2) the process to realize that identity (abhid- heya-tattva), and (3) the ultimate goal achieved by doing so (prayo- jana-tattva). In the Sat Sandarbhas, Sri Jiva elaborates on these three topics.&#xA;Tattva Sandarbha is the first of the Six Sandarbhas and is an intro- duction to the rest. It can be divided into two parts: pramāņa and prameya. The first part (pramāna) deals with epistemology, the means of acquiring valid knowledge. In this part, Jīva Gosvāmī establishes Śrīmad Bhagavatam as the foremost source of valid tran- scendental knowledge. It is very important to note Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi&amp;rsquo;s conviction that Srimad Bhagavatam is not merely a book containing valid knowledge of Reality; it actually qualifies the reader to directly perceive Reality and is itself nondifferent from Reality. This convic- tion is indeed shared by Śrī Vyasa himself and proclaimed decisively at the very beginning of Srimad Bhagavatam (1.1.2 and 1.3.44).&#xA;The second part (prameya) begins to focus on the actual meaning of Bhāgavatam, revealing its essence in summary by examining the vision of Reality that was disclosed to Vyasadeva while in the state of trance. In short, Jīva Gosvāmī establishes that the ultimate subject of knowledge is Bhagavan in relation to His variegated energies.&#xA;xviii&#xA;Introduction&#xA;In the next three Sandarbhas (beginning with this one, Bhaga- vat Sandarbha), Jiva Gosvāmi elaborates on the topic of ontology (sambandha-jñāna). He begins this volume by establishing Reality as the nondual absolute substantive, existing most completely as Bhagavan, the transcendent Supreme Person.&#xA;In the third volume (Paramätma Sandarbha), he delineates Bha- gavan&amp;rsquo;s manifestation immanent within all entities, called Param- ātmā, Iśvara or Purușa. He also describes the ontology of the indi- vidual living beings (jivas) and the illusory potency (māyā). The jiva is a conscious integrated part of Paramātmā, and the illusory energy that enthralls and conditions the jiva is Paramātmā&amp;rsquo;s exter- nal energy.gilson lliw loubivibuildieiviai&#xA;The fourth volume (Krsna Sandarbha) reveals Śrī Kṛṣṇa as Svayam Bhagavan, the original Supreme Person. It also describes how Śrī Kṛṣṇa has His eternal abode manifest in three places, namely, Vṛndāvana, Mathura and Dvārakā. He is timelessly present in these three places along with His ever-liberated associates, engaged in His eternal divine līlā.&#xA;The fifth volume (Bhakti Sandarbha) elaborates upon the method- ology of self-realization (abhidheya). Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī explains that devotional service performed for the pleasure of Śrī Kṛṣṇa (bhakti) without any tinge of vested interest is the method to realize one&amp;rsquo;s relationship to Absolute Reality, which naturally entails real- ization of one&amp;rsquo;s true identity. Without bhakti, no other process, such as jñāna-yoga, is efficacious in realizing the Absolute. He describes the various types and practices of bhakti and concludes that the highest form of bhakti is performed following the intrinsic mood and nature of the eternal associates in Vraja.&#xA;bulm&#xA;Bhakti leads one to the ultimate goal, prayojana, which is the sub- ject matter of the sixth and final volume, Priti Sandarbha. Here Śrī Jiva Gosvāmī provides a detailed analysis of priti, love for Kṛṣṇa. He shows that priti is not just a sentiment (bhava), but an aesthetic relish of that sentiment (rasa). Priti brings about the union of the devo- tee and Kṛṣṇa without any loss of ontological individuality. This union or oneness is indeed the secret meaning of the non-dualistic statements of the Upanisads, such as tat tvam asi - You are that.&#xA;xix&#xA;Introduction&#xA;Summary of Bhagavat Sandarbha dan orts al&#xA;The central theme of Jiva Gosvāmi&amp;rsquo;s discussion in Bhagavat San- darbha is based upon the second line of the famous verse from Bhā- gavata Purana (1.2.11): &amp;ldquo;Knowers of the Absolute describe it as non- dual consciousness, naming it as Brahman, as Paramātmā and as Bhagavan.&amp;ldquo;sus did dashni nodinama nivag&#xA;Jiva Gosvāmi&amp;rsquo;s purpose in writing this Sandarbha is to establish Bhagavan, consisting of a trans-empirical form replete with tran- scendental energies, as the highest manifestation of the Absolute, superior even to Brahman. Although Absolute Reality is one and indivisible, an individual will realize it in three stages of completion, as far as his or her individual capacity of realization permits. Thus, individuals can realize Absolute Reality as Brahman, Paramātmā or Bhagavan. The specific sequence of nouns used in this verse (&amp;ldquo;Brah- man, Paramātmā and Bhagavan&amp;rdquo;) indicates the increasing impor- tance and completeness of each succeeding manifestation. Śrī Jīva Gosvāmī also points out that Absolute Reality is never authentically realized as the jiva, the individual living being. malog din sdr&#xA;When one realizes the Absolute Truth without perceiving any distinction between its energies and the Absolute itself as Energetic Source, it is called Brahman. When through deeper intuitive insight one apprehends a distinction between the energies and the Ener- getic Source, but perceives this distinction only in relation to phe- nomenal energies (the world and the living entities within it), the Reality thus realized is called Paramātmā. When one&amp;rsquo;s discernment of the distinction between energy and Energetic Source moves still deeper to include the internal, transcendental energies of Reality, one begins to perceive Reality as Bhagavan.balada&#xA;Thus, it is clear that there is no ontological difference between Brahman, Paramātmā and Bhagavan. The difference lies only in the level of perception of the respective seekers. Nevertheless, the difference is not just one of nomenclature. () from dedi la aid For example, the phrase &amp;ldquo;blue lotus&amp;rdquo; has three components: (1) &amp;ldquo;lotus&amp;rdquo; - the noun itself, a substance unqualified by any adjective, ( 2 ) “blue” — the adjective qualifying the noun, and (3) the complete&#xA;XX&#xA;Introduction&#xA;phrase, &amp;ldquo;blue lotus&amp;rdquo; - a qualified substance. There is no real differ- ence between &amp;ldquo;lotus&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;blue lotus&amp;rdquo; except that the former does not convey any specific features, whereas the latter clearly states its color. The distinction between Brahman and Bhagavan is similar.&#xA;In this way, even though He is qualified with all potencies, Bha- gavan is the undifferentiated Reality because He is the complete manifestation of the Absolute Truth. Brahman, on the other hand, exhibits no specific qualities and is therefore an incomplete mani- festation of that same Truth, just as &amp;ldquo;lotus&amp;rdquo; conveys an incomplete depiction of &amp;ldquo;blue lotus.&amp;rdquo; As such, even though there is no real dif- ference between Brahman and Bhagavan, they are not one and the same in all respects. The difference lies in the limitation of vision on the part of the seeker.slovni dobro2 aid to resear&#xA;Śrī Jiva explains that when the Absolute is perceived as unquali- fied (i.e., as Brahman), it amounts to bare awareness of the substan- tive prior to the specification of its intrinsic nature. At this stage it is known as viśeşya, or that which is yet to be defined. The energies that inhere in the Absolute are its qualifiers (viseṣana). When the same Absolute is perceived as inclusive of its intrinsic power (i.e., as Bhagavan), it amounts to complete awareness of the substantive as a qualified entity (visista). alidevisongard niti moti sosda bro&#xA;If one realizes Bhagavan, one will naturally understand Brah- man, just as one who beholds a blue lotus automatically sees a lotus. This is why Śrī Jiva did not dedicate a separate Sandarbha to Brah- man. Whatever is essential to know about Brahman is contained within Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;asbristo&#xA;As there is no absolute difference between Bhagavan and Brah- man, so too there is no absolute difference between Bhagavan and Paramātmā, the latter being a partial manifestation (sväṁśa) of Bha- gavan. In the Paramātmā manifestation, the Absolute is understood&#xA;*Thus, Śrī Jiva&amp;rsquo;s understanding of Brahman is notably distinct from the Advaita definition, which considers Brahman ultimately to be entirely devoid of all energies, manifest as qualities, forms, names and actions. Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi exerts considerable effort to establish that the energies of Bhagavan are real, eternal, and not superimposed or borrowed, countermanding the philosophy of Advaitavada, which claims that they are superimpositions of maya (Pañcadasi 1.236).&#xA;F&#xA;xxi&#xA;Introduction&#xA;as the source of creation who enters the individual ātmās constitut- ing His &amp;ldquo;intermediary energy&amp;rdquo; (taṭastha-śakti), catalyzes the evolu- tion of material elements and various forms from pradhāna, and acts as the inner regulator and facilitator of the interface between the ātmā and the material elements.&#xA;Although there is no absolute difference among the three aspects of the One Absolute Reality, Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi&amp;rsquo;s evaluation is that Bha- gavan is the most complete manifestation (pūrṇa-ävirbhāva), replete with unparalleled variegated potencies. In comparison to Bhagavan, Brahman and Paramätmä are incomplete manifestations (asamyag- āvirbhāva) of the One Absolute Reality. The realization of Bhagavan naturally includes that of Brahman, but not vice versa.&#xA;The rest of this Sandarbha involves a further elaboration on the nature of Bhagavan, revealing the transcendental character of His form, name, abode, devotees, activities and His superiority over Brahman. Hence, Jiva Gosvāmī rightly calls it Bhagavat Sandarbha - an essay on Bhagavan.do y ot&#xA;Referencing the statements of sage Parāśara in Visnu Purāņa (6.5.74), Jīva Gosvāmī shows that the word bhagavan means one who has six-fold majesties in infinite fullness: the power to regulate all existence from within, inconceivable potency, fame, wealth, knowl- edge and detachment. The word bhagavan also means one who is never influenced by the three gunas of prakṛti (VP 6.5.79). His ener- gies have a relationship of inherence (samavaya) with Him. They are inherent within His being, and thus He is never devoid of such potencies.&#xA;Although Bhagavan is endowed with infinite potencies, these potencies are categorized in three groups: internal (antaranga or svarupa-śakti), intermediary (taṭastha or jīva-śakti) and exter- nal (bahiranga or maya-śakti). The internal potency (constituting the true self of Bhagavan) is fully and directly displayed in Him. The other two potencies are displayed indirectly through Param- ātmā. By virtue of His inscrutable, inherent potency, the singular Ultimate Reality eternally manifests in four forms: (1) His own essential form (svarupa), (2) His partial self-expansions (vaibhava), (3) conscious entities with distinct individuality (jiva / ātmā), and&#xA;xxii&#xA;Introduction&#xA;(4) the potentiality inhering in the material elements (pradhana). Thus, Bhagavan is simultaneously endowed with conscious energy (cit-śakti) and inert matter (acit-sakti, also called māyā-śakti or bahiranga-sakti).b of bits&#xA;Māyā-śakti, or the external energy, can never exercise its influ- ence on Bhagavan. However, it has the power of causing delusion to the individual ātmās. The cit-sakti and māyā-śakti are mutu- ally antagonistic (one reveals, whereas the other deludes), and yet their manifold functions are founded in the common substratum of Bhagavan. Insvegara lo mol&#xA;Śrī Jīva Gosvāmī stresses that Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s energies have two important features: they are trans-rational (acintyatva) and intrin- sic to Him (svābhāvikatva). Since they are trans-rational, the ener- gies of Reality are ultimately inscrutable and not fully within the grasp of human thought and reason (tarka-asaha). &amp;ldquo;Trans-rational&amp;rdquo; also indicates that these energies can accomplish logically impossi- ble feats. Another import of &amp;ldquo;trans-rational&amp;rdquo; is that the relationship between these energies and their energetic source is not entirely within the grasp of logic. These energies are not distinct from the Energetic, but also not entirely identical to Him. It is by virtue of this understanding that the philosophy of Śrī Caitanya has become known as Acintya-bhedabheda-vāda (the school of trans-rational simultaneous oneness and distinction). That Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s energies are &amp;ldquo;intrinsic&amp;rdquo; indicates that they are natural to Him and constitute in their totality His very essence, although He remains transcen- dent to their totality, as their source. These energies are neither borrowed nor superimposed on Him from any other source.&#xA;In the final section of Bhagavat Sandarbha, Śrī Jīva Gosvāmi explains that these energies have distinct personalities, names and forms. This is why in almost all Indian temples dedicated to Bhaga- vān as Krsna or Visņu, Bhagavan is accompanied by His consort, Śrī Radha or Śrī Laksmi, the personification of His internal potency. of&#xA;The internal energy of Bhagavan also has three aspects: exis- tence (sandhini), awareness (samvit) and bliss (hlädini). The sandhini potency is the intrinsic power of existence of the Self-existent Bhaga- vän, and it upholds the existence of the individual ātmās and nature.&#xA;xxiii&#xA;Introduction&#xA;The samvit potency is the power of knowledge of Bhagavan by which He is all-knowing and which enables all others to know. The hlad- ini potency is the power of bliss, which bestows bliss both to Bha- gavan - who is inherently full of bliss - and to others. These three aspects of the internal potency are the very nature of Bhagavan and thus exist eternally in Him. The samvit potency includes and super- sedes the sandhini potency, and the hladini potency includes and supersedes the other two. This threefold internal energy of Bhaga- van constitutes His very nature and that of His abode and associates. Bra Next, Śrī Jiva establishes that the form of Bhagavan is not mate- rial like that of human beings. It is spiritual and consists of exis- tence, consciousness and bliss (sat-cit-ānanda-rūpatva). Such a form cannot be cognized by ordinary material senses, and yet it is self- revealed by the trans-rational potency of Bhagavan. Unlike mor- tal beings, the form of Bhagavan is not different from His essen- tial nature. Although the form of Bhagavan is one, it can mani- fest in unlimited places in infinite aspects simultaneously, in direct correspondence to the mood of His devotees.antin@swed&#xA;The contradictory attributes of localization and all-pervasive- ness were present in the form of Kṛṣṇa simultaneously. The form of Bhagavan is always beyond the limits of time and place even when manifest in the material world.&#xA;Like the form of Bhagavan, His dress, ornaments, abode and associates are all manifestations of the svarupa-sakti, the internal potency. Similarly, just as Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s form is nondifferent from His essential being, so too His name is identical with Him. It has the same power as Bhagavan and is similarly beyond the grasp of the material senses. Realizing His name even once can free one from the bondage of the material world. This is why Bengal Vaisnavism lays great stress on nama-japa and nama-sankirtana - celebrating the names of Bhagavan in a solitary quiet manner (japa) or en masse to the accompaniment of music and dance (sankirtana). Śrī Caitanya Mahaprabhu proclaimed that in the present age, Kaliyuga, congre- gational chanting of the names of Bhagavan is the most efficacious means for attaining perfection in spiritual life. The birth, acts, name, form, color and other features of Bhagavan are all spiritual, being&#xA;χχίν&#xA;Introduction&#xA;manifestations of His svarupa-sakti; they manifest to enhance the bliss of His devotees. Bhagavan is ātmārāma, one who delights in His own Self, yet He bestows grace upon His devotees. Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s grace is one of His infinite attributes, and it is an aspect of His partic- ularly wonderful nature whereby He displays His internal bliss. It is through the grace bestowed on His devotees that Bhagavan discloses His birth, form, pastimes and so on. Other than bestowing bliss upon His devotees, there is no other purpose behind such revela- tions because He is inherently complete in Himself. The realization of Bhagavan together with the various unique characteristics con- stituting Him as the essence of Ultimate Reality is said to be perfect and complete. Such complete and perfect realization of Bhagavan is possible only through bhakti.&#xA;Śrī Jiva Gosvāmi concludes Bhagavat Sandarbha with the glori- fication of divine love, prema-bhakti, the only means that self-dis- closes Bhagavan. But to realize the full benefit of bhakti, one must have a clear conceptual understanding of Bhagavan, without any lingering doubts.&#xA;In this way, Jiva Gosvāmi lays the groundwork for abhideya- tattva, or the truth regarding the means of attainment. Therefore, a serious spiritual seeker should invest the time and attention neces- sary to thoroughly study this book with great care, because it forms the indispensible foundation for spiritual practice (sadhanā).&#xA;In this book we have employed certain terminology that may be unfamiliar to the reader. There is an essay in the appendix entitled, &amp;ldquo;The Language of Transcendence,&amp;rdquo; that lucidly explains these terms and any neologisms. Without going through this essay, one may be at a loss to grasp the precise meaning of the terminology used. There- fore, we recommend readers to first acquaint themselves with this terminology before entering into the book proper.&#xA;XXVDedication&#xA;vraja-bhaktireva vedantaḥ śri-gaura eva rādhākāntaḥ prakhyāpito yena rāddhāntaḥ rātvidam mudam tasya svāntaḥ&#xA;Loving service to Bhagavan Śrī Kṛṣṇa in the mood of the Vraja gopīs is the ultimate conclusion of all the Vedas and Vedic literature. Śrī Caitanya Mahaprabhu is indeed Kṛṣṇa, the beloved of Rädhä. May this book delight the heart of my guru, who clearly disclosed this unequivocal truth unto me.&#xA;THIS BOOK IS DEDICATED to my guru śrī śrī 108 Śrī Śrotriya Bhagavad-niṣṭha Śrīmad Haridāsa Śāstrī Mahārāja Nava-tirtha, an ideal example of a devotee and ācārya.&#xA;I bow down at the holy feet of my Gurudeva. He taught me with great love most of the works of Śrī Rūpa, Sanatana and Jīva Gosvāmi, and other Gauḍīya ācāryas. The Ṣat Sandarbhas were the first works I studied under him. He was a great admirer of the Gosvāmis, not only through words but by being a strict adherent of their teachings. He was a living example of Gauḍīya Vaisnava theology and philoso- phy. Thus, I learned from him not only during his discourses, but also through being with him, seeing him deal with various life situa- tions, and serving in the gośälä and elsewhere. It is he who inspired me to propagate this knowledge by making it available in English.&#xA;xxvii&#xA;Śrī Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;dup bag baid, adh&#xA;beyond all breadonna vita o prom and to 992m&#xA;doroton his novedty sell air?mben ser din si vied&#xA;goinaged en is nalogom wou&#xA;Hood algnik &amp;amp; mo10) 2011-2 102 banabianos 3d&#xA;Mangalācaraṇa&#xA;Sil 202790 0W seat to Lansdal&#xA;bas equft clues aid to 1991&#xA;तौ सन्तोषयता सन्तौ श्रीलरूपसनातनौ । दाक्षिणात्येन भट्टेन पुनरेतद्विविच्यते ॥ १ ॥&#xA;dyew vida di ausged&#xA;FOR THE PLEASURE OF THE TWO SAGES, Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī and Śrīla Sanatana Gosvāmi, I am rearranging this book, compiled by Śri Gopala Bhaṭṭa Gosvāmi, who was born in South India.&#xA;तस्याद्यं ग्रन्थनालेखं क्रान्तव्युत्क्रान्तखण्डितम् ।&#xA;पर्यालोच्याथ पर्यायं कृत्वा लिखति जीवकः ॥ २॥&#xA;Some parts of his book were in order, some out of order, while others were incomplete or missing. After thorough deliberation, Śri Jiva now writes it in the appropriate order.&#xA;Commentary&#xA;atha natvā mantra-gurun śrī-gurun sandarbhärthadān sandarbheşu dvitiyasya bhāṣā-ṭīkā karomy aham&#xA;After offering obeisance to my initiating guru and to my instructing teachers, I am writing the translation and commentary to the second book of the Sat Sandarbhas.&#xA;ŚRILA JIVA GOSVĀMI COMPOSED eight verses at the beginning of Śrī Tattva Sandarbha as mangalacarana, or an auspicious invocation to the work. The mangalacarana of Bhagavat Sandarbha has only two&#xA;3&#xA;Śrī Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;verses, the first having the same significance as the third and fourth verses of the mangalacarana of Tattva Sandarbha, and the second being the fifth verse verbatim. Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī did not compose a new mangalācarana at the beginning of Bhagavat Sandarbha because he considered Sat Sandarbhas to form a single book.&#xA;In the first of these two verses, he again remembers the lotus feet of his teachers, Śrīla Rūpa and Sanatana Gosvāmīs, upon whose order the work was undertaken. In the second verse he again expresses gratitude to Śrīla Gopāla Bhaṭṭa Gosvāmi, who originally began it. In this way, he invokes the blessings of these masters for the completion of the work. For further explanation, the reader may refer to the commentaries on the third, fourth and fifth invocatory verses of Tattva Sandarbha.&#xA;18015&#xA;yd boligmos alood aids primers morené vě&#xA;elbut dino at mad unw odw. In ada alaga&#xA;nobisdilab ignosoil mit gnizales to stalgional anew.es&#xA;asbro staligongge add at aniW VOM BUILDI&#xA;Rhenendrobe nutup - beton Ato&#xA;mado y&#xA;regula&#xA;har&#xA;goudani ym od hms are golichid gator insod puissio&#xA;mband tog&#xA;of potoval quoibigeus ne to lophone oddest&#xA;lean all mod bitenom at by a brot -un spaded solder bare to snimated addi&#xA;Anuccheda 10 anssin sill to phoma segue a atmosp to use tooldus ad tadi baatalous edust stuloadA sdto naha&#xA;Absolute Reality Manifests in Three Different&#xA;phadapun Ania to Her jah sebati anons aid of swis&#xA;Ways&#xA;TIA&#xA;१ । अथैवमद्वयज्ञानलक्षणं तत्तत्त्वं सामान्यतो लक्षयित्वा पुनरुपासकयोग्यतावैशिष्ट्येन प्रकटितनिजसत्ताविशेषं विशेषतो निरूपयति “वदन्ति” (भा० १ २ ।११) इति अस्यैवोत्तरा- र्द्धेन &amp;ldquo;ब्रह्मेति परमात्मेति भगवानिति शब्द्यते” इति ॥&#xA;THE FIRST PART OF SB 1.2.11&amp;rsquo; describes Absolute Reality in a gen- eral manner, characterized as nondual consciousness. Then the second part2 elaborates the Absolute more specifically, &amp;ldquo;This non- dual consciousness is referred to as Brahman, Paramātmā and Bhagavan.&amp;rdquo; This one nondual Absolute thus manifests its own existence in one of these three aspects in exact accordance with the specific qualification of the worshiper.&#xA;tal&#xA;vd at hersten alquiles Instoftih 9out 92ach imao Evil sime of gnition Avegada Commentary&#xA;ortw la oreev&#xA;most&#xA;ŚRILA JIVA PRABHU BEGINS the first anuccheda with the word atha, which signifies continuity from the previous book. It also invokes auspiciousness. In the Vedic culture, the word atha is considered auspicious like Om, as is said: dosha qidazow to shom ara 951&#xA;bas, mad&#xA;saiah banged&#xA;exomel velit&#xA;1 vadanti tat tattva-vidas tattvaṁ yaj jñānam advayam&#xA;2 brahmeti paramätmeti bhagavan iti sabdyate 3 Śrī Jīva Prabhu divides each Sandarbha into sections called anucchedas. These&#xA;anucchedas are organized around one prominent verse from Srimad Bhāgavatam and conclude with the name of the speaker and hearer of that principal verse. In this translation, we refer to the anucchedas either by the Sanskrit word or as &amp;ldquo;section.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;5&#xA;Śrī Bhagavat Sandarbha&#xA;The word om and the word atha emanated from the throat of Śrī Brahma at the beginning of creation, and therefore, both are con- hsidered auspicious.ti. Svila&#xA;he In Tattva Sandarbha, Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī established that Śrīmad Bhāgavatam is the supreme pramaņa, or the means of valid knowl- edge of the Absolute. Then he explained that the subject matter of Srimad Bhagavatam is the one nondual Reality, which is conscious in nature. To this end, he cited the first half of SB 1.2.11 in Anuccheda 51:&#xA;W&#xA;All those who have realized Absolute Reality refer to that Reality as nondual consciousness.&#xA;This Absolute Reality is called äśraya, or the support and ground of all being. This topic is the culmination of the ten primary sub- jects discussed in Śrīmad Bhagavatam. The first nine subjects are described merely to provide the context for proper understand- ing of this tenth item. So, after introducing Absolute Reality in a general way as nondual consciousness in Tattva Sandarbha, Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī now begins Bhagavat Sandarbha with a more specific description.&#xA;Tom s&#xA;gana&#xA;W to ages 99717 529d? lo smo ni sonsdeixe In the vadanti tat verse, Sūta Gosvāmī explains that Absolute Reality is referred to by three names - Brahman, Paramātmā and Bhagavan. According to Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmi, these three different nomenclatures indicate three degrees of competence in the wor- shipers. In Bhagavad Gita Śrī Kṛṣṇa says, &amp;ldquo;I reveal Myself to all who surrender unto Me, exactly in accordance with the essential nature of their surrender.&amp;rdquo; Yatha, or &amp;ldquo;in accordance with the essential nature,&amp;rdquo; in this statement signifies the inner disposition of the devo- tee, the mode of worship, the devotee&amp;rsquo;s conceptual outlook in regard to Bhagavan&amp;rsquo;s form, and similar factors that contribute to and define the nature of the surrender undertaken.&#xA;staybdo&#xA;and&#xA;*onkāras catha sabdaś ca dvav etau brahmaṇaḥ pură pes&#xA;5&#xA;kāṇṭham bhittvā vīniryātau tena māngalikāv ubhau vadanti tat tattva-vidas tattvam yaj jñānam advayam ye yatha mam prapadyante tams tathaiva bhajamy aham&#xA;GĪTĀ 4.11&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>३-परमात्म</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/3-paramAtma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/3-paramAtma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;ŚRĪ&#xA;PARAMĀTMA&#xA;SANDARBHA&#xA;The Living Being, Its Bondage, and the Immanent Absolute&#xA;Translation &amp;amp; Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;Paramätma Sandarbha&#xA;THIS IS THE THIRD BOOK in the series of six treatises called Sat Sandarbhas or Bhagavata Sandarbha. It is an elaborate essay on the nature of Paramātmā. The distinction between Absolute Reality&amp;rsquo;s manifestations as Paramātmā and Bhagavan is relatively unknown, even to specialists in the field of Vedänta. These two specific designations are often used synonymously to refer to a single aspect of the tattva. It was Śri Jiva Gosvāmi&amp;rsquo;s genius to clearly define them and enumerate their characteris- tics and functions in detail. There is no other work in the entire gamut of Indian theological and philosophical literature that throws light on this subject so lucidly.&#xA;Paramātmā, also called Puruşa, is akin to what people usually conceive of as God, the creator and overseer of the cosmos, whereas Bhagavan is God in His supreme transcendence, without reference to the phenomenal world - God in His own intrinsic being. Paramātmā is the regulator of the intermedia- ry potency (taṭastha-sakti) and the extrinsic potency (bahiranga-sakti), otherwise known as māyā. He is never influenced by this extrinsic potency, even while present in the midst of it.&#xA;Satyanarayana Dasa&#xA;BORN IN 1954, he was drawn to the spiritual traditions of his home country India since his childhood. After receiving a postgraduate degree in 1978 from IIT Delhi, he then worked in the United States for four years. After this period, he returned to India to begin formal study of the orthodox systems of Indian philosophy known as şad-darśana under the direct guidance of his guru Śrī Haridāsa Śāstrī Mahārāja and Svāmī Śyäma Sarana Mahārāja. This education was pursued in the traditional manner for more than 25 years as he dedicated himself to the practice of bhakti-yoga. In 1991 he accepted the traditional Vaisnava order of renounced life, bābāji-veṣa. His main focus has been on the works of Jiva Gosvāmi, particularly the Sat Sandarbhas, providing English translation and&#xA;commentary. He also earned four sastric degrees, and received both a law degree and a PhD in Sanskrit from Agra University. Satyanarayana Dasa is the director of the Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies in Vrindavan, India. In 2013 he was honored by the president of India, Pranab Mukherjee, for his extraordi- nary contribution in presenting Vedic culture and philosophy to students and audiences within India and internationally.&#xA;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;ŚRĪ PARAMĀTMA SANDARBHA&#xA;$&#xA;विश्वं पुरुषरूपेण परिपाति त्रिशक्तिधृक्&#xA;श्री भागवत सन्दर्भ&#xA;hastamalakavat-tattvaṁ śrimad-bhāgavatasya yah darśayämäsa jivebhyas tam śri-jiva-prabhum numaḥ&#xA;We bow down to Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī Prabhupada who revealed the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam to the people of the world just as plainly as one would display an amalaki fruit kept on one&amp;rsquo;s palm.&#xA;sandarbha yena nadhītās tasya bhagavate śramaḥ sandarbha yena cadhītā nāsti bhāgavate bhramaḥ&#xA;One who has not undergone comprehensive study of Sat Sandarbhas must struggle to assimilate the message of Srimad Bhagavatam. One who has studied Sat Sandarbhas, however, will have no misgivings about the essential meaning of Śrimad Bhāgavatam.&#xA;ŞAT SANDARBHA&#xA;Tattva Sandarbha Bhagavat Sandarbha Paramātma Sandarbha&#xA;Krsna Sandarbha Bhakti Sandarbha&#xA;Priti Sandarbha&#xA;श्रीश्रीगौरगदाधरौ विजयेताम्&#xA;ŚRĪ PARAMĀTMA&#xA;SANDARBHA&#xA;The Living Being, Its Bondage, and the Immanent Absolute&#xA;Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;Sanskrit Text with English Translation and Jiva-toşani Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;JIVA&#xA;Jiva Institute of&#xA;Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Vrindavan&#xA;Paramatma Sandarbha: The Living Being, Its Bondage, and the Immanent Absolute. Translation and Commentary&#xA;Satyanarayana Dasant frumpsfiflefle&#xA;This book is published and distributed by Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies. For further information on Jiva books, please contact&#xA;Studier МАЛАЯ ІЯЗ&#xA;Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Sheetal Chaya 1, Raman Reti&#xA;Vrindavan, UP 281121 AH&#xA;India&#xA;or visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jiva.orgd&#34;&gt;www.jiva.orgd&lt;/a&gt; has sebnoƐ all gaisa gaivi.I adT To learn more about Sat Sandarbha, please go to sandarbhas.jiva.org&#xA;To report errors, please send a note to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@jiva.org&#34;&gt;contact@jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>५ भक्ति-सन्दर्भ-१</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/5_bhakti-sandarbha-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/5_bhakti-sandarbha-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmi&#xA;ŚRĪ&#xA;BHAKTI&#xA;SANDARBHA&#xA;The Sublime Path&#xA;to Attain Perfection&#xA;Volume 1&#xA;Translation &amp;amp; Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;स वै पुंसां परो धर्मः&#xA;श्रीभारास अन्दर्भ&#xA;hastamalakavat-tattvam śrimad-bhāgavatasya yaḥ&#xA;darśayamāsa jivebhyas tam śri-jiva-prabhum numaḥ&#xA;We bow down to Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī Prabhupada who revealed the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam to the people of the world just as plainly as one would display an amalaki fruit kept on one&amp;rsquo;s palm.&#xA;sandarbha yena nadhītās tasya bhagavate śramah sandarbha yena cadhītā nāsti bhagavate bhramaḥ&#xA;One who has not undergone comprehensive study of Sat Sandarbhas must struggle to assimilate the message of Srimad Bhagavatam. One who has studied Sat Sandarbhas, however, will have no misgivings about the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam.&#xA;ŞAT SANDARBHA&#xA;Tattva Sandarbha Bhagavat Sandarbha Paramātma Sandarbha&#xA;Kṛṣṇa Sandarbha&#xA;Bhakti Sandarbha&#xA;Priti Sandarbha&#xA;श्रीश्रीगौरगदाधरौ विजयेताम्&#xA;ŚRĪ BHAKTI SANDARBHA&#xA;The Sublime Path to Attain Perfection&#xA;Volume I&#xA;Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;Sanskrit Text with English Translation and Jiva-toṣaṇī Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;JIVA&#xA;Jiva Institute of&#xA;Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Vrindavan&#xA;Bhakti Sandarbha: The Sublime Path to Attain Perfection, Volume I Translation and Commentary: Satyanarayana Dasa&#xA;This book is published and distributed by Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies. For further information on Jiva books, please contact&#xA;Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Sheetal Chaya 1, Raman Reti&#xA;Vrindavan, UP 281121&#xA;India&#xA;or visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jiva.org&#34;&gt;www.jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;To learn more about Sat Sandarbha, please go to sandarbhas.jiva.org&#xA;To report errors, please send a note to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@jiva.org&#34;&gt;contact@jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>५ भक्ति-सन्दर्भ-२</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/5_bhakti-sandarbha-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/jIva-gosvAmI/ShaT-sandarbhaH/en/satya-nArAyaNaH/5_bhakti-sandarbha-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Śrila Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;ŚRĪ&#xA;BHAKTI&#xA;SANDARBHA&#xA;The Sublime Path&#xA;to Attain Perfection&#xA;Volume II&#xA;Translation &amp;amp; Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;स वै पुंसां परो धर्मः&#xA;श्री भागवन सन्दर्भ&#xA;hastamalakavat-tattvam srimad-bhagavatasya yah&#xA;darśayāmāsa jivebhyas tam śrī-jiva-prabhum numaḥ&#xA;We bow down to Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī Prabhupada who revealed the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam to the people of the world just as plainly as one would display an amalaki fruit kept on one&amp;rsquo;s palm.&#xA;sandarbha yena nadhītās tasya bhagavate sramaḥ sandarbha yena cadhītā nāsti bhagavate bhramaḥ&#xA;One who has not undergone comprehensive study of Sat Sandarbhas must struggle to assimilate the message of Srimad Bhagavatam. One who has studied Sat Sandarbhas, however, will have no misgivings about the essential meaning of Srimad Bhagavatam.&#xA;ŞAT SANDARBHA&#xA;Tattva Sandarbha Bhagavat Sandarbha Paramätma Sandarbha&#xA;Krsna Sandarbha&#xA;Bhakti Sandarbha&#xA;Priti Sandarbha&#xA;श्रीश्रीगौरगदाधरी विजयेताम्&#xA;ŚRĪ BHAKTI SANDARBHA&#xA;The Sublime Path to Attain Perfection&#xA;Volume II&#xA;Śrīla Jiva Gosvāmī&#xA;Sanskrit Text with English Translation and Jiva-toşani Commentary&#xA;SATYANARAYANA DASA&#xA;JIVA&#xA;Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Vrindavan&#xA;Bhakti Sandarbha: The Sublime Path to Attain Perfection, Volume II&#xA;Translation and Commentary: Satyanarayana Dasa&#xA;This book is published and distributed by Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies. For further information on Jiva books, please contact&#xA;Jiva Institute of Vaishnava Studies&#xA;Sheetal Chaya 1, Raman Reti&#xA;Vrindavan, UP 281121&#xA;India&#xA;or visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jiva.org&#34;&gt;www.jiva.org&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;To learn more about Sat Sandarbha, please go to sandarbhas.jiva.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
