<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/01/</guid>
      <description>THIRD PĀDA. Not Ether; on account of the absence of scriptural statement. We have demonstrated that the Sānkhya-system and other systems standing outside the Veda are untenable since they rest on fallacious reasoning and are self-contradictory. In order to prove that our own view is altogether free from all objections of this kind, we shall now explain in detail the mode in which this world, with all its sentient and non-sentient beings, is produced by Brahman, whom we hold to be the general creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/02/</guid>
      <description>But there is. But there is origination of Ether. For Scripture, which is concerned with matters transcending sense perception, is able to establish the truth even of the origination of Ether, although this be not proved by other means of knowledge.
And in a matter known from Scripture a contradictory inference, such as that Ether cannot originate because it is without parts, is not of sufficient force. That the non-originatedness of the Self also does not rest on its being without parts will be shown further on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/03/</guid>
      <description>It has a secondary sense, on account of impossibility and of the text. It is reasonable to assume that in passages such as &amp;lsquo;From that Self there sprang Ether.&amp;rsquo; the origination of Ether is not to be taken in its literal sense; for according to the Cḥāndogya-text &amp;lsquo;it sent forth fire.&amp;rsquo; Brahman engaged in creation first produces fire, and fire thus having the first place, the text cannot possibly mean to say that Ether also was produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/04/</guid>
      <description>There may be (a double sense) of the one (word), as in the case of the word &amp;lsquo;Brahman.&amp;rsquo; Since in the clause &amp;lsquo;from that Self there sprang Brahman,&amp;rsquo; the word &amp;lsquo;sprang&amp;rsquo; cannot be taken in its literal senbe, it may be used there in a secondary sense; while the same word as connected with the subsequent clauses &amp;lsquo;from Vāyu Agni,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., may have its primary sense. This would be analogous to the use of the word Brahman in Mu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/05/</guid>
      <description>The non-abandonment of the promissory statement (results) from non-difference. It is not appropriate to assume, from deference to the Cḥāndogya-text, a secondary meaning for those other texts also which declare Ether to have originated. For the Cḥāndogyaitself virtually admits the origination of Ether; in so far, namely, as the clause &amp;rsquo;that by which the non-heard is heard,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., declares that through the knowledge of Brahman everything is known. This declaration is not abandoned, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/06/</guid>
      <description>(As follows also) from (other) texts. That Ether is an originated thing follows from other clauses also in the Cḥāndogya: &amp;lsquo;Being only this was in the beginning, one without a second&amp;rsquo; affirms the oneness of everything before creation, and &amp;lsquo;In that all this has its Self implies that everything is an effect of, and hence non-different from, Brahman.&amp;ndash;Nor does the statement as to the creation of fire, &amp;lsquo;it sent forth fire,&amp;rsquo; exclude the creation of Ether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/07/</guid>
      <description>But the division (origination) extends over all effects; as in ordinary life. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; has the sense of &amp;lsquo;and.&amp;rsquo; As the clause &amp;lsquo;In that all this has its Self&amp;rsquo; and similar ones directly state that Ether also is a creation of Brahman, the division, i.e. the origination of Ether from Brahman, is implicitly declared thereby. As in ordinary life. When in ordinary life somebody has said &amp;lsquo;all these men are the sons of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/08/</guid>
      <description>Hereby air is explained. The same argumentation explains the origination of air also. That a special Sūtra is devoted to the origination of air&amp;ndash;instead of disposing in one Sūtra of Ether and air&amp;ndash;is for the sake of Sūtra 10, which states that &amp;lsquo;hence (i.e. from air) there originated fire.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/09/</guid>
      <description>But there is non-origination of that which is (only); on account of impossibility. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; has an affirmative sense. There is non-origination of that which is, i.e. of Brahman only; of whatever is different from Brahman non-origination cannot possibly be established. This means&amp;ndash;the origination of Ether and air has been proved only in order to illustrate a general truth. Only that which iś, i.e. Brahman, which is the general cause, cannot originate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/10/</guid>
      <description>Fire (is produced) thence, for thus Scripture declares. It has been stated that everything different from Brahman is the effect of Brahman. The doubt now arises whether the more remote effects of Brahman originate, each of them, only from that substance which is their immediately antecedent cause or from Brahman in the form of that substance.&amp;ndash;The decision is that they originate from those
substances only; for the text &amp;lsquo;from air fire&amp;rsquo; directly states the origination of fire from air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/11/</guid>
      <description>Water (from fire). Water also originates &amp;rsquo;thence,&amp;rsquo; i. e from fire; for so the texts declare &amp;lsquo;From fire water&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 1, 1); &amp;rsquo;that sent forth water&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VI, 2, 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/12/</guid>
      <description>Earth (from water). Earth originates from water; for so the texts declare &amp;lsquo;From water earth&amp;rsquo; (Taitt Up. II. 1, 1). &amp;lsquo;It (water) sent forth food&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VI, 2, 3). But how can the word &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; denote earth?&amp;ndash;To this the next Sūtra replies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/13/</guid>
      <description>Earth on account of the subject-matter, the colour, and other texts. That the word &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; denotes the earth is to be inferred from the fact that the section in which the word occurs has for its subject-matter the creation of the elements; as everything eatable is a product of the earth, the term denoting the effect is there applied to denote the cause. In the same chapter, where the colour of the elements is mentioned (&amp;lsquo;The red colour of a flame is the colour of fire, the white one that of water, the black one that of food &amp;lsquo;), the collocation of words clearly shows that &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; means something of the same kind as fire and water, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/14/</guid>
      <description>But he; from the inferential mark supplied by their reflection. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; indicates the setting aside of the primā facie view raised. Of all effected things, the Mahat, and so on, the highest Person himself, in so far as embodied in the immediately preceding substance, is the direct cause.&amp;ndash;How is this known?&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;From the inferential mark supplied by the reflection of them.&amp;rsquo; By &amp;lsquo;reflection&amp;rsquo; the Sūtra means the resolve expressed in the recurring phrase, &amp;lsquo;May I be many&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;That fire thought, may I be many&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;That water thought, may I be many&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/15/</guid>
      <description>But the order of succession (which is stated) in reverse order (of the true one) is possible, (only if the origination of all effects is) thence (i.e. from Brahman).
The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; has an asseverative sense. The direct origination from Brahman of all effects&amp;ndash;which in passages such as the one quoted by the Pūrvapakshin is stated in a form the reverse of the (true) order of origination according to which the Unevolved, the Mahat, the ahankāra, Ether, and so on, succeed each other&amp;ndash;is possible only on the supposition of the origination of each effect being really from Brahman itself in the form of a special causal substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/16/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that knowledge and mind (which are mentioned) between (breath and the elements) (are stated) in order of succession, owing to an inferential mark of this; we say, not so, on account of non-difference. &amp;lsquo;Knowledge&amp;rsquo; in the Sūtra denotes the means of knowledge, i.e. the sense-organs.&amp;ndash;An objection is raised against the conclusion arrived at under the preceding Sūtra. We cannot, the opponent says, admit the conclusion that the passage from the Muṇḍka Up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/17/</guid>
      <description>But that which abides in the things movable and immovable, i.e. the terms denoting those things, are non-secondary (i.e. of primary denotative power, viz. with regard to Brahman); since (their denotative power) is effected by the being of that (i.e. Brahman). The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; sets aside the objection raised. (The primā facie view here is as follows.) As Brahman, which has all things for its modes, is not the object of Perception and the other means of knowledge which give rise to the apprehension of the things only which are Brahman&amp;rsquo;s modes, and as hence, previously to the study of the Vedānta-texts, the idea of that to which the modes belong (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/18/</guid>
      <description>Not the Self, on account of scriptural statement, and on account of the eternity (which results) from them. The Sūtras so far have stated that this entire world, from Ether downwards, originates from the highest Brahman. It now becomes a matter for discussion whether the individual soul also originates in the same way or not.&amp;ndash;It does so originate, the Pūrvapakshin maintains. For on this assumption only the scriptural statement as to the cognition of all things through the cognition of one thing holds good, and moreover Scripture declares that before creation everything was one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/19/</guid>
      <description>For this very reason (the individual soul is) a knower. It has been shown that, different therein from Ether and the rest, the soul is not produced. This leads to the consideration of the soul&amp;rsquo;s essential nature. Is that essential nature constituted by mere intelligence as Sugata and Kapila hold; or is the soul as Kaṇāda thinks, essentially non-intelligent, comparable to a stone, while intelligence is merely an adventitious quality of it; or is it essentially a knowing subject?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/20/</guid>
      <description>On account of (its) passing out, moving and returning. The Self is not omnipresent, but on the contrary, of atomic size (aṇu).&amp;ndash;How is this known?&amp;ndash;Since Scripture says that it passes out, goes and returns. Its passing out is described in the following passage &amp;lsquo;by that light this Self departs, either through the eye, or through the skull, or through other parts of the body&amp;rsquo; (B_ri._ Up. IV, 4, 2). Its going in the following text &amp;lsquo;all those who pass away out of this world go to the moon,&amp;rsquo; and its returning in the text &amp;lsquo;from that world he comes again into this world, for action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/21/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the latter two (being effected) through the Self. The &amp;lsquo;and&amp;rsquo; has affirming power. The &amp;lsquo;passing out&amp;rsquo; might somehow be reconciled with a non-moving Self (such as the omnipresent Self would be) if it were taken in the sense of the Self separating from the body; but for the going and returning no analogous explanation is possible. They, therefore, must be taken as effected by the Self itself (which, then, cannot be omnipresent and non-moving).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/22/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that (the soul) is not atomic, on account of scriptural statement of (what is) not that; we say no, on account of the other one being the topic. The passage &amp;lsquo;He who is within the heart, surrounded by the Prāṇas, the person consisting of knowledge&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. IV, 3, 7) introduces as the topic of discussion the personal Self, and further on in the same chapter we read &amp;rsquo;the unborn Self, the great one&amp;rsquo; (IV, 4, 22).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/23/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the very word, and of measure. Scripture directly applies the word &amp;lsquo;aṇu&amp;rsquo; to the individual Self, &amp;lsquo;By thought is to be known that atomic Self into which Breath has entered fivefold&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. III, 1, 9).&amp;ndash;By the term &amp;lsquo;unmāna&amp;rsquo; in the Sūtra we have to understand measurement by selection of comparative instances.
Scripture declares the minuteness of the individual Self by reference to things which are like atoms in size, &amp;lsquo;The individual soul is to be known as part of the hundredth part of the point of a hair divided a hundred times, and yet it is to be infinite&amp;rsquo; (Śvet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/24/</guid>
      <description>There is no contradiction, as in the case of sandal-ointment. As a drop of sandal-ointment, although applied to one spot of the body only, yet produces a refreshing sensation extending over the whole body; thus the Self also, although dwelling in one part of the body only, is conscious of sensations taking place in any part of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/25/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said (that this is not so) on account of specialisation of abode; we say no, on account of the acknowledgment (of a place of the Self), viz. in the heart. There is a difference. The drop of ointment can produce its effect as at any rate it is in contact with a definite part of the body. But we know of no such part in the case of the soul!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/26/</guid>
      <description>Or on account of its quality as light. The &amp;lsquo;or&amp;rsquo; is meant to set aside the view previously stated. The Self extends through the whole body by means of its quality, viz. knowledge or consciousness. &amp;lsquo;As light.&amp;rsquo; As the light of things abiding in one place&amp;ndash;such as gems, the sun, and so on&amp;ndash;is seen to extend to many places, so the consciousness of the Self dwelling in the heart pervades the entire body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/27/</guid>
      <description>There is distinction as in the case of smell; and thus Scripture declares. Just as smell, which is perceived as a quality of earth, is distinct from earth; thus knowledge of which we are conscious as the quality of a knowing subject&amp;ndash;which relation expresses itself in judgments such as &amp;lsquo;I know&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;is different from the knowing subject. Scriptural texts also prove this relation, as e.g. &amp;lsquo;This Person knows.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/28/</guid>
      <description>On account of the separate statement. Scripture even states quite directly that knowledge is something distinct from the knowing subject, viz. in the passage &amp;lsquo;For there is not known any intermission of the knowing of the knower&amp;rsquo; (B_ri._ Up. IV, 3, 30).&amp;ndash;It has been said that in passages such as &amp;lsquo;he who abiding in knowledge&amp;rsquo; (B_ri._ Up. III, 7, 22); &amp;lsquo;Knowledge performs the sacrifice&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 5, 1); &amp;lsquo;having knowledge for its nature, absolutely free from stain,&amp;lsquo;Scripture speaks of the Self as being mere knowledge (not a knower).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/29/</guid>
      <description>But (the Self) is designated as that because it has that quality (viz. knowledge) for its essential quality; as in the case of the intelligent (prājña) Self. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; discards the objection. Because that quality, viz. the quality of knowledge, is the essential quality, therefore the Self is, in the passages quoted, designated as knowledge. For knowledge constitutes the essential quality of the Self. Similarly, the intelligent highest Self is occasionally called &amp;lsquo;Bliss,&amp;rsquo; because bliss is its essential quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/30/</guid>
      <description>And there is no objection, since (the quality of knowledge) exists wherever the Self is; this being observed. Since knowledge is an attribute which is met with wherever a Self is, there is no objection to the Self being designated by that attribute. Similarly we observe that special kinds of cows, as e.g. hornless ones, are designated by the term &amp;lsquo;cow,&amp;rsquo; since the quality of possessing the generic character of cows is met with everywhere in connexion with the essential character of such animals with mutilated horns; since in fact that quality contributes to define their essential character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/31/</guid>
      <description>Since there may be manifestation of that which exists; as in the case of virile power and so on. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; is meant to set the raised objection aside. The case may be that while consciousness is present also in deep sleep, and so on, it is manifested in the waking state only; whence there would be no objection to viewing consciousness as an essential attribute of the Self. &amp;lsquo;As in the case of virile power and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/32/</guid>
      <description>There would result permanent consciousness or non-consciousness, or else limitative restriction to either. On the other view, i.e. on the view of the Self being omnipresent and mere knowledge, it would follow either that consciousness and also non-consciousness would permanently take place together everywhere; or else that there would be definite permanent restriction to either of the two, i.e. either permanent consciousness or permanent non-consciousness.&amp;ndash;If the omnipresent Self, consisting of mere knowledge only, were the cause of all that actual consciousness and non-consciousness on the part of Selfs which takes place in the world, it might be conceived either as the cause of both&amp;ndash;i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/33/</guid>
      <description>(The soul is) an agent, on account of Scripture (thus) having a purport. It has been shown that the individual Self is a knowing subject and atomic. Now the question arises whether that Self is an agent or, being itself non-active, erroneously ascribes to itself the activity of the non-sentient guṇas. The primā facie answer is that the individual Self is not an agent, since the sacred texts concerned with the Self declare that the Self does not act, while the guṇas do act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/34/</guid>
      <description>On account of taking and the declaration as to its moving about. The text beginning &amp;lsquo;And as a great king,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., declares that &amp;rsquo;the Self taking the pranas moves about in its own body,
according to its pleasure&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. II, 1, 18), i.e. it teaches that the Self is active in taking to itself the prāṇas and moving about in the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/35/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the designation (of the Self as the agent) in actions. If not so, there would be change of grammatical expression. Because in the text &amp;lsquo;Knowledge performs the sacrifice, it performs all works&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 5) the Self is designated as the agent in all worldly and Vedic works, for this reason also the Self must be held to be an agent. And should it be said that the word &amp;lsquo;knowledge&amp;rsquo; in that text denotes not the Self, but the internal organ or buddhi, we point out that in that case there would be a change of grammatical expression, that is to say, as the buddhi is the instrument of action, the text would exhibit the instrumental case instead of the nominative case &amp;lsquo;by knowledge, and so on&amp;rsquo; (vijñānena instead of vijñānam).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/36/</guid>
      <description>(There would be) absence of definite rule, as in the case of consciousness. The Sūtra points out a difficulty which arises on the view of the Self not being an agent. Sūtra 32 has declared that if the Self were all-pervading it would follow that there would be no definite determination with regard to consciousness. Similarly, if the Self were not an agent but all activity belonged to Prakr̥ti it would follow that as Prakr̥ti is a common possession of all souls, all actions would result in enjoyment (experience) on the part of all souls, or else on the part of none; for as each Self is held to be omnipresent, they are all of them in equal proximity to all parts of the Pradhāna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/37/</guid>
      <description>On account of the inversion of power. If the internal organ were the agent, then&amp;ndash;since it is
impossible that a being other than the agent should be the enjoyer of the fruit of the action&amp;ndash;the power of enjoyment also would belong to the internal organ, and would consequently have to be denied of the Self. But if this were so, there would be no longer any proof for the existence of the Self; for they expressly teach that &amp;rsquo;the person (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/38/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the absence of samādhi. If the internal organ were the agent, it would be such even in that final state of meditation, called samādhi, which is the instrument of Release. But that state consists therein that the meditating being realises its difference from Prakr̥ti, and this is a conception which Prakr̥ti itself (of which the internal organ is only a modification) cannot form. The Self alone, therefore, is the agent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/39/</guid>
      <description>And as the carpenter, in both ways. The Self, although always provided with the instruments of action, such as the organ of speech, and so on, acts when it wishes to do so, and does not act when it does not wish to do so. Just as a carpenter, although having his axe and other implements ready at hand, works or does not work just as he pleases. If the internal organ, on the contrary, were essentially active, it would constantly be acting, since as a non-intelligent being it could not be influenced by particular reasons for action, such as the desire for enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/40/</guid>
      <description>But from the highest, this being declared by Scripture. Is the activity of the individual soul independent (free), or does it depend on the highest Self? It is free; for if it were dependent on the highest Self, the whole body of scriptural injunctions and prohibitions would be unmeaning. For commandments can be addressed to such
agents only as are capable of entering on action or refraining from action, according to their own thought and will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/41/</guid>
      <description>But with a view to the efforts made (the Lord makes the soul act) on account of the (thus resulting) non-meaninglessness of injunctions and prohibitions and the rest. The inwardly ruling highest Self promotes action in so far as it regards in the case of any action the volitional effort made by the individual soul, and then aids that effort by granting its favour or permission (anumati); action is not possible without permission on the part of the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/42/</guid>
      <description>(The soul is) a part, on account of the declarations of difference and otherwise; some also record (that Brahman is of) the nature of slaves, fishermen, and so on.
The Sūtras have declared that the individual soul is an agent, and as such dependent on the highest Person. The following question now arises&amp;ndash;Is the individual soul absolutely different from Brahman? or is it nothing else than Brahman itself in so far as under the influence of error?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/43/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the mantra. &amp;lsquo;One part (quarter) of it are all beings, three feet (quarters) of it are the Immortal in heaven&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. III, 12, 6)&amp;ndash;on account of this mantra also the soul must be held to be a part of Brahman. For the word &amp;lsquo;foot&amp;rsquo; denotes a part. As the individual souls are many the mantra uses the plural form &amp;lsquo;all beings.&amp;rsquo; In the Sūtra (42) the word &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; is in the singular, with a view to denote the whole class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/44/</guid>
      <description>Moreover it is so stated in Smr̥ti. Smr̥ti moreover declares the individual soul to be a part of the highest Person, &amp;lsquo;An eternal part of myself becomes
the individual soul (jīva) in the world of life&amp;rsquo; (Bha. Gī. XV, 7). For this reason also the soul must be held to be a part of Brahman.
But if the soul is a part of Brahman, all the imperfections of the soul are Brahman&amp;rsquo;s also!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/45/</guid>
      <description>But as in the case of light and so on. Not so is the highest. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; discards the objection. &amp;lsquo;Like light and so on.&amp;rsquo; The individual soul is a part of the highest Self; as the light issuing from a luminous thing such as fire or the sun is a part of that body; or as the generic characteristics of a cow or horse, and the white or black colour of things so coloured, are attributes and hence parts of the things in which those attributes inhere; or as the body is a part of an embodied being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/46/</guid>
      <description>And Smr̥ti texts declare this. That the world and Brahman stand to each other in the relation of part and whole, the former being like the light and the latter like the luminous body, or the former being like the power and the latter like that in which the power inheres, or the former being like the body and the latter like the soul; this Parāśara also and other Smr̥ti writers declare, &amp;lsquo;As the light of a fire which abides in one place only spreads all around, thus this whole world is the power (śakti) of the highest Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/47/</guid>
      <description>Permission and exclusion (result) from connexion with a body; as in the case of light and so on. Although all souls are essentially of the same nature in so far as they are parts of Brahman, knowing subjects and so on, the permissions and exclusions referred to are possible for the reason that each individual soul is joined to some
particular body, pure or impure, whether of a Brāhmaṇa or Kshattriya or Vaiśya or Śūdra, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/48/</guid>
      <description>And on account of non-connectedness there is no confusion. Although the souls, as being parts of Brahman and so on, are of essentially the same character, they are actually separate, for each of them is of atomic size and resides in a separate body. For this reason there is no confusion or mixing up of the individual spheres of enjoyment and experience. The Sūtrakāra introduces this reference to an advantage of his own view of things, in order to intimate that the views of the soul being Brahman deluded or else Brahman affected by a limiting adjunct are on their part incapable of explaining how it is that the experiences of the individual Self and the highest Self, and of the several individual Selfs, are not mixed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/49/</guid>
      <description>And it is a mere apparent argument. The argumentation by which it is sought to prove that that being whose nature is constituted by absolutely uniform light, i.e. intelligence, is differentiated by limiting adjuncts which presuppose an obscuration of that essential nature, is a mere apparent(fallacious) one. For, as we have shown before, obscuration of the light of that which is nothing but light means destruction of that light.&amp;ndash;If we accept as the reading of the Sūtra &amp;lsquo;ābhāśāḥ&amp;rsquo; (in plural) the meaning is that the various reasons set forth by the adherents of that doctrine are all of them fallacious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/50/</guid>
      <description>On account of the non-determination of the adr̥shṭas. As the adr̥shṭas also which are the causes of the series of upādhis have for their substrate Brahman itself, there is no reason for their definite allotment(to definite individual souls), and hence again there is no definite separation of the spheres of experience. For the limiting adjuncts as well as the adr̥shṭas cannot by their connexion with Brahman split up Brahman itself which is essentially one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>51</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/51/</guid>
      <description>And it is thus also in the case of purposes and so on. For the same reason there can be no definite restriction in the case of purposes and so on which are the causes of the,different adr̥shṭas. (For they also cannot introduce plurality into Brahman that is fundamentally one.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/3/52/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said (that that is possible) owing to the difference of place; we deny this, on account of (all upādhis) being within (all places). Although Brahman is one only and not to be split by the several limiting adjuncts with which it is connected,
yet the separation of the spheres of enjoyment is not impossible since the places of Brahman which are connected with the upādhis are distinct.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
