<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/01/</guid>
      <description>THIRD PĀDA. On the path beginning with light, that being known. The Sūtras now go on to determine the road which the soul of the wise man follows, after having&amp;ndash;assisted by the Person within the heart&amp;ndash;passed out of the body by way of one particular artery. Now of that road various accounts are given in Scripture. There is a detailed account in the Cḥāndogya. (IV, 15), &amp;rsquo;now whether people perform obsequies for him or not,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/14/</guid>
      <description>Now the Reverend Bādarāyaṇa declares his own view, which constitutes the final conclusion in this matter.
Those not depending on symbols he leads, thus Bādarāyaṇa thinks; there being a defect in both cases; and he whose thought is that. Bādarāyaṇa is of opinion that the deities lead those not depending on symbols, i.e. all meditating devotees other than those depending on symbols. That is to say. the view that those are led who meditate on the effected Brahman cannot be upheld; nor is there an exclusive rule that those only should be led on who meditate on the highest Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/02/</guid>
      <description>From the year to Vāyu; on account of non-specification and specification. In their description of the path beginning with light the Cḥandogas mention the year between the months and the sun, &amp;lsquo;from the months to the year, from the year to the sun&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. V, 10, 1); while the Vājasaneyins mention, in that very place, the world of the Gods,&amp;lsquo;from the months to the world of the Gods, from the world of the Gods to the sun&amp;rsquo; (Br̥.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/03/</guid>
      <description>Beyond lightning there is Varuṇa, on account of connexion. According to the text of the Kaushītakins the soul goes on to the world of Vāyu, to the world of Varuṇa, to the world of Indra, to the world of Prajāpati, to the world of Brahman. The doubt here arises whether Varuṇa and the divinities of the following stages are to be inserted in the series after Vāyu, in agreement with the order of enumeration in the text of the Kaushītakins; or at the end of the whole series as stated in the Cḥāndogya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/04/</guid>
      <description>Conductors, this being indicated. The decision here is that light, Vāyu, and the rest mentioned in the texts as connected with the soul&amp;rsquo;s progress on the path of the Gods are to be interpreted not as mere marks indicating the road, nor as places of enjoyment for the soul, but as divinities appointed by the Supreme Person to conduct the soul along the stages of the road; for this is indicated by what the Cḥandogya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/05/</guid>
      <description>From thence by him only who belongs to lightning, the text stating that. The only leader from lightning up to Brahman is the not-human person connected with lightning; for the text states this directly. Varuṇa, Indra, and Prajāpati take part in the work in so far only as they may assist the person connected with lightning.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;the conductors.&#39;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/06/</guid>
      <description>(Him who meditates on) the effected Brahman, (thus opines) Bādari; because for him going is possible. The following question now presents itself for consideration. Does the troop of conducting divinities, Agni and the rest, lead on those who meditate on the effected Brahman, i.e. Hiraṇyagarbha; or those only who meditate on the highest Brahman; or those who meditate on the highest Brahman and those who meditate on the individual Self as having Brahman for its Self?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/07/</guid>
      <description>And on account of (Brahman) being specified. The text &amp;lsquo;a person not human leads them to the worlds of Brahman&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. VI. 2, 15) by using the word &amp;lsquo;world,&amp;rsquo; and moreover in the plural, determines the specification that the not-human person leads those only who meditate on Hiraṇyagarbha, who dwells within some particular world.
Moreover, the text &amp;lsquo;I enter the hall of Prajāpati, the house&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up.VIII, 14) shows that he who goes on the path beginning with light aims at approaching Hiraṇyagarbha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/08/</guid>
      <description>But on account of nearness there is that designation. Hiraṇyagarbha is the first created being (as declared by the text &amp;lsquo;he who creates Brahma&amp;rsquo;); he thus stands near to Brahman, and therefore may be designated by the same term (viz. Brahman). This explanation is necessitated by the reasons set forth in the preceding Sūtras (which show that the real highest Brahman cannot be meant).&amp;ndash;But, if the soul advancing on the path of the Gods reaches Hiraṇyagarbha only, texts such as &amp;lsquo;This is the path of the Gods, the path of Brahman; those who proceed on that path do not return to the life of man&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/09/</guid>
      <description>On the passing away of the effected (world of Brahma), together with its ruler, (the souls go) to what is higher than that; on account of scriptural declaration. On the passing away of the effected world of Brahma, together with its ruler Hiraṇyagarbha, who then recognises his qualification for higher knowledge, the soul also which had gone to Hiraṇyagarbha attains to true knowledge and thus reaches Brahman, which is higher than that,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/10/</guid>
      <description>And on account of Smr̥ti. This follows from Smr̥ti also, which declares &amp;lsquo;when the pralaya has come and the end of the Highest, they all together with Brahman enter the highest place.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;For all these reasons Bādari holds that the troop of the conducting deities, beginning with Light, leads the souls of those only who meditate on the effected Brahman, i e. Hiraṇyagarbha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/11/</guid>
      <description>The Highest, Jaimini thinks; on account of primariness of meaning. The teacher Jaimini is of opinion that those deities lead on the souls of those only who meditate on the highest Brahman. For in the text &amp;lsquo;a person not human leads them to Brahman&amp;rsquo; the word Brahman is naturally taken in its primary sense (i.e. the highest Brahman); the secondary sense (i.e. the effected Brahman) can be admitted only if there are other valid reasons to refer the passage to the effected Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/12/</guid>
      <description>And because Scripture declares it. And Scripture moreover directly declares that the soul which has departed by way of the artery in the upper part of the head and passed along the path of the Gods reaches the highest Brahman: &amp;lsquo;This serene being having risen from the body, having reached the highest light manifests itself in its own shape &amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 12, 3).&amp;ndash;Against the contention that the text &amp;lsquo;I enter the hall of Prajāpati, the house&amp;rsquo; shows that he who proceeds on the path beginning with light aims at the effected Brahman, the next Sūtra argues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/13/</guid>
      <description>And there is no aiming at the effected (Brahman). The aim of the soul is not at Hiraṇyagarbha, but at the highest Brahman itself. For the complementary sentence &amp;lsquo;I am the glorious among Brāhmaṇas&amp;rsquo; shows that what the soul aims at is the condition of the universal Self, which has for its antecedent the putting off of all Nescience. For this appears from the preceding text, &amp;lsquo;As a horse shakes his hairs and as the moon frees herself from the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/3/15/</guid>
      <description>And Scripture declares the difference. The text, &amp;lsquo;He who meditates on name as Brahman, for him there is movement as he wishes as far as name extends,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Cḥ. Up. VII, 1 ff.), declares that those who meditate on the series of symbols beginning with name and ending with prāṇa attain to a result of limited nature and not depending on any particular path. Those therefore who meditate on the Intelligent either as mixed with the Non-intelligent or by itself, viewing it either under the aspect of Brahman or as separated from Brahman, are not led on by the conducting deities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
