<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 The Public Dimension of the Vishnu-House on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 The Public Dimension of the Vishnu-House on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 Introduction - Spacetime and Its Display</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/00_Introduction_-_Spacetime_and_Its_Disp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/00_Introduction_-_Spacetime_and_Its_Disp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief review of ideas discussed in chapter 2 may at this point be useful. As we noted there, the Bhagavan’s body of ever-changing matter is like the human body with both gross and subtle modes, except that the Bhagavan’s bodies are endlessly varied. The gross body is manifest to human eyes, while the subtle body is not. In the case of both God and humans, the Self (&lt;em&gt;atman&lt;/em&gt;) of pure consciousness and eternal being gazes into the world through the sense organs of those subtle and gross bodies. Made of matter, those bodies are always in flux. In the case of humans, that flux causes the Self to misperceive itself, but in the case of God, he is never fooled; even while he plays the game of illusion, part of Narayana watches the game, transcendent to it all. Narayana is both actor and audience in his lila.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Vimana Panels on the Western Side</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/11_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Western_Side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/11_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Western_Side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To enter inside the prakara wall enclosing the Vishnu-house, visitors must first pass through a dark hall (&lt;em&gt;mandapa&lt;/em&gt;) without windows and walk eastward toward sunlight shining through the doorway ahead. When they then pass through that doorway, the entire western face of the porch comes into view, blazing in sunlight. Symbolically, they have just emerged from the nighttime darkness of the Kali Yuga into the brillant light of God’s body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Panels on the Ardhamandapa or Porch</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/12_The_Panels_on_the_Ardhamandapa_or_Por/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/12_The_Panels_on_the_Ardhamandapa_or_Por/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The northern and southern sides of the ardhamandapa or porch have the same arrangement.1 The corner panel is visually set apart from the other two. At the center of the wall is a window flanked on each side by a tall covered structure housing a graceful male guard (depicted at Panel NP3). The windows have been closed up to allow for later shrines to be built inside. At the bottom of the sealed window on the southern side emerges a drainage channel to carry the flow from the unction rites conducted in the shrine of the Goddess Sri Lakshmi, known in Tamil as Tayar, the Venerable Mother. Her east-facing black stone icon stands in a sanctum built inside the porch adjacent to this south wall. As a later addition, it would have required the closing of the window. Framed by tall pillars with a roofed top, these blank panels share the visual status of the central figures in the two panels on either side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Vimana Panels on the Northern Side</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/13_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Northern_Sid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/13_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Northern_Sid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The vimana’s northern side depicts the Plower formation’s jnana or knowledge, and bala or transformative power, as they are relevant to human life on Bharata. Numerical symbolism for Vasudeva’s three vyuha formations begins with this side; the design of each corner panel visually encodes the numerical place of the formation it signifies: one, two, or three. The four panels bracketed by the two at the corners illustrate the Plower’s power and knowledge. The two panels west of the wall’s central opening illustrate bala through the life of Narada (Panel N2) and the birth of Kapila (Panel N3). The two panels east of the central opening illustrate jnana with the supreme secret that Vasudeva teaches Brahma (Panel N4), and the eight-syllable mantra, &lt;em&gt;Om namo narayanaya&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Om&lt;/em&gt; veneration to Narayana) represented by the rishi Nara venerating the rishi Narayana (Panel N5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Vimana Panels on the Eastern Side</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/14_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Eastern_Side/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/14_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Eastern_Side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The panels on the eastern side of the vimana illustrate the virya action and the aishvarya sovereignty of Pradyumna, Vasudeva’s second and Pre-eminently Mighty formation. This formation, based on the self-delusion of Samkarshana the Plower, expresses the passion propelling Vasudeva’s emanation of directional space and chronological time through Brahma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of matter’s three “threads” (&lt;em&gt;guna&lt;/em&gt;), the east-facing panels illustrate rajas, the passion that accounts for desire (&lt;em&gt;kama&lt;/em&gt;), anger (&lt;em&gt;krodha&lt;/em&gt;), and deed (&lt;em&gt;karma&lt;/em&gt;). When a sense of “I” and “mine” motivates action, it is generative (&lt;em&gt;pravritti&lt;/em&gt;) and moves the actor forward within chronological time. When the sense of “I” and “mine” is removed from action, it is nongenerative (&lt;em&gt;nivritti&lt;/em&gt;) and leads the actor out of chronological time. Nivritti as the solution to pravritti is the subject of the east-facing panels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Vimana Panels on the Southern Side</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/15_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Southern_Sid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/03_The_Public_Dimension_of_the_Vishnu-Ho/15_The_Vimana_Panels_on_the_Southern_Sid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The side facing south represents afternoon, beginning with midday at the southeast corner and ending with sunset at the southwest corner. Aniruddha the Unobstructed on the sanctum wall gazes through the central window of the enclosing vimana. Representations of his shakti or potency are on the vimana to his right (west), and representations of his tejas, or brilliant conquering power, are to his left (east). Aniruddha’s shakti, when embodied as mantras, may function as arrows (&lt;em&gt;astra&lt;/em&gt;) deployed in ceremony (&lt;em&gt;kriya&lt;/em&gt;) intended to produce worldly pleasure (&lt;em&gt;bhukti&lt;/em&gt;), or emancipation (&lt;em&gt;mukti&lt;/em&gt;), or both. Ceremonies intended to produce bhukti alone are called prayoga, “the hurling or casting of missiles”; and in specific contexts, the Bhagavan holds the wheel or chakra as a prayogachakra, with its rim facing the viewer, as if about to throw it. The wheel, whose name is Sudarshana (Pleasing in Apearance), appears in ceremonies as the wheel or chakra mandala inscribed on a flat surface, usually temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
