<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/01/</guid>
      <description>FOURTH ADHYĀYA FIRST PĀDA. Repetition, on account of the text teaching (what has to be done more than once). The third adhyāya was concerned with the consideration of meditation, together with its means. The Sūtras now enter on a consideration of the results of meditation, after a further preliminary clearing up of the nature of meditation. The question here arises whether the act of knowledge of Brahman inculcated in Vedānta-texts, such as &amp;lsquo;He who knows Brahman reaches the Highest,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Having known him thus he passes beyond death,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;He knows Brahman, he becomes Brahman,&amp;rsquo; is, in the view of Scripture, to be performed once only, or to be repeated more than once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/02/</guid>
      <description>And on account of an inferential mark. Inferential mark here means Smr̥ti. Smr̥ti also declares that that knowledge which effects Release is of the nature of continued representation. Meditation therefore has to be repeated.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;lsquo;repetition.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/03/</guid>
      <description>But as the Self; this (the ancient Devotees) acknowledge (since the texts) make (them) apprehend (in that way). The following point is now taken into consideration. Is Brahman to be meditated upon as something different from the meditating Devotee, or as the Self of the latter?&amp;ndash;The Pūrvapakshin holds the former view. For, he says, the individual soul is something different from Brahman; as has been proved under II, 1, 22; III, 4, 8; I, 1, 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/04/</guid>
      <description>Not in the symbol; for (the symbol) is not that one (i.e. the Self of the Devotee). &amp;lsquo;Let a man meditate on mind as Brahman &amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. III, 18, 1); &amp;lsquo;He who meditates on name as Brahman&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VII, l5)&amp;ndash;with regard to these and similar meditations on outward symbols (pratīka) of Brahman there arises a doubt, viz. whether in them the symbols are to be thought of as of the nature of Self or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/05/</guid>
      <description>The view of Brahman, on account of superiority. The view of Brahman may appropriately be superimposed on mind and the like; but not the view of mind, and so on, on Brahman. For Brahman is something superior to mind, and so on; while the latter are inferior to Brahman. To view a superior person, a prince e.g., as a servant would be lowering; while, on the other hand, to view a servant as a prince is exalting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/06/</guid>
      <description>And the ideas of Āditya and the rest on the member; on account of this being rational. &amp;lsquo;He who shines up there let a man meditate on him as the Udgītha&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. I, 3, 1).&amp;ndash;With regard to this and similar meditations connected with subordinate parts of sacrificial performances there arises the doubt whether
the idea of Āditya and so on has to be superimposed on the subordinate part of the sacrifice, such as the Udgītha, or vice versā (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/07/</guid>
      <description>Sitting; on account of possibility. It has been shown that that special form of cognitional activity which the Vedānta-texts set forth as the means of accomplishing final Release and which is called meditation (dhyāna; upāsana) has to be frequently repeated, and is of the nature of continued representation. A question now arises as to the way in which it has to be carried on.&amp;ndash;There being no special restrictive rule, the Pūrvapakshin holds that the Devotee may carry it on either sitting or lying down or standing or walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/08/</guid>
      <description>And on account of meditation. Since, as intimated by the text,&amp;rsquo;the Self is to be meditated
upon,&amp;rsquo; the mental activity in question is of the nature of meditation, it requires as its necessary condition concentration of mind. For by meditation is understood thought directed upon one object and not disturbed by the ideas of other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/09/</guid>
      <description>And with reference to immobility. And it is with reference to their immobility that the earth and other inanimate things&amp;ndash;the air, the sky, the waters, the mountains&amp;ndash;may be spoken of as thinking, &amp;rsquo;the earth thinks (dhyāyati) as it were,&amp;rsquo; and so on. Movelessness hence is characteristic of the intensely meditating person also, and such movelessness is to be realised in the sitting posture only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/10/</guid>
      <description>And Smr̥ti texts say the same. Smr̥ti texts also declare that he only who sits can meditate, &amp;lsquo;Having placed his steady seat upon a pure spot, there seated upon that seat, concentrating his mind he should practise Yoga&amp;rsquo; (Bha. Gī. VI, 11-12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/11/</guid>
      <description>Where concentration of mind (is possible), there; on account of there being no difference. As the texts do not say anything as to special places and times, the only requisite of such places and times is that they should favour concentration of mind. This agrees with the declaration &amp;lsquo;Let a man apply himself to meditation in a level and clean place, &amp;amp;c., favourable to the mind&amp;rsquo; (Śvet. Up. II, 10).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/12/</guid>
      <description>Up to death; for there also it is seen. The question now arises whether the meditation described which is the means of final Release is to be accomplished within one day, or to be continued day after day, until death.&amp;ndash;The view that it is accomplished within one day, as this will satisfy the scriptural injunction, is disposed of by the Sūtra. Meditation is to be continued until death. For Scripture declares that meditation has to take place &amp;rsquo;there,&amp;rsquo; i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/13/</guid>
      <description>On the attainment of this, there result the non-clinging and the destruction of later and earlier sins; this being declared. Having, so far, elucidated the nature of meditation, the Sūtras now begin to consider the result of meditation. Scripture declares that on the knowledge of Brahman being attained a man&amp;rsquo;s later and earlier sins do not cling to him but pass away. &amp;lsquo;As water does not cling to a lotus leaf, so no evil deed clings to him who knows this &amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/14/</guid>
      <description>Of the other also there is thus non-clinging; but at death. It has been said that, owing to knowledge, earlier and subsequent sins do not cling and are destroyed. The same holds good also with regard to the other, i.e. to good works&amp;ndash;they also, owing to knowledge, do not cling and are destroyed; for there is the same antagonism between knowledge and the fruit of those works, and Scripture moreover expressly declares this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/15/</guid>
      <description>But only those former works the effects of which have not yet begun; on account of that being the term. A new doubt arises here, viz. whether all previous good and evil works are destroyed by the origination of knowledge, or only those the effects of which have not yet begun to operate.&amp;ndash;All works alike, the Pūrvapakshin says; for the texts-as e.g. &amp;lsquo;all sins are burned&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;declare the fruits
of knowledge to be the same in all cases; and the fact of the body continuing to exist subsequently to the rise of knowledge may be accounted for by the force of an impulse once imparted, just as in the case of the revolution of a potter&amp;rsquo;s wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/16/</guid>
      <description>But the Agnihotra and the rest, (because they tend) to that effect only; this being seen. It might here be said that special works incumbent on the several āśramas, as e. g. the Agnihotra, need not be undertaken by those who are not desirous of their results, since these works also fall under the category of good works the result of which does not &amp;lsquo;cling.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;This view the Sūtra sets aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/17/</guid>
      <description>According to some (a class of good works) other than these, of both kinds. The text quoted above from one śākhā (&amp;lsquo;His friends enter upon his good deeds&amp;rsquo;) refers to good works other than the Agnihotra and the rest, the only object of which is to give rise to knowledge, viz. to all those manifold good works, previous or subsequent to the attaining to knowledge, the results of which are obstructed by other works of greater strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/18/</guid>
      <description>For (there is the text) &amp;lsquo;whatever he does with knowledge.&amp;rsquo; The declaration made in the text &amp;lsquo;whatever he does with knowledge that is more vigorous,&amp;rsquo; viz. that the knowledge of the Udgītha has for its result non-obstruction of the result of the sacrifice, implies that the result of works actually performed may be obstructed. We thus arrive at the conclusion that the text of the Sāṭyāyanins,&amp;rsquo; his friends enter upon his good works,&amp;rsquo; refers to those good works of the man possessing knowledge the results of which were somehow obstructed (and hence did not act themselves out during his lifetime, so that on his death they may be transferred to others).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/4/1/19/</guid>
      <description>But having destroyed by fruition the other two sets he becomes one with Brahman. There now arises the doubt whether the good and evil
works other than those the non-clinging and destruction of which have been declared, that is to say those works the results of which have begun to act, come to an end together with that bodily existence in which knowledge of Brahman originates, or with the last body due to the action of the works last mentioned, or with another body due to the action of the anārabdhakārya.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
