<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Ekāntins in the Nārāyaṇīya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Ekāntins in the Nārāyaṇīya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) Setting the scene</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/1_i_Setting_the_scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/1_i_Setting_the_scene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we have seen above, and will see again below, the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; (MBh 12.321-339) has played a crucial role in the self-understanding of later Pāñcarātra traditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the last fifteen years or so, scholarship on this text has been dominated by the German language volume *Nārāyaṇīya-Studien *(1997), the outcome of a collaborative project undertaken by Reinhold Grünendahl, Angelika Malinar, Thomas Oberlies and Peter Schreiner. The contributions of these scholars are briefly summarised in an English language introduction to the volume by Schreiner (1997a), who writes near the beginning (ibid: 1):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) The terms ekānta, ekāntin etc</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/2_ii_The_terms_ekAnta_ekAntin_etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/2_ii_The_terms_ekAnta_ekAntin_etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the context of the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, several modern scholars (e.g. Bhandarkar 1913: 6, Gonda 1977: 9, Matsubara 1994: 51 &lt;em&gt;ff&lt;/em&gt;) have understood the terms &lt;em&gt;ekānta&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt; to denote primarily “monotheism”. However, although the exclusive worship of Hari-Nārāyaṇa, also called Viṣṇu and Vāsudeva, certainly appears to be one of the key meanings of &lt;em&gt;ekānta&lt;/em&gt; and its related terms in several passages belonging to &lt;em&gt;Part B&lt;/em&gt;, there is little justification for the claim that this is the primary sense of these terms throughout the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; as a whole. In the following I will argue that, as used in the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, the terms &lt;em&gt;ekānta&lt;/em&gt; etc. are multivalent, and that the text itself quite explicitly invites this interpretation. It is worth noting here that I am in agreement on this issue, at least in principle, with Vedāntadeśika, who himself stressed the multiple meanings of the term &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt;.294 In sorting through the various, and concurrent, senses of &lt;em&gt;ekānta&lt;/em&gt; and its related terms in the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, I will draw attention to three in particular, and argue that each of these can be more significant to a preliminary understanding of the identity of the Ekāntins than is the characteristic of monotheism. Only in certain portions of Part B, moreover, does “monotheism” (i.e.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Sectarianism, syncretism, and the religious identity of the Ekāntins in Part B</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/3_iii_Sectarianism_syncretism_and_the_re/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/3_iii_Sectarianism_syncretism_and_the_re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several modern scholars (e.g. Jaiswal 1967:40; Brockington 1998: 299) have claimed that the Ekāntins in the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; are devotees of Nārāyaṇa, and that they are to be distinguished on this basis from the followers of Vāsudeva, who are considered to be inferior. These two religious groupings, according to this theory, are thus depicted as two distinct Vaiṣṇava “sects”. This reading is based exclusively on the following passage: [[192]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;aho hy ekāntinaḥ sarvān prīṇāti bhagavān hariḥ&lt;/em&gt;/ &lt;em&gt;vidhiprayuktāṃ pūjāṃ ca gṛhṇāti bhagavān svayam&lt;/em&gt;// &lt;em&gt;ye tu dagdhendhanā loke puṇyapāpavivarjitāḥ&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 iv \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/4_iv_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/2_The_ekAntins_in_the_nArAyaNIya/4_iv_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a late addition to Part A of the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, and in Part B, ‘Pañcarātra’ is named as the comprehensive Upaniṣad (326.100), or the &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt; of the Ekāntins (336.76), both of which subsume the three traditions Veda, Sāṃkhya and Yoga. Already in the oldest parts of the text, Nārada is shown to combine the practice of Vedic recitation with ascetic and meditative techniques typical of the liberation-seeking Sāṃkhya and 342 I am very grateful to Professor Fitzgerald for allowing me to read and refer to several of his as yet unpublished works. [[204]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
