<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अभय-चरणः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अभय-चरणः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Dedication</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presented to my friends&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and devotees who like to read&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my books and who approached me to request&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that I render the great&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt; into English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A. C. Bhaktivedanta Swami&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Originally delivered as five morning lectures on the&lt;/em&gt; Caitanya-caritāmṛta &lt;em&gt;— the authoritative biography of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu by Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī — before the International Society for Krishna Consciousness, New York City, April 10-14, 1967.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;caitanya&lt;/em&gt; means “living force,” &lt;em&gt;carita&lt;/em&gt; means “character,” and &lt;em&gt;amṛta&lt;/em&gt; means “immortal.” As living entities we can move, but a table cannot because it does not possess living force. Movement and activity may be considered signs or symptoms of the living force. Indeed, it may be said that there can be no activity without the living force. Although the living force is present in the material condition, this condition is not &lt;em&gt;amṛta,&lt;/em&gt; immortal. The words &lt;em&gt;caitanya-caritāmṛta,&lt;/em&gt; then, may be translated as “the character of the living force in immortality.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no difference between the teachings of Lord Caitanya presented here and the teachings of Lord Kṛṣṇa in the &lt;em&gt;Bhagavad-gītā.&lt;/em&gt; The teachings of Lord Caitanya are practical demonstrations of Lord Kṛṣṇa’s teachings. Lord Kṛṣṇa’s ultimate instruction in the &lt;em&gt;Bhagavad-gītā&lt;/em&gt; is that everyone should surrender unto Him, Lord Kṛṣṇa. Kṛṣṇa promises to take immediate charge of such a surrendered soul. The Lord, the Supreme Personality of Godhead, is already in charge of the maintenance of this creation by virtue of His plenary expansion, Kṣīrodakaśāyī Viṣṇu, but this maintenance is not direct. However, when the Lord says that He takes charge of His pure devotee, He actually takes direct charge. A pure devotee is a soul who is forever surrendered to the Lord, just as a child is surrendered to his parents or an animal to its master. In the surrendering process, one should (1) accept things favorable for discharging devotional service, (2) reject things unfavorable, (3) always believe firmly in the Lord’s protection, (4) feel exclusively dependent on the mercy of the Lord, (5) have no interest separate from the interest of the Lord, and (6) always feel oneself meek and humble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/00_meta/abhaya-charaNaH/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt;, by Śrīla Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī, is the principal work on the life and teachings of Śrī Kṛṣṇa Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Caitanya Mahāprabhu is the pioneer of a great social and religious movement that began in India about five hundred years ago and that has directly and indirectly influenced the subsequent course of religious and philosophical thinking not only in India but throughout the world. That Śrī Kṛṣṇa Caitanya’s influence has spread so far is due in large part to the efforts of His Divine Grace A. C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupāda, the present work’s translator and commentator and the founder and &lt;em&gt;ācārya&lt;/em&gt; (spiritual guide) of the International Society for Krishna Consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
