<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Pāñcarātra and the Veda on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Pāñcarātra and the Veda on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) Vedamūlatva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/1_i_vedamUlatva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/1_i_vedamUlatva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do the Pāñcarātra scriptures define themselves in relation to the Veda? Are there common approaches to this question among those works which do not appeal to the Ekāyanaveda? And do largely earlier texts such as the *Jayākhyasaṃhitā *(JS), *Sātvatasaṃhitā *(SS) and &lt;em&gt;Pauṣkarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (PauṣS) utilise similar methods to the Saṃhitās composed in South India? As we will see in the following, one of the most frequently used strategies in the later, South Indian works is the claim that the original form of the teaching upon which the present work is based is none other than the Veda itself. Of course, acceptance of this claim would satisfy the well-known Mīmāṃsaka criterion for a source of valid knowledge ( &lt;em&gt;pramāṇa&lt;/em&gt;) relating to &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) “Vedification” in the South Indian Pāñcarātra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/2_ii_Vedification_in_the_South_Indian_pA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/2_ii_Vedification_in_the_South_Indian_pA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an article devoted to the referent of the term &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt; in the Dharmasūtras, Albrecht Wezler (2004) explores the manner in which “the &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt; of the Dharmaśāstra” is presented as having been “extracted” from the Veda. Addressing the opening two verses of the *Gautamadharmasūtra *(GDh), Wezler argues that there is a clear distinction presupposed between the Vedic &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;, on the one hand, and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“the &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt; of the Dharmaśāstra” on the other. It is the latter, says Wezler, to which Gautama refers in the phrase “the Veda is the root of &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;” ( &lt;em&gt;vedo dharmamūlam&lt;/em&gt;, GDh 1.1). According to Wezler, this statement, together with the second verse, which he translates as “and tradition as well as practice of those who know it (that is, the Veda), [are the root of &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;]”, is a clear sign of a process of “Vedification”, which he explains as meaning “in the first place the development of the &lt;em&gt;vedamūlatva&lt;/em&gt; concept” (ibid.: 643-644).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/3_iii_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/2_The_pAncharAtra_and_the_Veda/3_iii_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter I have attempted to give an overview of the ways in which authors of the Pāñcarātra scriptures associated their own tradition with that of the Veda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this is not intended to be an exhaustive account. As we have seen, the claim that the Pāñcarātra scriptures are “rooted in the Veda” ( &lt;em&gt;vedamūlatva&lt;/em&gt;) appears to have a long history, since it is mentioned already in Bhaṭṭa Jayanta’s ninth-tenth century ĀḌ. However, it is not included in the early Saṃhitās, and of the works available to me, its earliest articulation &lt;em&gt;on behalf of&lt;/em&gt; the Pāñcarātra is in Yāmuna’s ĀP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
