<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अधिवैष्णवम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अधिवैष्णवम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Temple Agama shifts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/temple-Agama-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/temple-Agama-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;shrIrangam is said to have been originally pAncharAtrika.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hari Rao (1976) dicusses how the Kōyiloḷugu, the Śrīraṅgam temple chronicle, describes in great detail the substitution, by Rāmānuja, of a Vaikhānasa-based system of temple-worship for one based on the Pāñcarātra Saṃhitās. However, this did not signal the end of this competitive rivalry, since from 1223-1225 CE, Śrīraṅgam was occupied by the Oḍḍas, the army of the Eastern Gaṅga King Anaṅgabhīma III, who reinstated Vaikhānasa ritual practices throughout the short period of their occupation (Spencer 1978: 18). - Leach&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tradition relations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/tradition-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/tradition-relations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhagavata-sattvata-pancharatra&#34;&gt;bhAgavata, sattvata, pAncharAtra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/2_ii_Distinct_pAncharAtrika_identities_i&#34;&gt;leach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;doctrinal-or-ritual-difference&#34;&gt;Doctrinal or ritual difference?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;तद् अपि लीचोल्लेखेन स्पष्टम् इह -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That distinct groups within the Pāñcarātra should have held opposing views (as per rAmakaNTha) on the ontology of individual selves seems somewhat surprising given that in the Pāñcarātra literature that is currently available, such concerns do not figure prominently. Moreover, in the works by the Vedāntin defenders of Pāñcarātra orthodoxy, in the Vaikhānasa literature and, as we will see presently, in the Pāñcarātra scriptures, different types of Pāñcarātrika are distinguished from one another not on account of opposing philosophical positions, but rather because of such factors as their different religious goals, liturgical practices, social class ( &lt;em&gt;varṇa&lt;/em&gt;), customs, everyday habits, and religious insignia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>क्षात्रम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/xAtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/xAtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;major-vaishnava-polities-and-rulers&#34;&gt;Major vaiShNava polities and rulers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most gupta-s were vaiShNava-s (garuDa emblem). Narasimhagupta baladitya who defeated foreigners was also a vaishnava.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great Mihira Bhoja was a Vaishnava.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kalanjar was lost to sullas by chandellas but then reclaimed again for them by a trailokyavarman who was supposedly a vaishnava.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;rANa kumbha, who wrote a commentary on gIta-govinda and fought Islamic rulers, was vaiShNava. Many sUryavaMshI rAjaputra-s adore rAma most - even if where the family deity is ekalingjI shiva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
