<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अधि-ग्रन्थम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अधि-ग्रन्थम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Broo Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/broo_preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/broo_preface/</guid>
      <description>I have been attracted to religious ritual since my childhood and an initiated Gauḍīya Vaiṣṇava since my youth, so it is perhaps natural that I began reading and translating from the Haribhaktivilāsa already as a Sanskrit student in Uppsala, Sweden, in the late 1990s. My first book was a translation of the chapters dealing with Ekādaśī (Dāsa 2001), and since then, I have through the years kept returning to various topics of the Haribhaktivilāsa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/broo_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kriyA/hari-bhakti-vilAsaH/meta/broo_intro/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction to the Text The present book is a text-critical edition and annotated translation of the Bhagavad- or Haribhaktivilāsa (“Splendour of devotion to Hari”, henceforth HBV). This text, written ca.1540, is one of the first Sanskrit works of the Gauḍīya Vaiṣṇava saṃpradāya begun by Śrī Kṛṣṇa Caitanya (1486–1533; for classical overviews on this devotional Hindu tradition, see e.g., De 1942 or Eidlitz 1968), detailing in twenty long chapters and around 12000 verses the normative sadācāra or correct conduct as well as the ritual life of a Vaiṣṇava, ranging from how to properly brush the teeth upon getting up in the morning to how to build a temple for Viṣṇu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
