<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/01/</guid>
      <description>FOURTH PĀDA. The benefit to man results from thence, on account of scriptural statement; thus Bādarāyaṇa thinks. We have concluded the investigation into the oneness or diverseness of meditations&amp;ndash;the result of which is to indicate in which cases the special points mentioned in several meditations have to be combined, and in which not. A further point now to be investigated is whether that advantage to the meditating devotee, which is held to accrue to him from the meditation, results from the meditation directly, or from works of which the meditations are subordinate members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/02/</guid>
      <description>On account of (the Self) standing in a complementary relation, they are arthavādas, as in other cases; thus Jaimini opines. What has been said as to Scripture intimating that a beneficial result is realised through the meditations by themselves is untenable. For texts such as &amp;lsquo;he who knows Brahman reaches the Highest&amp;rsquo; do not teach that the highest aim of man is attained through knowledge; their purport rather is to inculcate knowledge of Truth on the part of a Self which is the agent in works prescribed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/03/</guid>
      <description>On account of (such) conduct being seen. It is seen, viz in Scripture, that those who knew Brahman busied themselves chiefly with sacrifices.&amp;ndash;Aśvapati Kaikeya had a deep knowledge of the Self; but when three R̥shis had come to him to receive instruction regarding the Self, he told them &amp;lsquo;I am about, to perform a sacrifice, Sirs&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. V, II). Similarly we learn from Smr̥ti that Janaka and other princes deeply versed in the knowledge of Brahman applied themselves to sacrificial works, &amp;lsquo;By works only Janaka and others attained to perfection&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;He also, well founded in knowledge, offered many sacrifices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/04/</guid>
      <description>On account of direct scriptural statement. Scripture itself directly declares knowledge to be subordinate to works, &amp;lsquo;whatever he does with knowledge, with faith, with the Upanishad, that is more vigorous&amp;rsquo;. Nor can it be said that this text refers, on the ground of leading subject-matter (prakaraṇa), to the Udgītha only; for direct scriptural statement (śuti) is stronger than subject-matter,
and the words &amp;lsquo;whatever he does with knowledge&amp;rsquo; clearly refer to knowledge in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/05/</guid>
      <description>On account of the taking hold together. The text &amp;rsquo;then both knowledge and work take hold of him&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. IV, 4, 2) shows that knowledge and work go together, and this going together is possible only if, in the manner stated, knowledge is subordinate to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/06/</guid>
      <description>On account of injunction for such a one. That knowledge is subordinate to works follows therefrom also that works are enjoined on him only who possesses knowledge. For texts such as &amp;lsquo;He who has learnt the Veda from a family of teachers,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 15), enjoin works on him only who has mastered the sacred texts so as fully to understand their meaning&amp;ndash;for this is the sense of the term &amp;rsquo;learning&amp;rsquo; (adhyayana).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/07/</guid>
      <description>On account of definite rule. Another argument for our conclusion is that the text &amp;lsquo;Doing works here let a man desire to live a hundred years,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Is. Up. II), expressly enjoins lifelong works on him who knows the Self. The general conclusion, therefore, is that knowledge (meditation) is merely auxiliary to works. Of this view the next Sūtra finally disposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/08/</guid>
      <description>But on account of the teaching of the different one, Badarāyaṇa&amp;rsquo;s (view is valid); as this is seen. Knowledge by itself benefits man; since Scripture teaches that the object of knowledge is the highest Brahman which, as it is of an absolutely faultless and perfect nature, is other than the active individual soul.
Badarāyaṇa, therefore, holds that knowledge has an independent fruit of its own. Let the inferential marks (referred to by the Pūrvapakshin) be; the direct teaching of the texts certainly refers to a being different from the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/09/</guid>
      <description>But the declarations are equal. The argument that knowledge must be held subordinate to work because we learn from Scripture that those who know Brahman perform sacrificial works, will not hold good; since, on the other hand, we also see that men knowing Brahman abandoned all work; cp. texts such as &amp;lsquo;The R̥shis descended from Kavasha said: For what purpose should we study the Veda? for what purpose should we sacrifice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/10/</guid>
      <description>(It is) non-comprehensive. The scriptural declaration does not refer to all meditations, but only to the meditation on the Udgītha. In the clause &amp;lsquo;what he does with knowledge,&amp;rsquo; the &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo; is in itself indefinite, and therefore must be defined as connecting itself with the Udgītha mentioned in the previous clause, &amp;lsquo;Let him meditate on the Udgītha.&amp;rsquo; The sentence cannot be construed to mean &amp;lsquo;whatever he does is to be done with knowledge,&amp;rsquo; but means &amp;rsquo;that which he does with knowledge becomes more vigorous,&amp;rsquo; and that which is done with knowledge that is the Udgītha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/11/</guid>
      <description>There is distribution, as in the case of the hundred. As knowledge and work have different results, the text &amp;lsquo;of him knowledge and work lay hold&amp;rsquo; must be understood in a distributive sense, i.e. as meaning that knowledge lays hold of him to the end of bringing about its own particular result, and that so likewise does work. &amp;lsquo;As in the case of a hundred,&amp;rsquo; i.e. as it is understood that, when a man selling a field and a gem is said to receive two hundred gold pieces, one hundred are given for the field and one hundred for the gem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/12/</guid>
      <description>Of him who has merely read the Veda. Nor is there any force in the argument that knowledge is only auxiliary to work because works are enjoined on him who possesses knowledge. For the text which refers to the man &amp;lsquo;who has read the Veda&amp;rsquo; enjoins works on him who has merely read the texts, and reading there means nothing more than the apprehension of the aggregate of syllables called Veda, without any insight into their meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/13/</guid>
      <description>Not so, on account of non-specification. Nor is it true that the text &amp;lsquo;Doing works here,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., is meant to divert him who knows the Self from knowledge and restrict him to works. For there is no special reason to hold that that text refers to works as independent means of a desirable result: it may as well be understood to refer to works merely subordinate to knowledge. As he who knows the Self has to practise meditation as long as he lives, he may also have to practise, for the same period, works that are helpful to meditation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/14/</guid>
      <description>Or the permission is for the purpose of glorification. The or has assertive force. The introductory words of the Upanishad, &amp;lsquo;Hidden in the Lord is all this,&amp;rsquo; show knowledge to be the subject-matter; hence the permission of works can aim only at the glorification of knowledge. The sense of the text therefore is&amp;ndash;owing to the power of
knowledge a man although constantly performing works is not stained by them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/15/</guid>
      <description>Some also, by proceeding according to their liking. In some śākhās, moreover, we read that he who possesses the knowledge of Brahman may, according to his liking, give up the state of a householder, &amp;lsquo;What shall we do with offspring, we who have this Self and this world?&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. V, 4, 22.) This text also proves knowledge not to be subsidiary to works; for if it were so subsidiary, it would not be possible for him who knows Brahman to give up householdership (with all the works obligatory on that state) according to his liking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/16/</guid>
      <description>And destruction. There is moreover a Vedānta-text which declares the knowledge of Brahman to destroy work-good and evil- which is the root of all the afflictions of transmigratory existence: &amp;lsquo;The knot of the heart is broken, all doubts are solved, all his works perish when He has been beheld who is high and low&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. II, 2, 8). This also contradicts the view of knowledge being subordinate to works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/17/</guid>
      <description>And of him who is chaste; for in Scripture (this is declared). The knowledge of Brahman belongs to those who have to observe chastity, and men living in that state have not to perform the Agnihotra, the Darśapūrṇamāsa, and similar works. For this reason also knowledge cannot be subsidiary to works.&amp;ndash;But, it may be objected, there is no such condition of life; for texts such as &amp;lsquo;he is to perform the Agnihotra as long as he lives,&amp;rsquo; declare men to be obliged to perform sacrifices and the like up to the end of their lives, and Smr̥ti texts contradicting Scripture have no authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/18/</guid>
      <description>A reference (only) Jaimini (holds them to be), on account of absence of injunction; for (Scripture) forbids. The argument for the three stages of life, founded on their mention in Vedic texts, has no force, since all those references are only of the nature of anuvāda. For none of those texts contain injunctive forms. The text &amp;lsquo;There are three branches of sacred observance,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Cḥ. Up. II, 23, 1), is meant to glorify the previous meditation on Brahman under the form of the pra«ava, as appears from the concluding clause &amp;lsquo;he who is firmly grounded in Brahman obtains immortality&amp;rsquo;; it therefore cannot mean to enjoin the three conditions of life as valid states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/19/</guid>
      <description>It is to be accomplished, Bādarayaṇa holds, on account of scriptural statement of equality. Bādarāyaṇa is of opinion that, in the same way as the condition of householdership, those other conditions of life also are obligatory; since in the section beginning &amp;rsquo;there are three branches of sacred duty&amp;rsquo; all the three conditions of life are equally referred to, with a view to glorifying him who is firmly grounded in Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/20/</guid>
      <description>Or an injunction, as in the case of the carrying. As the second part of the text &amp;lsquo;Let him approach carrying the firewood below the ladle; for above he carries
it for the gods&amp;rsquo; (which refers to a certain form of the Agnihotra), although having the form of an anuvāda, yet must be interpreted as an injunction, since the carrying of firewood above is not established by any other injunction; so the text under discussion also must be taken as an injunction of the different stages of life (which are not formally enjoined elsewhere).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/21/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that they are mere glorification, on account of their reference; not so, on account of the newness. The following point is next enquired into. Are texts such as &amp;lsquo;That Udgītha is the best of all essences, the highest, holding the supreme place, the eighth&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. I, 1, 3) meant to glorify the Udgītha as a constituent element of the sacrifice, or to enjoin a meditation on the Udgītha as the best of all essences, and so on?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/22/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the words denoting becoming. That the texts under discussion have an injunctive purport also follows from the fact that they contain verbal forms denoting becoming or origination&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;he is to meditate&amp;rsquo; and the like; for all such forms have injunctive force. All these texts therefore are meant to enjoin special forms of meditation.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of mere glorification.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/23/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that (the stories told in the Upanishads) are for the purpose of the Pāriplava; not so, since (certain stories) are specified. We meet in the Vedānta-texts with certain stories such as &amp;lsquo;Pratardana the son of Divodāsa came to the beloved abode of Indra,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., and similar ones. The question here arises whether the stories are merely meant to be recited at the Aśvamedha sacrifice or to convey knowledge of a special kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/24/</guid>
      <description>This follows also from the textual connexion (of those stories with injunctions). That those stories subserve injunctions of meditation is proved thereby also that they are exhibited in textual connexion with injunctions such as &amp;rsquo;the Self is to be seen,&amp;rsquo; and so on. Their position therefore is analogous to that of other stories told in the texts, which somehow subserve injunctions of works, and are not merely meant for purposes of recitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/25/</guid>
      <description>For this very reason there is no need of the lighting of the fire and so on. The Sūtras return, from their digression into the discussion of two special points, to the question as to those whose condition of life involves chastity. The above Sūtra declares that as persons of that class are referred to by Scripture as specially concerned with meditation (&amp;lsquo;He who is founded on Brahman reaches immortality;&amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo;those who in the forest,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/26/</guid>
      <description>And there is need of all (works), on account of the scriptural statement of sacrifices and the rest; as in the case of the horse.
If knowledge (meditation), without any reference to sacrifices and the like, is able to bring about immortality, it must be capable of accomplishing this in the case of householders also; and the mention made of sacrifices and the rest in texts such as &amp;lsquo;Brāhmaṇas seek to know him by the study of the Veda, by sacrifice, by gifts&amp;rsquo; (Br̥.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/27/</guid>
      <description>But all the same he must be possessed of calmness, subjection of the senses, &amp;amp;c., since those are enjoined as auxiliaries to that, and must necessarily be accomplished. The question is whether the householder also must practise calmness and so on, or not. The Pūrvapakshin says he must not, since the performance of works implies the activity of the outer and inner organs of action, and since calmness and so on are of an exactly opposite nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/28/</guid>
      <description>And there is permission of all food in the case of danger of life; on account of this being seen. In the meditation on prāṇa, according to the Vājasaneyins and the Cḥāndogas, there is a statement as to all food being allowed to him who knows the prāṇa. &amp;lsquo;By him there is nothing eaten that is not food&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. VI, 1, 14; and so on). A doubt here arises whether this permission of all food is valid for him who possesses the knowledge of prāṇa, in all circumstances, or only in the case of life being in danger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/29/</guid>
      <description>And on account of non-sublation. The conclusion above arrived at is confirmed by the consideration that thus only those texts are not stultified
which enjoin, for those who know Brahman, purity in matters of food with a view to the origination of knowledge of Brahman. Cp.&amp;rsquo; when the food is pure the mind becomes pure&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VII, 26, 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/30/</guid>
      <description>This is said in Smr̥ti also. That for those as well who know Brahman, as for others, the eating of food of any kind is lawful only in case of extreme need, Smr̥ti also declares, &amp;lsquo;He who being in danger of his life eats food from anywhere is stained by sin no more than the lotus leaf by water.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/31/</guid>
      <description>And hence also a scriptural passage as to non-proceeding according to liking. The above conclusion is further confirmed by a scriptural passage prohibiting licence of conduct on the part of any one. The text meant is a passage in the Saṁhitā of the Kaṭḥas, &amp;lsquo;Therefore a Brahmawa does not drink spirituous liquor, thinking &amp;ldquo;may I not be stained by sin.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;the allowance of all food.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/32/</guid>
      <description>The works of the āśramas also, on account of their being enjoined. It has been said that sacrifices and other works are auxiliary to the knowledge of Brahman. The doubt now arises whether those works are to be performed by him also who merely wishes to fulfil the duties of his āśrama, without aiming at final Release, or not. They are not, the Pūrvapakshin holds, for that things auxiliary to knowledge should stand in subordinate relation to a certain state of life would imply the contradiction of permanent and non-permanent obligation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/33/</guid>
      <description>And on account of co-operativeness. These works are to be performed also on account of their being co-operative towards knowledge in so far, namely, as they give rise to the desire of knowledge; and their thus being enjoined for a double purpose does not imply contradiction any more than the double injunctions of the Agnihotra, which one text connects with the life of the sacrificer and another text with his desire to reach the heavenly world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/34/</guid>
      <description>In any case they are the same, on account of twofold inferential signs. There is no radical difference of works; but in any case, i.e. whether they be viewed as duties incumbent on the āśrama or as auxiliary to knowledge, sacrifices and other works are one and the same. For Scripture, in enjoining them in both these aspects, makes use of the same terms, so that we recognise the same acts, and there is no means of proof to establish difference of works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/35/</guid>
      <description>And Scripture also declares (knowledge) not to be overpowered. Texts such as &amp;lsquo;By works of sacred duty he drives away evil&amp;rsquo; declare that sacrifices and similar works have the effect of knowledge &amp;rsquo;not being overpowered,&amp;rsquo; i.e. of the origination of knowledge not being obstructed by evil works. Sacrifices and similar works being performed day after day have the effect of purifying the mind, and owing to this, knowledge arises in the mind with ever increasing brightness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/36/</guid>
      <description>Also in the case of those outside, as this is seen. It has been declared that the members of the four āśramas have a claim to the knowledge of Brahman, and that the duties connected with each āśrarna promote knowledge. A doubt now arises whether those men also who, on account of poverty and so on, stand outside the āśramas are qualified for the knowledge of Brahman, or rtot.&amp;ndash;They are not, the Pūrvapakshin holds, since such knowledge is to be attained in a way dependent on the special duties of each āśrama; while those who do not belong to an āśrama are not concerned with āśrama duties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/37/</guid>
      <description>Smr̥ti also states this. Smr̥ti also declares that men not belonging to an āśrama grow in knowledge through prayer and the like. &amp;lsquo;Through prayer also a Brāhmaṇa may become perfect. May he perform other works or not, one who befriends all creatures is called a Brāhmaṇa&amp;rsquo; (Manu Smr̥. II, 17).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/38/</guid>
      <description>And there is the promotion (of knowledge) through special acts (of duty). The above conclusion is founded not only on Reasoning and Smr̥ti; but Scripture even directly states that knowledge is benefited by practices not exclusively prescribed for the āśramas, &amp;lsquo;By penance, abstinence, faith, and knowledge he is to seek the Self (Pr. Up. I, 10).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/39/</guid>
      <description>But better than that is the other also on account of an inferential mark. Better than to be outside the āśramas is the condition of standing within an āśrama. The latter state may be due to misfortune; but he who can should be within an āśrama, which state is the more holy and beneficial one. This follows from inference only, i.e. Smr̥ti; for Smr̥ti says, &amp;lsquo;A Brāhmaṇa is to remain outside the āśramas not even for one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/40/</guid>
      <description>But of him who has become that there is no becoming not that, according to Jaimini also, on account of (Scripture) restraining from the absence of the forms of that. The doubt here arises whether those also who have fallen from the state of life of a Naishṭḥika, Vaikhānasa or Pārivrājaka are qualified for the knowledge of Brahman or not.&amp;ndash;They are so, since in their case, no less than in that of widowers and the like, the growth of knowledge may be assisted by charity and other practices not confined to āśramas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/41/</guid>
      <description>Nor the (expiatory performance) described in the chapter treating of qualification; that being impossible on account of the Smr̥ti referring to such lapse. Those expiatory performances which are described in the chapter treating of qualification (Pū. Mī. Sū. VI) are not possible in the case of him who has lapsed from the condition of a Naishṭḥika; since such expiations do not apply to him, as is shown by a Smr̥ti text referring to such lapse, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/42/</guid>
      <description>A minor one, thus some; (and hence they hold) the existence (of expiation), as in the case of eating. This has been explained. Some teachers are of opinion that even on the part of Naishṭḥikas and the rest the lapse from chastity constitutes only a minor offence which can be atoned for by expiatory observances; in the same way as in the case of the eating of forbidden food the same prāyaścitta may be used by the ordinary Brahmacārin and by Naishṭḥikas and the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/43/</guid>
      <description>But in either case (such men) stand outside; on account of Smr̥ti and custom. Whether the point under discussion constitutes a minor or a major offence, in any case those who have lapsed stand outside the category of those qualified for the knowledge of Brahman. For Smr̥ti, i.e. the text quoted above, &amp;lsquo;I see no expiatory performance by which he, a slayer of Brahman as he is, could become pure again,&amp;rsquo; declares that expiations are powerless to restore purity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/45/</guid>
      <description>(They are) the priest&amp;rsquo;s work, Auḍulomi thinks; since for that he is engaged. The teacher Auḍulomi is of opinion that the meditation on the Udgītha and the like is the work of the priest, since it is he who is engaged for the purpose of performing that which gives rise to the fruit, i.e. of the entire sacrifice with all its subordinate parts. Injunctions referring to the performance of the sacrifices such as &amp;lsquo;he chooses the priests; he gives to the priests their fee&amp;rsquo; indicate that the entire sacrificial performance is the work of the priests, and that hence all activities comprised within it&amp;ndash;mental as well as bodily&amp;ndash;belong to the priests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/46/</guid>
      <description>There is injunction of other auxiliary means for him who is such, as in the case of injunction and so on; (the term mauna denoting) according to an alternative meaning a third something. &amp;lsquo;Therefore let a Brāhmaṇa after he has done with learning wish to stand by a childlike state; and after having done with the childlike state and learning (he is) a Muni&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. III, 5). A doubt arises whether this text enjoins Muni-hood in the same way as it enjoins learning and the childlike state, or merely refers to it as something already established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/47/</guid>
      <description>But on account of the existence (of knowledge) in all, there is winding up with the householder. As knowledge belongs to the members of all āśramas it belongs to the householder also, and for this reason the Upanishad winds up with the latter. This winding up therefore is meant to illustrate the duties (not of the householder only, but) of the members of all āśramas. Analogously in the text under discussion (Br̥.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/48/</guid>
      <description>On account of the others also being taught, in the same way as the condition of the Muni. The injunction, on him who has passed beyond all desire, of mauna preceded by pārivrājya (wandering about as a mendicant), is meant to illustrate the duties of all āśramas . For the duties of the other āśramas are taught by Scripture no less than those of the Muni (and the householder). Similarly it was shown above that in the text &amp;lsquo;There are three branches of sacred duty&amp;ndash;he who is founded on Brahman goes to immortality,&amp;rsquo; the term &amp;lsquo;founded on Brahman&amp;rsquo; applies equally to members of all āśramas .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/49/</guid>
      <description>Not manifesting itself; on account of the connexion. In the text discussed above we meet with the word &amp;lsquo;bālya,&amp;rsquo; which may mean either &amp;lsquo;being a child&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;being and doing like a child.&amp;rsquo; The former meaning is excluded, as that particular age which is called childhood cannot be assumed at will. With regard to the latter meaning, however, a doubt arises, viz. whether the text means to say that he who aims at perfect knowledge is to assume all the ways of a child, as e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/50/</guid>
      <description>What belongs to this world, there being no obstruction at hand; as this is seen. Knowledge, as enjoined by Scripture, is twofold, having
for its fruit either exaltation within the sphere of the Saṁsāra, or final Release. With regard to the former the question arises whether it springs up only immediately subsequent to the good works which are the means to bring it about; or, indefinitely, either subsequent to such works or at some later time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>51</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/4/51/</guid>
      <description>In the same way there is non-determination with regard to what has Release for its result; that condition being ascertained, that condition being ascertained. So likewise in the case of the origination, through works of very great merit, of such knowledge as has for its result final Release, the time is not definitely fixed; for here also there is ascertained the same condition, viz. the termination of the obstruction presented by other works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
