<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;04 Appendices on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;04 Appendices on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1: Who are the Bhagavatas?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/1_Who_are_the_Bhagavatas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/1_Who_are_the_Bhagavatas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;bhagavatas-in-the-padma-samhita&#34;&gt;Bhagavatas in the Padma-samhita&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Padma-samhita&lt;/em&gt;, Bhagavatas include Brahmins and non-Brahmins, both of whom receive diksha:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A [Brahmin] Bhagavata is one who, along with his devoted love of the Bhagavan, worships him five times a day at home or in a temple according to the scriptures, who is born in a Bhagavata family, and who has received consecration. While they must also maintain their private worship, [Brahmin] Bhagavatas are the only ones who are allowed to perform liturgies for the benefit of others in a village or town and should be employed in one’s home or in essential matters (&lt;em&gt;svatantra&lt;/em&gt;). One [a non-Brahmin] who belongs to a non-Bhagavata lineage (&lt;em&gt;vamsha&lt;/em&gt;) may be consecrated and maintain private worship, but may not perform worship for the benefit of others. Any Bhagavata [Brahmin or non-Brahmin]—whether by birth or consecration—is to be shown the highest respect and honor by all others. (&lt;em&gt;PS&lt;/em&gt; 4.13–24, modifying Smith 1975: 236)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2: Vasudeva’s Path in the *Satvata-samhita*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/2_Vasudevas_Path_in_the_Satvata-samhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/2_Vasudevas_Path_in_the_Satvata-samhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-satvata-system&#34;&gt;The Satvata System&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To perceive God in all things and all things in God is to be wide awake (&lt;em&gt;sambuddha&lt;/em&gt;). If one is wide awake, one’s death will be “extinguishing into &lt;em&gt;brahman&lt;/em&gt;” (&lt;em&gt;brahmanirvana&lt;/em&gt;) and eternal presence in God’s supreme home (&lt;em&gt;dhama parama&lt;/em&gt;). Only a few Bhagavatas attain this goal, because it requires the sadhaka’s full attention day and night and God’s grace. But every serious devotee can begin walking the path even if most go only the minimum distance. The path is “Approaching the Honey of the Lotus Feet,” and the feet are Krishna’s as he dances on Kaliya. Vasudeva described this path to the Plower as a body of teachings now found in the &lt;em&gt;Satvata-samhita&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3: Prithu, the People’s Indra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/3_Prithu_the_Peoples_Indra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/3_Prithu_the_Peoples_Indra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;prithu-in-the-shatapatha-brahmana&#34;&gt;Prithu in the &lt;em&gt;Shatapatha Brahmana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as the south-facing sequence of the “Path of the Southern Doctrine” begins with the sculpted panel of Prithu’s sacrifice at the southwest corner of nirriti, the rajasuya ceremony begins with an oblation to Nirriti south of the sacrificial ground. Her oblation is made with a firebrand from the southern fire at a “self-produced hollow or cleft.” The priest offers her the grains that fell to the ground during the preparation of sacrificial food for her complement named Anumati. Before Anumati can be enlisted on behalf of the rajasuya’s sponsor, Nirriti must be satisfied: “For Nirriti is this (earth); whomsoever she seizes upon with evil, him she seizes upon with destruction (&lt;em&gt;nirriti&lt;/em&gt;): hence whatever part of this (earth) is of the Nirriti nature, that he thereby propitiates; and thus Nirriti does not seize upon him, while being consecrated. And the reason why he offers in a self-produced hollow or cleft, is that that much of this (earth) is possessed with Nirriti” (&lt;em&gt;SB&lt;/em&gt; 5.2.3.2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4: Mantras in The *Jayakhya-samhita*</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/4_Mantras_in_The_Jayakhya-samhita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/04_Appendices/4_Mantras_in_The_Jayakhya-samhita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;Jayakhya-samhita&lt;/em&gt;, Hari explains to Narada that the reason portions of him in sonic bodies of vowels and consonants may be used to attain emancipation and worldly enjoyment is because the virya of his own unified consciousness operates their mantra shapes. Mantras intended for emancipation are of his shape having no parts (&lt;em&gt;nishkala&lt;/em&gt;), while those intended for worldly success are of his shape having parts (&lt;em&gt;sakala&lt;/em&gt;) (&lt;em&gt;JS&lt;/em&gt; 4.30–33; Smith 1975:116). Hari also tells him that mantras employed under the guidance of a guru in the practice of yoga will produce worldly success and emancipation, but leaves the topic of yoga for the final chapter (&lt;em&gt;JS&lt;/em&gt; 5.1–10). Mantras employed during ceremonial performance (&lt;em&gt;kriya&lt;/em&gt;) are of greater relevance to most people, and he explains them with the metaphor of a nursing mother of a newborn: “And another means gives success by means of mantras with ‘mantra breasts.’ When employed using mudra and other instruments they give birth to samadhis born from the heart. All mantras likewise uttered during ceremonies by sadhakas who are truly good possess supreme power [over] myriads of thousands of obstacles” (&lt;em&gt;JS&lt;/em&gt; 5.31–32; my translation).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
