<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>01 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 01 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 the small pūrvapaksha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>THE SMALL PŪRVAPAKSHA.
THE SMALL PŪRVAPAKSHA. But&amp;ndash;a further objection is urged&amp;ndash;as that which has to precede the systematic enquiry into Brahman we should assign something which that enquiry necessarily presupposes. The enquiry into the nature of duty, however, does not form such a prerequisite, since a consideration of the Vedanta-texts may be undertaken by any one who has read those texts, even if he is not acquainted with works.&amp;ndash;But in the Vedanta-texts there are enjoined meditations on the Udgītha and the like which;uc matters auxiliary to works; and such meditations are not possible for him who is not acquainted with those works!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 the small siddhānta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/02/</guid>
      <description>THE SMALL SIDDHĀNTA.
THE SMALL SIDDHĀNTA. To this argumentation we make the following reply. We admit that release consists only in the cessation of Nescience, and that this cessation results entirely from the knowledge of Brahman. But a distinction has here to be made regarding the nature of this knowledge which
the Vedānta-texts aim at enjoining for the purpose of putting an end to Nescience. Is it merely the knowledge of the sense of sentences which originates from the sentences?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 the great pūrvapaksha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/03/</guid>
      <description>THE GREAT PŪRVAPAKSHA.
THE GREAT PŪRVAPAKSHA. THE ONLY REALITY IS BRAHMAN. Brahman, which is pure intelligence and opposed to all difference, constitutes the only reality; and everything else, i.e. the plurality of manifold knowing subjects, objects of knowledge, and acts of knowledge depending on those two, is only imagined on (or &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo;) that Brahman, and is essentially false.
&amp;lsquo;In the beginning, my dear, there was that only which is, one only without a second&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 the great siddhānta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/04/</guid>
      <description>THE GREAT SIDDHĀNTA.
THE GREAT SIDDHĀNTA. This entire theory rests on a fictitious foundation of altogether hollow and vicious arguments, incapable of being stated in definite logical alternatives, and devised by men who are destitute of those particular qualities which cause individuals to be chosen by the Supreme Person revealed in the Upanishads; whose intellects are darkened by the impression of beginningless evil; and who thus have no insight into the nature of words and sentences, into the real purport conveyed by them, and into the procedure of sound argumentation, with all its methods depending on perception and the other instruments of right knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 there is no</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/05/</guid>
      <description>There is no proof of non-differenced substance.
There is no proof of non-differenced substance. To enter into details.&amp;ndash;Those who maintain the doctrine of a substance devoid of all difference have no right to assert that this or that is a proof of such a substance; for all means of right knowledge have for their object things affected with difference.&amp;ndash;Should any one taking his stand on the received views of his sect, assert that the theory of a substance free from all difference (does not require any further means of proof but) is immediately established by one&amp;rsquo;s own consciousness; we reply that he also is refuted by the fact, warranted by the witness of the Self, that all consciousness implies difference: all states of consciousness have for their object something that is marked by some difference, as appears in the case of judgments like &amp;lsquo;I saw this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Sound</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/06/</guid>
      <description>S
S As to sound (speech; śabda) it is specially apparent that it possesses the power of denoting only such things as are affected with difference. Speech operates with words and sentences. Now a word (pada) originates from the combination of a radical element and a suffix, and as these two elements have different meanings it necessarily follows that the word itself can convey only a sense affected with difference. And further, the plurality of words is based on plurality of meanings; the sentence therefore which is an aggregate of words expresses some special combination of things (meanings of words), and hence has no power to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 pratyakshaeven of the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/07/</guid>
      <description>Pratyaksha&amp;ndash;even of the nirvikalpaka kind&amp;ndash;proves difference.
Pratyaksha&amp;ndash;even of the nirvikalpaka kind&amp;ndash;proves difference. Perception in the next place&amp;ndash;with its two subdivisions of non-determinate (nirvikalpaka) and determinate (savikalpaka) perception&amp;ndash;also cannot be a means of knowledge for things devoid of difference. Determinate perception clearly has for its object things affected with difference; for it relates to that which is distinguished by generic difference and so on. But also non-determinate perception has for its object only what is marked with difference; for it is on the basis of non-determinate perception that the object distinguished by generic character and so on is recognised in the act of determinate perception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 the bhedābheda view</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/08/</guid>
      <description>The bhedābheda view is untenable.
The bhedābheda view is untenable. The same arguments tend to refute the view that there is difference and absence of difference at the same time (the so-called bhedābheda view). Take the judgment &amp;lsquo;This is such and such&amp;rsquo;; how can we realise here the non-difference of &amp;lsquo;being this&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;being such and such&amp;rsquo;? The &amp;lsquo;such and such&amp;rsquo; denotes a peculiar make characterised, e.g. by a dewlap, the &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo; denotes the thing distinguished by that peculiar make; the non-difference of these two is thus contradicted by immediate consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 inference also teaches</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/09/</guid>
      <description>Inference also teaches difference.
Inference also teaches difference. Perception thus having for its object only what is marked by difference, inference also is in the same case; for its object is only what is distinguished by connexion with things known through perception and other means of knowledge. And thus, even in the case of disagreement as to the number of the different instruments of knowledge, a thing devoid of difference could not be established by any of them since the instruments of knowledge acknowledged by all have only one and the same object, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 perception does not</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/10/</guid>
      <description>Perception does not reveal mere being.
Perception does not reveal mere being. In reply to the assertion that perception causes the apprehension of pure Being only, and therefore cannot have difference for its object; and that &amp;lsquo;difference&amp;rsquo; cannot be defined because it does not admit of being set forth in definite alternatives; we point out that these charges are completely refuted by the fact that the only objects of perception are things distinguished by generic character and so on, and that generic character and so on&amp;ndash;as being relative things&amp;ndash;give at once rise to the judgment as to the distinction between themselves and the things in which they inhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 plurality is not</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/11/</guid>
      <description>Plurality is not unreal.
Plurality is not unreal. Next as to the assertion that all difference presented in our cognition-as of jars, pieces of cloth and the like&amp;ndash;is unreal because such difference does not persist. This view, we maintain, is altogether erroneous, springs in fact from the neglect of distinguishing between persistence and non-persistence on the one hand, and the relation between what sublates and what is sublated on the other hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 being and consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/12/</guid>
      <description>Being and consciousness are not one.
Being and consciousness are not one. Hence mere Being does not alone constitute reality. And as the distinction between consciousness and its objects&amp;ndash;which rests just on this relation of object and that for which the object is&amp;ndash;is proved by perception, the assertion that only consciousness has real existence is also disposed of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 the true meaning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/13/</guid>
      <description>The true meaning of Svayaṁprakāsatva.
The true meaning of Svayaṁprakāsatva. We next take up the point as to the self-luminousness of consciousness (above, p. 33). The contention that consciousness is not an object holds good for the knowing Self at the
time when it illumines (i.e. constitutes as its objects) other things; but there is no absolute rule as to all consciousness never being anything but self-luminous. For common observation shows that the consciousness of one person may become the object of the cognition of another, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 consciousness is not</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/14/</guid>
      <description>Consciousness is not eternal.
Consciousness is not eternal. It was further maintained by the pūrvapakshin that as consciousness is self-established it has no antecedent non-existence and so on, and that this disproves its having an origin. But this is an attempt to prove something not proved by something else that is equally unproved; comparable to a man blind from birth undertaking to guide another blind man! You have no right to maintain the non-existence of the antecedent non-existence of consciousness on the ground that there is nothing to make us apprehend that non-existence; for there is something to make us apprehend it, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 there is no</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/15/</guid>
      <description>There is no consciousness without object.
There is no consciousness without object. Nor is there any consciousness devoid of objects; for nothing of this kind is ever known. Moreover, the self-luminousness of consciousness has, by our opponent himself, been proved on the ground that its essential nature consists in illumining (revealing) objects; the self-luminousness of consciousness not admitting of proof apart from its essential nature which consists in the lighting up of objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 consciousness is capable</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/16/</guid>
      <description>Consciousness is capable of change.
Consciousness is capable of change. Against the assertion that the alleged non-origination of consciousness at the same time proves that consciousness is not capable of any other changes (p. 36), we remark that the general proposition on which this conclusion rests is too wide: it would extend to antecedent non-existence itself, of which it is evident that it comes to an end, although it does not originate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17 consciousness is the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/17/</guid>
      <description>Consciousness is the attribute of a permanent Conscious self.
Consciousness is the attribute of a permanent Conscious self. Let it then be said that consciousness is proof (siddhiḥ) itself. Proof of what, we ask in reply, and to whom? If no definite answer can be given to these two questions, consciousness cannot be defined as &amp;lsquo;proof&amp;rsquo;; for &amp;lsquo;proof&amp;rsquo; is a relative notion, like &amp;lsquo;son.&amp;rsquo; You will perhaps reply &amp;lsquo;Proof to the Self&amp;rsquo;; and if we go on asking &amp;lsquo;But what is that Self&amp;rsquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 the view that</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/18/</guid>
      <description>The view that the conscious subject is something unreal, due to the ahaṁkāra, cannot be maintained.
The view that the conscious subject is something unreal, due to the ahaṁkāra, cannot be maintained. We turn to a further point. You maintain that consciousness which is in reality devoid alike of objects and substrate presents itself, owing to error, in the form of a knowing subject, just as mother o&amp;rsquo; pearl appears as silver; (consciousness itself being viewed as a real substrate of an erroneous imputation), because an erroneous imputation cannot take place apart from a substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19 the conscious subject</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/19/</guid>
      <description>The conscious subject persists in deep sleep.
The conscious subject persists in deep sleep. We now come to the question as to the nature of deep sleep. In deep sleep the quality of darkness prevails in the mind and there is no consciousness of outward things, and thus there is no distinct and clear presentation of the &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;; but all the same the Self somehow presents itself up to the time of waking in the one form of the &amp;lsquo;I,&amp;rsquo; and the latter cannot therefore be said to be absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 the conscious subject</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/20/</guid>
      <description>The conscious subject persists in the state of release.
The conscious subject persists in the state of release. To maintain that the consciousness of the &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; does not persist in the state of final release is again altogether inappropriate.
It in fact amounts to the doctrine&amp;ndash;only expressed in somewhat different words&amp;ndash;that final release is the annihilation of the Self. The &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; is not a mere attribute of the Self so that even after its destruction the essential nature of the Self might persist&amp;ndash;as it persists on the cessation of ignorance; but it constitutes the very nature of the Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 in cases of</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/21/</guid>
      <description>In cases of Scripture conflicting with Perception, Scripture is not stronger. The True cannot be known through the Untrue.
In cases of Scripture conflicting with Perception, Scripture is not stronger. The True cannot be known through the Untrue. With reference to the assertion (p. 24 ff.) that Perception, which depends on the view of plurality, is based on some defect and hence admits of being otherwise accounted for&amp;ndash;whence it follows that it is sublated by Scripture; we ask you to point out what defect it is on which Perception is based and may hence be accounted for otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22 no scriptural texts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/22/</guid>
      <description>No scriptural texts teach a Brahman devoid of all difference.
No scriptural texts teach a Brahman devoid of all difference. We now turn to the assertion that certain scriptural texts, as e.g. &amp;lsquo;Being only was this in the beginning,&amp;rsquo; are meant to teach that there truly exists only one homogeneous substance, viz. Intelligence free from all difference.&amp;ndash;This we cannot allow. For the section in which the quoted text occurs, in order to make good the initial declaration that by the knowledge of one thing all things are known, shows that the highest Brahman which is denoted by the term &amp;lsquo;Being&amp;rsquo; is the substantial and also the operative cause of the world; that it is all-knowing, endowed with all powers; that its purposes come true; that it is the inward principle, the support and the ruler of everything; and that distinguished by these and other good qualities it constitutes the Self of the entire world; and then finally proceeds to instruct Śvetaketu that this Brahman constitutes his Self also (&amp;lsquo;Thou art that&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 nor do smṛti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/23/</guid>
      <description>Nor do Smr̥ti and Purāṇa teach such a doctrine.
Nor do Smr̥ti and Purāṇa teach such a doctrine. Nor is it true that also according to Smr̥ti and Purāṇas only non-differenced consciousness is real and everything else unreal.&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;He who knows me as unborn and without a beginning, the supreme Lord of the worlds&amp;rsquo; (Bha. Gī. X, 3); &amp;lsquo;All beings abide in me, I abide not in them. Nay, the beings abide not in me&amp;ndash;behold my lordly power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 the theory of</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/24/</guid>
      <description>The theory of Nescience cannot be proved.
The theory of Nescience cannot be proved. We now proceed to the consideration of Nescience.&amp;ndash;According to the view of our opponent, this entire world, with all its endless distinctions of Ruler, creatures ruled, and so on, is, owing to a certain defect, fictitiously superimposed upon the non-differenced, self-luminous Reality; and what constitutes that defect is beginningless Nescience, which invests the Reality, gives rise to manifold illusions, and cannot be denned either as being or non-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 all knowledge is</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/25/</guid>
      <description>All knowledge is of the Real.
All knowledge is of the Real. &amp;lsquo;Those who understand the Veda hold that all cognition has for its object what is real; for.Śruti and Smr̥ti alike teach that everything participates in the nature of everything else. In the scriptural account of creation preceded by intention on the part of the Creator it is said that each of these elements was made tripartite; and this tripartite constitution of all things is apprehended by Perception as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26 neither scripture nor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/26/</guid>
      <description>Neither Scripture nor Smr̥ti and Purāṇa teach Nescience.
Neither Scripture nor Smr̥ti and Purāṇa teach Nescience. The assertion that Nescience&amp;ndash;to be defined neither as that which is nor as that which is not&amp;ndash;rests on the authority of Scripture is untrue. In passages such as &amp;lsquo;hidden by the untrue&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 3, 2), the word &amp;lsquo;untrue&amp;rsquo; does not denote the Undefinable; it rather means that which is different from &amp;lsquo;r̥ta,&amp;rsquo; and this latter word&amp;ndash;as we see from the passage &amp;rsquo;enjoying the r̥ta&amp;rsquo; (Ka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27 scripture does not</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/27/</guid>
      <description>Scripture does not teach that Release is due to the knowledge of a non-qualified Brahman.&amp;ndash;the meaning of &amp;rsquo;tat tvam asi.&#39;
Scripture does not teach that Release is due to the knowledge of a non-qualified Brahman.&amp;ndash;the meaning of &amp;rsquo;tat tvam asi.&#39; Nor can we admit the assertion that Scripture teaches the cessation of avidyā to spring only from the cognition of a Brahman devoid of all difference. Such a view is clearly negatived by passages such as the following: &amp;lsquo;I know that great person of sun-like lustre beyond darkness; knowing him a man becomes immortal, there is no other</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 summary statement as</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/28/</guid>
      <description>Summary statement as to the way in which different scriptural texts are to reconciled.
Summary statement as to the way in which different scriptural texts are to reconciled. The whole matter may be summarily stated as follows. Some texts declare a distinction of nature between non-intelligent matter, intelligent beings, and Brahman, in so far as matter is the object of enjoyment, the souls the enjoying subjects, and Brahman the ruling principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29 nescience cannot be</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/29/</guid>
      <description>Nescience cannot be terminated by the simple act of cognising Brahman as the universal self.
Nescience cannot be terminated by the simple act of cognising Brahman as the universal self. The doctrine, again, that Nescience is put an end to by the cognition of Brahman being the Self of all can in no way be upheld; for as bondage is something real it cannot be put an end to by knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 the vedāntin aiming</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/01/30/</guid>
      <description>The Vedāntin aiming to ascertain the nature of Brahman from Scripture, need not be disconcerted by the Mīmāṁsā-theory of all speech having informing power with regard to actions only.
The Vedāntin aiming to ascertain the nature of Brahman from Scripture, need not be disconcerted by the Mīmāṁsā-theory of all speech having informing power with regard to actions only. Here another primā facie view 1 finally presents itself. The power of words to denote things cannot be ascertained in any way but by observing the speech and actions of experienced people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
