<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;तत्त्वम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;तत्त्वम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>नारायणभट्ट-भक्त-भूषण-सन्दर्भः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/nArAyaNa-bhaTTa-bhakta-bhushana-sandarbhaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/nArAyaNa-bhaTTa-bhakta-bhushana-sandarbhaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[TODO: परिष्कार्यम्]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;श्रीगौरहरिर्जयति&#xA;भक्तभूषण सन्दर्भः&#xA;ब्रजाचार्य-&#xA;महामहिम श्रीश्रीनारायणभट्ट बिरचितः&#xA;(सानुवादः)&#xA;संगणक संस्करणं दासाभासेन हरिपार्षद्वासेन&#xA;कृतम&#xA;सम्वत् २०२१&#xA;प्रथमावृत्ति ५०० मूल्य १)&#xA;Digitization,&#xA;PDF Greation&#xA;and uploading&#xA;by:&#xA;Hari Parsada Dasa (R44)&#xA;प्रकाशक व मुद्रक-&#xA;कृष्णदास बाबा&#xA;गौरहरि प्रेस, कुसुमसरोवर, राधाकुण्ड&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;भक्तभूषणसन्दर्भः&#xA;-::::-&#xA;नित्यगुणाश्रयमीशं प्रकटितरसिकं च विश्वमाक्रीडम् । भजनरसाश्रयमानैर्गम्यं पश्यन् जनो जयति ॥ १॥ भक्तालङ्क तिसन्दर्भे प्रोक्त प्रकरणं&#xA;त्रयम् । कृष्ण-भक्त- जगद्वाचि क्रमेणैव विचार्यते ॥२॥ ईशं सर्वगुणाश्रयं प्रकटितरसिकं नित्यसिद्ध एव प्रकटित आविभू- तो यो रसिकस्तं, बिश्वं चाक्रीडं क्रीडोपकरणं पश्यन् जनः भक्तः जयति रसास्वादकतया विराजत इत्यर्थः । कीदृशं ईशं विश्वं च ? भजनरसाश्रयमानैर्गम्यं भजनरसं श्राश्रयन्ति यान्यनुमानानि प्रत्यक्षादिप्रमाणानि तैर्गम्यं विषयीकृतमास्वादय च । तत्रेशे केचिद्र प-रस-गंध-स्पर्श संख्या-परिमाण -पृथक्त्व-संयोग- विभाग- परत्वापरत्व- गुरुत्व- द्रवत्व-स्नेह-शब्द-बुद्धि-सुख दुःखेच्छा- द्वेष- प्रयत्न- धर्माधर्म- गुणवत्वं बदन्ति । सांख्याः कूटस्थत्वं तत्त न शिष्टादरणीयं यथात्वस्य श्रुताबनुक्तः । न च सांख्यादोनां गुणत्वं श्रयते, न च कूटस्थत्वे भक्तवात्सल्यादयः संभवति । ततश्च श्रुतिपुराणप्रसिद्धा ये गुणास्तद्वत्वं ज्ञेयम् । तत्र केचित् &amp;ldquo;अगोत्र- मवर्णमचक्षुः श्रोत्रं निष्कलं निष्क्रियं निरञ्जनं निष्कलं निलयनो अस्थूलमरगुबिरजो बिमृत्युविशोको बिजिघत्सो विपास:&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;यतो बाचो निबत्तन्ते” “कूटस्थेपीश्वरे आत्मे&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;त्यादिवाकयः कूटस्थत्वं निद्रम्मकत्वमिति बदन्ति । तत्र पृच्छाम:- निद्धर्मकस्य लोकवे- दाप्रतीतेः बंध्यापुत्रवत् । किञ्च निद्धर्मकत्वं वेदादिप्रमाणगम्यं न वा? प्रमाणगम्यं चेदागतं सधर्मकत्वमेव । नहि निद्धर्मकत्वं कुत्रापि प्रमीयते । निर्धर्मके वस्तुनि सधर्मकत्वप्रतिपादने वेदस्या- प्रामाण्यं स्यात् । न च &amp;ldquo;याजमानोऽयं प्रस्तर&amp;rdquo; इत्यत्र यथा यज्ञ- साधनधर्मवति धर्मे वाधितेऽपि प्रस्तरशब्दः साधनधर्मपरः प्रमा-&#xA;I&#xA;सहकृतेन बाक्य ेन यजमानः प्रस्तरः यज्ञसाधनं तद्वदत्रापि सर्व-&#xA;(२&#xA;&amp;quot;&#xA;स्य वशी सर्वस्य कर्त्त त्यादौ वाधकवाक्यान्तरसहकृतेन धर्मबाधे बाकयार्थसंको चाल्लक्षणया निधर्मकत्वे पर्यवसानं भविष्यतीति वाच्यं । न चेदस्याप्रामाण्यमिति वाच्यं । धर्मि - धम्मभावस्य प्रामाणिकत्वे न कुत्रापि भवतानभ्युपगमात् । कल्पितधर्मवाधे सत्यकाम इत्यादौ सत्यादिपदबाधः स्यात् । नहि निर्धर्मकब्रह्म- बोधने सत्यादिपदमनुकूलं प्रत्युत प्रतिकूलमेव । किञ्च कुत्रापि प्रामाणिकत्वे सिद्ध कल्पितत्वं सिध्यति अन्यथा कल्पकप्रमाण- स्यापि मिध्यात्वेन कल्पितत्वग्यैवा सिद्ध, ओमिति चेत्तर्हि ब्रह्म- गोऽपि कल्पितत्वे शून्यमेवावशिष्टं स्यात् । निर्धर्मकस्वप्रकाशे स्वतः सिद्ध े ब्रह्मणि नान्यापेक्षेति न शून्यतेति चेन्न, &amp;ldquo;अथातो ब्रह्मजिज्ञासा&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;सोन्वेष्टव्यः स विजिज्ञासितव्य&amp;rdquo; इत्यादि श्रति- स्मृति सूत्र- गुर्वादय पदेशानयं स्यात् । किञ्च वेदस्य प्रामा- ण्यमप्रामाण्यं वा प्रामाण्ये तासिद्धौ सधर्मकत्वं श्रप्रामाण्ये बौद्ध- मतप्रवेशजजगदांध्यं च स्यात्, प्रवृत्त्येकवेदस्याप्रामाण्यात् &amp;ldquo;तस्मा- द्वा एतस्मादात्मनः आकाशः संभूतः” “सर्वं खल्विदं ब्रह्म&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;ऐतदा- त्म्यमिदं सर्वं ” “ एष एव साधुकर्म्म कारयति यमूद्ध मुन्निनीषति एष एवासाधुकम कारयति यमधो निनीषति” “पापः पापेन कर्मणा भवति साधुकारी साधु र्भवति&amp;rdquo; इत्यादि प्रवत्त कवाकयानामान- थ्य कथं स्यात् । अज्ञ प्रतीत्यादिपरिपाटी प्रतारणमात्रं तदुक्तं भास्करभाष्ये &amp;ldquo;नहि रूपमनंधानामसत्यं तेष्वसद्भवेत् तन्मते स्वप्रकाश ब्रह्मातिरिक्तस्याभावात् । नच &amp;ldquo;न निरोधो न चोत्पत्ति- नेच बंधो न साधकः । न मुमुक्षुर्नवै मुक्त इत्येषा परमार्थता &amp;quot; इति वाच्यं तव उल्ल कबदुपेक्षणीयत्वात्तथोक्त&amp;rsquo; &amp;quot; न च कार्ये प्रतिपत्यभिसंधिः&amp;rdquo; अस्मिन्नधिकरणे भाष्यकारेण &amp;quot; नहि निगुणं वस्तु विदयते, नहि प्रकाशादिप्रत्याख्याने अग्निर्नाम, नापि द्रव्यप्रत्याख्याने गुणो नामास्ति । यदि चेत्तन्मात्र ब्रह्म तहि आनन्द - गुणोपदेशे व्यर्थता स्यात् । सर्बज्ञत्वं सर्बशक्तित्वं सर्व-&#xA;9&#xA;&amp;quot;&#xA;( ३ )&#xA;कर्तृत्वमित्यादयो गुणाः परस्यासाधारणा&amp;rdquo; इति फलाध्याये कंठो तत्वात् । यदि चास्मादुक्तजीवभेदप्रतिपादकप्रामाण्येष्वस्म- दुक्ताभासैरेव दृषणमुच्यते त्वया तच स्माभिरपि त्वोक्त प्रबोध- प्रमाणानां त्वां प्रति तव मते मिध्यात्वेऽपि ह्य च्यमाने भेद एव प्रमाणिक इति । पदयार्थस्तु सर्वस्य मिथ्यानुसंधानेन रागादि- राहित्यं ततः भगवाँस्फुरणमिति । न निरोध इत्युक्त्वा वीतरागभ- । यक्रोधै मुनिभिरिति मध्ये उक्त्वा तत्वीभूतरतदा रामस्तत्वा दप्रच्युतो भवेदिति उपसंहृतम् । अन्यथा ब्रहीभूत इति स्यात् । विषं भुवेतिवत् । वैराग्यार्थमेव सर्वस्य मिध्यात्वमुच्यते न तु तथा, तथा श्रुत्यन्तरे- विद्वान्परात्परं पुरुषमुपैति दिव्यमित्युक्त&amp;rsquo; न तु परपुरुषो भवत्युक्तमिति । तस्मात् &amp;ldquo;विशोको विजिघत्सोऽबि- पासः सत्यकामः सत्यसंकल्पः नित्यं विभु सर्वगतं सूक्ष्मं द्रष्टा श्रोता रसयिता घ्राता वोद्धा मंता कर्ता विज्ञानात्मा&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;तमीश्व- राणां परमं महेश्वरं सर्वकर्मा सर्वकामः सर्वरसः&amp;rdquo; इत्यादिगुणा सिद्धाः । विष्णुधर्मोत्तरे चे-&#xA;।&#xA;&amp;quot; गुणाः सर्वेऽपि युज्यन्ते स्वैश्वर्यात्परमेश्वरे । दोषाः कथञ्चिन्नवान युज्यन्ते परमो हि सः । गुणदोषौ माययैव केचिदाहुर पण्डिताः” । कल्पितधर्मवादिनो मूर्खा इति हृदयम् ॥ श्रीभागवते साम्यासंगादयो गुणाः श्रगुणा गुणपरिणामरूपा न नित्या इत्यर्थः ।&#xA;सत्यं शौचं दया क्षान्तिस्त्यागः सन्तोष आर्जवम् । शमो दमस्तपः साम्यं तितिक्षोपरतिः श्रुतम् ज्ञानं बिरक्तिरैश्वय्यं शौर्यं तेजो वलं स्मृतिः । स्वातन्त्र्यं कौशलं कान्ति धैय्र्यमार्दवमेव च । प्रागल्भ्यं प्रश्रयः शीलं मह ओजो बलं भगः ।&#xA;( 8 )&#xA;गाम्भीर्यं स्थैर्य मास्तिकच कीर्त्तिर्मानोऽनहंकृतिः । इमे चान्ये च भगवन्नित्या यत्र महागुणाः” ।।&#xA;इत्यादि । सिद्धम् ॥१॥&#xA;श्रुतिस्मृतिश्रीभागवतादिप्रतिपादित नित्यगुणवत्त्वं&#xA;ननु &amp;ldquo;यतो वाचो तिवत्तन्ते अप्राप्य मनसा सह&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;विज्ञाता- रमरे केन विजानीयां&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;स्वयं ज्योतिः स्वप्रकाश&amp;rdquo; इत्यादिभिर्निध- मकत्वमायातीति चेन्न । “सन्मात्रो नित्यः शुद्धो बुद्धः सत्यो मुक्तो निरज्जनो विभुरद्वयात्मानंदः परः प्रत्यगेकरसः प्रमाणैरेतैरव- गत&amp;rdquo; इति महोपनिषदि सर्व प्रमाण गम्यत्वोक्तयंत इति विज्ञाता- रमिति स्वयं ज्योतिरित्यादिवाक्यैरेव सधर्मकत्व सिद्ध । तयोक्त भाष्यकारेण प्रथमचरण - &amp;quot; श्रानन्दगुणस्य ब्रह्मणो विवक्षितत्वात्&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>व्रज-भक्ति-विलासः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/vraja-bhakti-vilAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/vraja-bhakti-vilAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;श्री-नारायण-भट्ट-विरचितं&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्री-व्रज-भक्ति-विलासं&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्री-नारायण-भट्ट-विरचितं&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्री-व्रज-भक्ति-विलासं&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;रधया सहितं कृष्णं लाडिलेयं स्वभिष्टकम् ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;रेवती-सहितं देवं वन्देऽहञ् च हलायुधम् ॥१॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;कृष्णाज्ञया कृतं स्वेष्टं नत्वा देव-त्रयं शुभम् ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;शङ्करं परमानन्दं सर्व-विद्या-विशारदम् ॥२॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;कुर्वेऽहं पञ्चमं गोप्यं वन-यात्रा-शुभ-प्रदम् ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;व्रज-भक्ति-विलासाख्यं व्रज-माहात्म्य-दर्शिनम् ॥३॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;वास-प्रदक्षिणार्थाय दान-पूजन-हेतवे ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;त्रयोदश-सहस्रैस् तु सङ्ख्या-वेष्टित-सुन्दरम् ॥४॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;समस्त-व्रज-द्वाराणि वनान्य् उपवनानि च ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;प्रतिवनाधिवनानि स्युः बहु-पुNय-प्रदानि च ॥५॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;द्वादशा द्वादशाख्यातास् त्व् अष्ट-चत्वार-सङ्ख्यका ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;मासेषु द्वादशेष्व् एषु मासो भाद्रपदो वरः ॥६॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;तस्मिन् प्रदक्षिणा कार्या मन्त्रपूर्व विधानतः ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;यथोक्त विधिना कुर्याद् दान पूजन पूर्वकम् ॥७॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>श्रीधरः - प्रपन्न-जीवामृतम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/shrIdhara-deva-prapanna-jIvAmRtam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/tattvam/shrIdhara-deva-prapanna-jIvAmRtam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sri-sri-prapanna-jivanamrtam&#34;&gt;Sri Sri Prapanna-jivanamrtam&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;death-stone-would-be-more-immortal-than-human-beings-and-conscious-entities-would-be-mortal-forever-denied-immortality-what-then-is-the-positive-conception-of-immortality-how-are-the-immortal-immortal-what-is-the-positive-reality-in-immortality-how-can-one-become-immortal-one-must-search-out-his-intrinsic-location-in-the-universal-order-it-will-not-do-to-attempt-to-solve-only-the-negative-side-of-life-which-is-full-of-suffering---birth-death-infirmity-and-disease-we-should-know-that-there-exists-a-conception-of-life-worth-living-for-this-positive-side-has-been-almost-totally-neglected-in-general-religious-views&#34;&gt;The Complete Unabridged English Edition -&#xA;Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls Positive and Progressive Immortality&#xA;by the Intimate Servitor of&#xA;the Illustrious Universal Preceptor of Vaisnava Thought, Vaisnava-siddhantacarya-samrat Jagad-guru&#xA;Prabhupada Sri Srimad Bhakti Siddhanta Saraswati Goswami Maharaja:&#xA;Om Visnupada Paramahamsa Parivrajakacarya-varya Sarva-sastra-siddhanta-vit Astottara-sata-&#xA;Sri Srimad Bhakti Raksaka Sridhara Deva Goswami Maharaja&#xA;Published by the Appointed President-Acarya Parivrajakacarya Srimad Bhakti Sundara Govinda Maharaja&#xA;Rendered into English by&#xA;Tridandiswami Sripada Bhakti Ananda Sagara Maharaja&#xA;Preface&#xA;(translated from the Publisher&amp;rsquo;s Note of the first Bengali edition)&#xA;The best introduction to the author of this book is given by the work itself. Pujyapada Parivrajakacarya Tridandiswami Srimad Bhakti Raksaka Sridhara Maharaja is the fit recipient of the grace bestowed upon him by that great Universal Guru who shines like the sun among the Gaudiya Acaryas: Om Visnupada Sri Srimad Bhakti Siddhanta Saraswati Goswami Prabhupada. Srila Prabhupada, now left this world&#xA;to join the eternal divine pastimes, is the Divine Agent to flood the world with the nectarine universal preaching of the glory of the Supreme Lord, in the Divine Succession of Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu. Although the devotional community is well-acquainted with the illustrious personality of His Holiness B.R. Sridhara Maharaja, I may nonetheless take the opportunity to enumerate some of his glories herein for my self- purification.&#xA;The brilliance of his unprecedented scholarship is found in the artful compilation and harmony of Sri Prapanna-jivanamrtam, Life Nectar of the Surrendered Souls, accurately drawn from the axiomatic teachings of pure devotion (bhakti-siddhanta-vani) as evolved by the Vaisnava preceptors in the line of the bona fide Scriptures. We have already seen the extraordinary competence of His Holiness in preaching the beautiful, illuminating conceptions of the kings of transcendental scholars - the Vaisnava Preceptors headed by Sri Rupa, Sri Sanatana, and Sri Jiva - in various languages throughout the whole of India. Upon reading the first Sanskrit poem composed by His Holiness, Sri Bhaktivinoda Viraha Dasakam, our Divine Master commented that the writing was of a happy style. Srila Prabhupada profusely praised the devotional gravity of the presentation, revealing his deep satisfaction and joyful confidence that in times to come the message of Sri Caitanyadeva would be befittingly upheld and preached by the author. Just prior to his entrance into his eternal pastimes, Srila Prabhupada, in preference to hearing devotional prayer (kirtana) performed by devotees recognized for expertise, called for His Holiness&amp;rsquo; pure rendering of Sri Rupa-manjari pada, sei mora sampada, the worshipful prayer of the Gaudiya Vaisnavas&amp;rsquo; most cherished ideal.&#xA;The theme of Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls is described in the introductory first chapter, Prelude to Approaching Nectar. In some instances throughout the work, the Bengali verse interpretation of the venerated pure devotees has been fittingly given for the translation of the authentic stanzas quoted. In Words of Nectar from the Devotees, statements of the Supreme Lord have occasionally been quoted in conformation with the development of the theme. In his explanatory aphorisms that precede each stanza, the author reveals the unique&#xA;axiomatic truths (siddhanta) of his Divine Succession. Doubtlessly, the good readers who know the supereminence of the Gaudiya- siddhanta - the axiomatic devotional teachings in the line of Sri Caitanya&#xA;Mahaprabhu - will be overjoyed with His Holiness&amp;rsquo; novel illuminations. In the epilogue, the author has mentioned his line of Divine Succession and the time and place of the writing of the book.&#xA;It has been vividly illustrated herein that a life without surrender unto the lotus feet of Sri Krsna is utterly futile, and the most treasured perfection achieved through exclusive surrender has been revealed. This will especially encourage those who are aspiring to enter the land of devotion, drawing them onward to the lotus feet of Sri Hari. And it will infuse spiritual joy and exhilaration in the hearts of the established devotees. This book is the supreme wealth of the surrendered souls. Devotion for the Supreme Lord, Sri Hari-bhakti, is the singular quintessence in this world, and only by exclusive surrender, saranagati, is it happily attained. May this Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls graciously appear all the world over, distributing the ever-increasing aspiration to reach the abode of divine ecstasy - the lotus feet of Sri Hari. Just as the repeated rubbing of sandalwood produces more and more charming fragrance, we remain confident that the faithful devotees, whose only pleasure is in conclusive theological truth (sat-siddhanta), will experience the ambrosial devotional fragrance of this holy treatise in their spiritual discussions, and thus relish transcendental delight. We shall consider ourselves blessed when this book inevitably comes to be treasured by the august assembly of the fortunate souls.&#xA;a Vaisnava&amp;rsquo;s servant&amp;rsquo;s servant, Sri Nrsimhananda Brahmacari&#xA;on the holy anniversary of Srila Bhakti Siddhanta Prabhupada&amp;rsquo;s departure,&#xA;Gaurabda 457 (14th January, 1944) at Sri Dhama Navadvipa&#xA;All glory to the Divine Master and the Supreme Lord Sri Krsna Caitanya&#xA;Publisher&amp;rsquo;s Note&#xA;Sri Sri Prapanna-jivanamrtam, The Life-nectar of the Surrendered Souls, is the crown-jewel of divine literatures as the eternal elixir of life for the exclusively surrendered souls, the bestower of the perpetual relish of full-fledged nectar, and the awakening and sustaining fountainhead of life in Divine Consorthood. Indeed, who can fittingly portray her holy glory and renown? In the same way we cannot but feel ever inadequate when we attempt to sing the glories of the illustrious author, our most worshipful Divine Master, Om Visnupada Sri Srila Bhakti Raksaka Sridhara Deva Goswami Maharaja, the dearmost intimate attendant of the great pioneer pre-eminent among the Gaudiya Acaryas, Sri Gauranga&amp;rsquo;s transcendental message incarnate - Prabhupada Sri Srila Bhakti Siddhanta Saraswati Goswami Thakura. Even without world itineracy, the seat of Universal Guru (Jagad-guru) of the world&amp;rsquo;s renowned gurus has been gracefully won by Srila Sridhara Deva Goswami Maharaja while presiding in the grand, noble distinction of his venerable years of devotional life at the Sri Chaitanya Saraswat Math of Nabadwip, his exclusive, personal holy place of bhajana.&#xA;Since its first printing, which was in Bengali, this sublime literature has brought heartfelt satisfaction to the stalwart devotees of the highest order, being hailed by them as an Essential Scripture to be unfailingly sung and cultivated as a daily devotional function in spiritual life, as is customarily practiced with the Holy Scriptures such as the Srimad Bhagavad-gita. In both the Eastern and Western countries, its English publication will doubtlessly be similarly worshiped with the utmost reverence, constantly studied and sung with devotion by the surrendered souls of fine theistic intellect, and by the noble souls engaged in their divine search for the Supreme Lord.&#xA;This monumental work was originally composed in the Sanskrit language. The authentic Bengali translation that was sanctioned by the author is extremely developed, profoundly exploring the heart of the book; scholars who know the internal conclusive scriptural purports can&#xA;alone realize how difficult is its translation and publication into English. However, by the boundless mercy of the most magnanimous Supreme Lord Sri Caitanyacandra, the fountainhead of all incarnations of Godhead, and by the causeless grace of His most beloved, our Divine Master, and the pure devotees whose hearts are absorbed in divine love - this formidable task has now been fulfilled. Thus, I again and again worship the holy lotus feet of Them all.&#xA;For their tireless efforts to usher in the Advent of the present edition in its perfectly elegant form, all those Godbrothers and Godsisters who served in the various facets of the publication have attained the unending graces of our Divine Master and the Vaisnavas. They have bound us in eternal gratitude. For executing the task of the English translation, proofing, and editing, special mention is due to Tridandiswami Sripada Bhakti Ananda Sagara Maharaja, assisted by Sriman Nimaisundara Brahmacari Vidyavinoda. And for their dedicated effort in securing the necessary funds and assistance for the printing and publishing of the work in a most dignified presentation, special mention is due to Sripada Dayadhara Gauranga Dasa Brahmacari Bhakti Prabhakara Prabhu and all the good devotees assisting him.&#xA;In conclusion, invoking the charming verse of Sri Gurupadapadma this humble servant earnestly prays at his holy lotus feet that this crownjewel of Sacred Writings, Sri Sri Prapanna-jivanamrtam, may remain with Her merciful presence in every land, in every home, and in every heart. And in Her gracious acquiescence, may She acknowledge the glorious victory of Her goodwill by churning and overflooding the entire living universe with Her supramundane wave of ecstatic love, to bless all souls with the supreme good fortune.&#xA;sri-srimad-bhagavat-padambuja-madhu-svadotsavaih sat-padair niksipta madhu-bindavas ca parito bhrasta mukhat gunjitaih yatnaih kincid ihahrtam nija-parasreyo &amp;lsquo;rthina tan maya bhuyobhuya ito rajamsi pada-samlagnani tesam bhaje&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The bees, intoxicated in the festival of drinking the honey of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s lotus feet, busily humming the glories of the Lord, drops of honey&#xA;from their mouths fall and scatter all around; for my divine prospect, I&amp;rsquo;ve carefully collected some of those drops herein - and thus do I worship the dust of the holy lotus feet of those saints, again and again.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;I beg to remain most humbly,&#xA;Tridandi-bhiksu Sri Bhakti Sundara Govinda&#xA;16 October, 1987&#xA;93rd Holy Appearance Day of&#xA;His Divine Grace Srila Bhakti Raksaka Sridhara Deva Goswami&#xA;Maharaja&#xA;This Divine Book was prepared and presented to the Lotus Hands of the Venerable Author by his disciples and aspiring servitors on the&#xA;celebrated appearance day of Lord Gauracandra, Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu, March 3, 1988&#xA;All glory to the Divine Master and the Supreme Lord Sri Krsna Caitanya&#xA;Foreword&#xA;Because the soul is a particle of consciousness, it is endowed with free will. Eliminating free will, only gross matter remains. Without independence, the soul could not progress from bondage to liberation, and his ultimate salvation would have been impossible. But his spirit of exploitation is a foreign force, an intoxicant - a miscalculation that surrounds his independence.&#xA;Life&amp;rsquo;s objectives may be scientifically analyzed as threefold: exploitation, renunciation, and dedication. The most common tendency is in those engaged in exploiting other persons, species, or elements, for mundane sense enjoyment. They desire to materially elevate themselves in the present environment, and thus they are described as elevationists. A more sober class discover the severe equal and opposite reactions to worldly pursuits, and they engage in renunciation of the world, in search&#xA;of an equilibrium comparable to a deep, dreamless slumber. By being unawake to the world, they hope to escape its concomitant reactions and sufferings. Thus their goal is liberation, and they are known as salvationists or liberationists. But through the correct interpretation of the Revealed Scriptures by learned votaries such as Sri Sanatana Goswami, Sri Jiva Goswami, and Sri Ramanuja, the devotees of divinity know the pursuits of both exploitation and renunciation as not only fruitless, but injurious to real progress.&#xA;The normal, wholesome, and happy plane is in the life of dedication. Without exploiting or borrowing anything from the environment, and without attempting to artificially renounce it, one who is sincere to dedicate himself naturally comes into contact with a higher and more subtle plane of life. By his readiness to give and serve, he will attain to a higher society and achieve an appropriate master. The enjoying spirit forces one to be associated with a lower section to control and enjoy. And the renouncing spirit allures even the scholars with its &amp;lsquo;prestigious&amp;rsquo; superiority over exploitation. Thus it is more dangerous, just as a half-truth is more dangerous than falsehood. As it is difficult to awaken someone from the deepest possible sleep, the liberationists may remain for incalculable time within their cell of non-differentiated liberation. But the higher existence will invite the service of one who desires to purely dedicate himself without remuneration.&#xA;Seva - service, dedication, is the summum bonum of the teachings of the Vaisnava school, the third plane of life where every unit is a dedicating member in an organic whole. In such a normal adjustment, everyone mutually assists one another in their service to the center, the higher recipient, the highest entity. Everything is existing to satisfy Him, because He must possess this qualification to be the Absolute. He is the prime cause of all causes - and everything exists for Him, to satisfy Him.&#xA;A barren conception of mere &amp;lsquo;deathlessness&amp;rsquo; cannot afford us any knowledge of a positive thing, but only freedom from the negative side. If immortality means &amp;rsquo;no influence of mortality,&amp;rsquo; what, then, is its positive conception? What will be the nature, movement, and progress of that which is immortal? Without this understanding immortality is only an abstract idea. Because it does not appear to exhibit the symptoms of&#xA;death, stone would be &amp;lsquo;more immortal&amp;rsquo; than human beings, and conscious entities would be &amp;lsquo;mortal,&amp;rsquo; forever denied immortality! What, then, is the positive conception of immortality? How are the immortal &amp;lsquo;immortal&amp;rsquo;? What is the positive reality in immortality? How can one become immortal? One must search out his intrinsic location in the universal order. It will not do to attempt to solve only the negative side of life which is full of suffering - birth, death, infirmity, and disease. We should know that there exists a conception of life worth living for. This positive side has been almost totally neglected in general religious views.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;persons-who-do-not-take-shelter-of-the-one-without-a-second-the-supreme-lord-simply-loiter-in-the-world-of-birth-and-death&#34;&gt;The &amp;lsquo;immortality&amp;rsquo; professed by the schools of Buddha and Sankaracarya yields no positive life. Their goals are maha-nirvana and brahma-sayujya respectively. The Buddhist theory is that after liberation, nothing remains. They crave absolute extinction of material existence (prakrti-nirvana). And the Sankarite monist theory of liberation is to lose one&amp;rsquo;s individuality by &amp;lsquo;becoming one&amp;rsquo; with the non-differentiated aspect of the Absolute. That is, they crave extinction in Brahman (brahma- nirvana). They postulate that when the triad of seer, seen, and seeing (drasta-drsya-darsana), or knower, knowable, and knowledge (jnata- jneya-jnana) culminate at one point, the triad is destroyed (triputi- vinasa) and nothing remains.&#xA;Material action and reaction ceases in Viraja, the river of passivity, which is located at the uppermost edge of this illusory (mayika) world. And above Viraja is the destination of the Sankarites - the &amp;lsquo;abscissa&amp;rsquo; stage or the non-differentiated plane of Brahman, called Brahmaloka, which is located at the lowest edge of the spiritual realm. Both are vague areas of ,negative immortality.&amp;rsquo; Brahmaloka is a marginal or &amp;lsquo;buffer&amp;rsquo; state midway between the material and spiritual worlds. Composed of innumerable souls, it is an immortal plane devoid of specific variegatedness (nirvisesa). It possesses positivity only in the sense that it is a plane of existence, a background (kastha), but in itself it lacks positive development of variegated existence (kala). The nature of the background is oneness, and development woven over it necessitates plurality or a differentiated nature (kala-kasthadi rupena parinama- pradayini - Candi, Markandeya Purana).&#xA;In the Bhagavad-gita (15.16), mutable (ksara) and immutable&#xA;(aksara) existences are described, representing the personal and the impersonal, the development and the basis, or differentiated and non- differentiated conceptions of general existence. The mutable is represented by the multitude of embodied living beings, while the immutable aspect is the great expanse of the all-accommodating Absolute, the Brahman (8.3). In the analysis of worldly action, the most subtle form of unfructified past action, prior to the present tendency (the seedling stage) to sin, has been defined (Bhakti-rasamrita-sindhu, Purva 1.23) as unknowable, indistinct, and of untraceable origin (kuta). The immutable Brahman aspect of the Absolute is similarly defined as being one-dimensional - undetectable, unspecific, and of no definite color, sound, or taste; an unknown and unknowable &amp;lsquo;un-understandable&amp;rsquo; stage of existence (kuta). But the Supreme Lord, Krsna, is above both the mutable and immutable existences, and thus His glories are sung throughout the Vedas and in the world as the Purusottama, the Supreme Personality (Bhagavad-gita, 15.18). Sri Sukadeva Goswami affirms that in the most remote and distant plane, Lord Krsna is to be found: everywhere is He - the fountainhead of all conceptions (vidura-kasthaya, Bhagavatam, 2.4.14). He cannot be eliminated.&#xA;Thus, the &amp;lsquo;immortality&amp;rsquo; of the impersonalistic schools such as Buddhists, Sankarites, etc., offers no positive life. But in Vaisnavism, immortality is positive, dynamic existence. Above the non-differentiated Brahman aspect of the Absolute, the transcendental, variegated existence begins in the first glimpse of the spiritual sky, the plane known as Paravyoma (Chaitanya-charitamrita, Madhya 19.153). Situated there in the spiritual plane is the positive Kingdom of God: firstly Vaikuntha, then Ayodhya, Dvaraka, Mathura, and finally, above all, Goloka. Transcending the vague areas of &amp;rsquo;negative immortality&amp;rsquo; that the impersonalists aspire for, the devotees - the Vaisnavas - dedicate themselves to the life of eternal devotional service to the Supreme Lord of the transcendental realm (Bhagavad-gita, 18.54). Although the soul can maladopt himself to a fallen state of existence in the planes of exploitation and renunciation, he is inherently adoptable to the positive life in the Kingdom of God. And fully blossomed, he reaches the realm of Goloka (svarupe sabara haya golokete sthiti - Sri Sri Krsnera&#xA;Astottara-sata-nama).&#xA;Sri Prapanna-jivanamrtam: amrta means &amp;lsquo;undying,&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;nectar,&amp;rsquo; and jivana means &amp;rsquo;life.&amp;rsquo; Positive immortality is possible only for the surrendered (prapannanam). All others are necessarily mortal. Only those who have wholly given themselves to the center are living in eternality. Surrender is fully established in its excellence and its constant position. Yet there is variegatedness within that constancy, in the form of progressive movement, or pastimes (vilasa). The Supreme Absolute Personality being infinitely superior to both the mutable &amp;ldquo;mortals&amp;rsquo; and the immutable &amp;ldquo;immortal&amp;rsquo; (negative) Brahman, only the svarupa-siddha souls - those who are perfectly established in their divine relationship with Him - are eternally freed from the disease of mutation and mortality ( svarupena-vyavasthitih Bhagavatam, 2. 10.6).&#xA;With a broad vision, we must know ourselves as created of smaller stuff, and thus only with assistance from above can we improve our situation and achieve a position in the higher plane. A submissive, serving attitude is necessary in us. If we submit, the universal dictatorial aspect of the Absolute will take us upward to a higher prospect. He is the autocrat, the absolute knowledge, the absolute good - everything about Him is absolute. Being in a vulnerable position as we experience in this world, why, then, should we not submit to Him?&#xA;The road to the sphere of transcendence (adhoksaja) is the deductive or descending method (avaroha-pantha). We can reach the absolute good, the absolute will, by His consent alone. Only by faith in absolute surrender is anyone allowed entry into that domain, never by ,exploration,&amp;rsquo; by,colonization,&amp;rsquo; or by attempting to become a,monarch&amp;rsquo; there. No inductive or ascending method (aroha-pantha) such as renunciation or yoga, etc., can compel Him to accept us. Whosoever He chooses can alone reach Him (Svetasvataropanisad, 6.23). Although the highest point of the renunciates is desirelessness or freedom from possessiveness, the surrendered soul (saranagata) is naturally desireless ( akincana, Chaitanya-charitamrita, Madhya 22.99). Detachment is only the negative side of surrender, and above selflessness, the devotee surrenders himself to the higher substance, and this is to be awake in another world, another plane of life. Such is the positive, Vaisnavaconception of life - to determine one&amp;rsquo;s real self beyond the jurisdiction of the world of misconception.&#xA;The nature of the progressive substance is eternal existence, knowledge, and beauty (sac-cid-ananda). The one harmonizing organic whole (advaya-jnana-tattva) contains all similarities and differences, held inconceivably in the hand of the Absolute (acintya-bhedabheda- tattva). And there is no anarchy in the absolute power. Nonetheless, mercy is found to be above justice. Above judiciousness, the supreme position is held by love, sympathy, and beauty: &amp;lsquo;I am the absolute power, but I am friendly to you all. Knowing this, you need never fear (Bhagavad-gita, 5.29).&amp;rsquo; This revelation relieves us of all apprehension: we are not victims of a chaotic environment, but it is judicious, considerate - and the ultimate dispenser is our friend.&#xA;Sri Jiva Goswami has stated that of the six symptoms of surrender, to embrace the guardianship of the Lord (goptrtve varanam) is central, since total surrender expresses the same ideal. The remaining five symptoms of accepting the favorable, rejecting the unfavorable, faith in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s protection, full self-surrender, and humility, are natural contributing associate-servitors to the ideal (angangi-bhedena sad-vidha; tatra &amp;lsquo;goptrtve varanam&amp;rsquo; evangi, saranagati-sabdenaikarthyat; anyani tv angani tat parikaratvat - Bhakti-sandarbha, 236).&#xA;Surrender is the foundation of the world of devotion. It is the very life and essence. One cannot enter into that domain without surrender. It must be present in every form of service, and to attempt divine service without it will be mere imitation or a lifeless formality. The entire gist of the Vedic instruction is to dedicate oneself to the service of the Lord. In his commentary of Srimad-Bhagavatam, Sri Sridhara Swamipada has stated that only if the practices of devotion are initially offered to the Supreme Lord can they be recognized as devotion. To attempt to execute them and subsequently offer them cannot be pure devotion (iti nava laksanani yasyah sa, adhitena ced bhagavati visnau bhaktih kriyate, sa carpitaiva sati yadi kriyeta, na tu krta sati pascad arpyeta) Without surrender, the activity will be adulterated with exploitation, renunciation, artificial meditation (karma, jnana,yoga), and so on.&#xA;By constitution, the soul is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s servant, and the Lord has the&#xA;right to make or mar, to do anything according to His sweet will. If accepting this truth we undertake the devotional practices such as hearing, chanting, remembering, and worshipping, only then will our activity be devotional. Only the activity of the self-dedicated soul can be devotion. Sincere prayer will help us to seek the help of the Lord, but, again, prayer in the spirit of surrender can alone reach Him (Saranagati, 1.5). The path of devotion entails increasing our negative status to invite the positive to descend and embrace us: &amp;lsquo;I am very low, and You are so high. You can purify me, take me and utilize me for Your higher purpose. Be pleased. Otherwise I am helpless, neglected.&amp;rsquo; It is impossible to take Him captive in the cage of our knowledge. Only the way of devotion can help us. In every respect He is high, great, and infinite - and we are similarly small. His mercy - His sympathy, love, and grace, are the only medium through which we can come together. And good faith is autonomous in that sweet land which is so high that we will earnestly hope and pray for the association of the higher existence as His slave; and that also will be our happy prospect for the future.&#xA;Krsna is not within our purview, and thus we are always recommended by Scriptures and saints to approach the bona fide Divine Master and Vaisnavas. To satisfy the Supreme Lord, the criterion is to satisfy our Gurudeva: if Gurudeva is dissatisfied with us, the Lord is surely dissatisfied. An analogy has been cited in the Scriptures where the Lord is compared to the sun, the Guru to a pond, and the disciple to a lotus flower. If the pond withdraws, the very sun will scorch and dry up the lotus - and the lotus will be cheered by the sun as long as the water supports and surrounds it. Yasya prasadad bhagavat prasado, yasyaprasadan na gatih kuto &amp;lsquo;pi, dhyayam stavams tasya yasas tri- sandhyam, vande guroh sri-caranaravindam (Gurvastakam, 8): &amp;lsquo;I bow down to the lotus feet of Sri Gurudeva. By his grace we achieve the grace of Krsna; without his grace, we are lost. Therefore, at daybreak, noon, and evening, we meditate upon and sing the glories of Sri Gurudeva, and pray for his mercy.&amp;rsquo;&#xA;The Vaisnava Guru&amp;rsquo;s dealings with the disciple are all grace, and his grace is his will to extend his wealth to the disciple. His instruction is the medium of asserting his will, which is service for the satisfaction of the&#xA;Lord. And by service, we invite his grace. By an earnest desire to serve, we draw his sympathy and his willing extension of goodwill to encourage us in our relationship with the supreme entity. Firstly, surrender: we must offer him exclusive respect (pranipata), otherwise we shall not allow ourselves to approach him. Secondly, we may make our sincere and substantial inquiry (pariprasna). In a surrendered spirit, we may hear our Divine Master&amp;rsquo;s messages which he delivers to us from his venerated seat, the Vyasasana. In that conducive setting, the proper inspiration and dictation may fortuitously come down to us. And finally, to render service (sevaya) enables us to taste the essence (Bhagavad-gita, 4.34).&#xA;On the instruction of his Gurudeva Devarsi Narada, Vyasadeva had to undergo a progressive development (Bhagavatam, 1.5). Narada is established in non-calculative devotion (jnana-sunya-bhakti, or jnana- vimukta-bhakti-paramah ), and above Narada is Uddhava, who is established in exclusive divine love for Krsna (premaika-nisthah). Until one reaches Goloka, where there is full-fledged Krsna conception, all other stages may be changeable. There is no further change when one is firmly established in his serving relationship with the Original Lord (svayam-bhagavan), Krsna. In the narrative of Brhad-Bhagavatamrtam, Gopakumara passes through Vaikuntha, Ayodhya, Mathura, Dvaraka, and then he finally arrives in Vrndavana. There, his particular divine relationship with the Lord firmly culminates in friendship (sakhya-rasa). For him, the previous stages were passing, although for others a permanent relationship may occur in one of them. They are progressive stages of,positive immortality.&amp;rsquo;&#xA;On the banks of the Godavari river, in progressively deeper and deeper planes, the entirety of theological development was expressed in the conversation between Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu and Sri Ramananda Raya. A positive hierarchy of divine relationships with the Lord exists in progressive stages for the various types of devotees ( karmibhyah &amp;hellip; kah krti, Upadesamritam, 10), each type having its characteristic central relationship (vaikunthaj &amp;hellip; viveki na kah, Upadesamritam, 9). In the divine realm, the depth and degree of surrender may also be measured according to the science of mellows (rasa-tattva): peacefulness,&#xA;servitorship, friendship, parenthood, and consorthood (santa-, dasya-, sakhya-, vatsalya-and madhura-rasa) are the natural divisions, each consecutively of a finer layer. And higher than even the direct consorthood of the Godhead is the most elevated of the entire compass of devotional services - the divine service of the Supreme Predominated Moiety (Sri Radha-dasya).&#xA;According to the intensity of surrender - to the point of no return - the quality of the magnitude of truth encountered may be measured. The inner sweetness of the truth and its infinite characteristic attracts the devotees&amp;rsquo; hearts to the highest degree, so much that they never feel any satisfaction of achievement in what is actually the acme of their highest fortune. In Vaikuntha, only peacefulness and servitorship are present, with a hint of friendship. If we commit the offense of giving more attention to law than to love, we will be &amp;lsquo;cast down&amp;rsquo; from Goloka to Vaikuntha: Goloka is the land of love, and there the inhabitants know nothing more. And by love is meant self-sacrifice and self-forgetfulness for the service of Krsna, without a care for one&amp;rsquo;s good or bad future - total risk in the extreme.&#xA;In his Bhakti-sandarbha, Sri Jiva Goswami defines &amp;lsquo;Bhagavan,&amp;rsquo; the Supreme Personality of Godhead, as more than &amp;lsquo;Lord Narayana of Vaikuntha, the most powerful in all phases.&amp;rsquo; Above that, His existence, appearance, and nature attracts everyone to serve Him, love Him, and die for Him (bhajaniya-guna-visista). His qualification is so beautiful. Thus, the highest conception of the Godhead is the Krsna conception, and He can be known by the devotees in Krsna consciousness. Those who serve and worship the Supreme Lord according to the scriptural regulation and calculation belong to the category of Vaikuntha worship. In Vaikuntha, in the initial transcendental conscious conception (adhoksaja), the Godhead as Lord Narayana accepts reverential service in His Majestic Dignity. But the devotees of the highest order are exclusively surrendered to the&#xA;service of Lord Krsna with their innermost love and faith.&#xA;The Krsna conception of Goloka Vrndavana is corroborated in the Srimad Bhagavatam, which is the greatest interpretation of the Vedic Scriptures. And Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu is known to be Krsna Himself,&#xA;united with His highest potency, Sri Radha. Mahaprabhu Sri Caitanyadeva has clearly revealed that the genuine interpretation and purpose of all the Revealed Scriptures is to faithfully guide us to the highest goal: the domain of love and unconditional surrender unto the central power of truth, personified in Lord Krsna as beauty and affection. Not power, but affection is the highest force to attract us all. Consciously or unconsciously, the absolute position is held by love and affection, and love is superior to all power and knowledge. It is the real fulfillment of the inner heart. Our inner existence wants only love, beauty, and affection - neither knowledge nor power. The finite cannot capture the infinite, but the infinite can make Himself known to the finite. And when the infinite appears as a member of the finite land, the highest gain of the finite is achieved. Krsna carries His father&amp;rsquo;s shoes, and He cries when chastised by His mother. Through love, the Absolute comes down to the finite.&#xA;The infinite&amp;rsquo;s most intimate approach to the finite is found in Vrndavana. The infinite comes to embrace the finite in its fullest capacity (aprakrta), mixing with finite things so closely that people cannot perceive the Lord&amp;rsquo;s transcendental Godly character as the Divinity. We, the infinitesimal souls, can attain our greatest fortune when the infinite comes to us in His highest approach - as if He were one of us! His approach is so merciful, so great, so intimate, and so perfect.&#xA;Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu, who is sweetness and magnanimity combined, openly announced that we are all natural slaves of the highest entity (Chaitanya-charitamrita, Madhya 20.108). But this is slavery to the great force of love and beauty. It is the greatest fortune to be utilized in any way by the absolute existence, knowledge, and beauty - to be in harmony with the highest center. No one is forced or barred but this is the soul&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic nature.&#xA;Faithfully in the Divine Succession from Nitya-lila-pravista Om Visnupada Paramahamsa Astottara-sata Sri Srimad Bhakti Siddhanta Saraswati Goswami Prabhupada, especially inspired by the divine message of Srila Thakura Bhaktivinoda&amp;rsquo;s Saranagati, and attending the authentic Gaudiya Vaisnava literatures such as Sri Hari-bhakti-vilasa and Bhakti-sandarbha as well as the writings of other Authorized Divine&#xA;Successions such as the Ramanuja Sampradaya - this Sri Sri Prapanna- jivanamrtam has been compiled in order to supply the devotees&amp;rsquo; spiritual sustenance and nourishment. Surrender is the indispensable necessity in the life of a devotee, and Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls will sustain and fortify the surrendered souls as the nectar in their lives of Positive and Progressive Immortality.&#xA;1.1&#xA;Chapter 1&#xA;Upakramamrtam - Prelude to Approaching Nectar&#xA;atha mangalacaranam -&#xA;sri-guru-gaura-gandharva-, govindanghrin ganaih saha vande prasadato yesam, sarvarambhah subhankarah&#xA;Auspicious invocation -&#xA;I make my obeisance unto the lotus feet of my Divine Master, Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu, Sri Sri Gandharva-Giridhari (Sri Sri Radha and Krsna), and Their associates. By Their grace, all endeavors are successful.&#xA;1.2&#xA;gaura-vag-vigraham vande, gaurangam gaura-vaibhavam gaura-sankirtanonmattam, gaura-karunya-sundaram&#xA;I make my obeisance unto the Deity, Gaura-Saraswati - the personified message of the Golden Lord Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu - whose bodily luster is of a beautiful golden hue, like that of the selfsame Lord Gaurasundara; who is the personal expansion of that Supreme Lord Gaurahari; who is always intoxicated by preaching the message of that Golden Lord; and whose divine beauty blooms in the revelation of Lord Gauranga&amp;rsquo;s mercy potency. (This is the fundamental meaning of the verse. Within the scope of the Sanskrit&#xA;language, various expanded purports may be drawn from the original.)&#xA;1.3&#xA;guru-rupa-harim gauram, radha-ruci-rucavrtam nityam naumi navadvipe, nama-kirtana-nartanaih&#xA;Perpetually do I sing the glories of Lord Gauranga, who is the Supreme Personality of Godhead, Sri Hari, embraced by the heart and halo of Sri Radhika, and who has descended as the Divine Master. In this holy abode of Sri Navadvipa Dhama, He is absorbed in the pastimes of profusely chanting the holy names, dancing in ecstasy. (As with verse two, expanded purports may be drawn from this verse.)&#xA;1.4&#xA;srimat-prabhu-padambhoja-, madhupebhyo namo namah trpyantu krpaya te &amp;rsquo;tra, prapanna-jivanamrte&#xA;Again and again I make my obeisance unto the eternal personal servitors of my Divine Master, who drink the nectar of his lotus feet. I pray they may be graciously pleased in tasting this Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls.&#xA;1.5&#xA;atma-vijnaptih -&#xA;aty-arvacina-rupo &amp;lsquo;pi, pracinanam susammatan slokan katipayan atra, caharami satam mude&#xA;A humble petition - Despite my disqualifications, for the satisfaction of the pure devotees I have compiled in this book an anthology of stanzas that are well established by our predecessors.&#xA;1.6&#xA;tad-vag-visargo janatagha-viplavo yasmin prati-slokam abaddhavaty api&#xA;namany anantasya yaso &amp;rsquo;nkitani yat srnvanti gayanti grnanti sadhavah&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Even if every stanza is imperfectly composed, that is, unlucidly expressed, the sins of the people are totally vanquished by those expressions or books in which the glorious holy names of the Infinite Supreme Lord are described - since the pure devotees hear those holy names (from a qualified preacher), they solitarily sing those holy names (even in the absence of others), and they chant the unending glories of those holy names (in the presence of a deserving listener).&amp;rdquo;&#xA;1.7&#xA;abhivyakta mattah prakrti-laghu-rupad api budha vidhatri siddharthan hari-gunamayi vah krtir iyam pulindenapy agnih kim u samidham unmathya janito hiranya-sreninam apaharati nantah kalusatam&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O learned personalities, this treatise, composed of the divine qualities of Lord Hari, will fulfill your cherished wishes despite the fact that it is presented by me, a very insignificant person. Does not the fire ignited from pieces of wood rubbed together by a low-born barbarian dissipate the impurities in gold?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;1.8&#xA;yathokta rupa-padena, nicenotpadite &amp;rsquo;nale&#xA;hemnah suddhis tathaivatra, viraharti-hrtih satam&#xA;As Srila Rupa Goswamipada has (in his humility) expressed that gold can be purified with fire lit by a barbarian, similarly, the pure devotees&amp;rsquo; grief born of their separation from the Lord may also be dispelled by this book (which will light the lamp of their divine love for the Lord).&#xA;1.9&#xA;antah kovi-yasas-kamam, sadhutavaranam bahih sudhyantu sadhavah sarve, duscikitsyam imam janam&#xA;O saintly devotees, please purify this wrongdoer who on the pretext of saintliness desires in his heart the prestige of a poet, and who is thus afflicted with the practically incurable disease of insincerity.&#xA;1.10&#xA;krsna-gatha-priya bhakta, bhakta-gatha-priyo harih kathancid ubhayor atra, prasangas tat prasidatam&#xA;Tidings of Lord Krsna are naturally very dear to the devotees, and tidings of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s devotees are also dear to Him. Since narratives of both the Supreme Lord and His devotees can be found within this book, I have hope, O pure devotees, that you may be propitiated hereby.&#xA;1.11&#xA;svabhava-krpaya santo, mad uddesya-malinatam&#xA;samsodhyang ikurudhvam bho, hy ahaituka krpabdhayah&#xA;O pure devotees, by your natural divine grace, kindly purify me of ill motives (offenses) and accept this treatise. Certainly you will do so, because you are the ocean of causeless mercy.&#xA;1.12-14&#xA;atha grantha-paricayah -&#xA;granthe &amp;lsquo;smin parame nama, prapanna-jivanamrte dasadhyaye prapannanam, jivana-prana-dayakam varddhakam posakam nityam, hrdindriya-rasayanam atimartya-rasollasa-, paraspara-sukhavaham viraha-milanarthaptam, krsna-karsna-kathamrtam prapatti-visayam vakyam, coddhrtam sastra-sammatam&#xA;Introduction to the book -&#xA;The substance expressed within the ten chapters of this holy book called Prapanna-jivanamrtam gives life to the surrendered souls, effecting their eternal growth and nourishment. It is the panacea of the heart and spiritual senses, bestowing those dedicated devotees&amp;rsquo; mutual happiness by the ever-increasingly newer and newer play of supramundane joy (aprakrta-rasa). Lord Krsna and His associates are portrayed in their natural pastimes of separation and union, and the line of unconditional surrender as established by Scriptures and saints has been elucidated.&#xA;1.15-22&#xA;atra cananya-cittanam, krsna-pada-rajojusam krsna-pada-prapannanam, krsnarthe &amp;lsquo;khila-karmanam krsna-premaika-lubdhanam, krsnocchistaika jivinam krsna-sukhaika-vanchanam, krsna-kinkara-sevinam krsna-viccheda-dagdhanam, krsna-sangollasadd-hrdam krsna-svajana-bandhunam, krsnaika-dayitatmanam bhaktanam hrdayodghati-, marma-gathamrtena ca bhaktarti-hara-bhaktasa-, bhista-purtikaram tatha sarva-samsaya-cchedi-hrd-, granthi-bhij jnana-bhasitam apurva-rasa-sambhara-, camatkarita-cittakam viraha-vyadhi-santapta-, bhakta-citta-mahausadham yuktayuktam parityajya, bhaktarthakhila-cestitam atma-pradana-paryanta-, pratijnantah-pratisrutam bhakta-premaika-vasya-sva-, svarupollasa-ghositam purnasvasakaram saksat, govinda-vacanamrtam samahrtam pibantu bhoh, sadhavah suddha-darsanah&#xA;Carefully compiled in this book is the nectar of the deep,&#xA;heartrevealing transcendental messages of those devotees whose hearts are unalloyed; who are servitors of the dust of the lotus feet of Krsna; who perform their every act for Krsna; who are filled with insatiable desire exclusively in love of Krsna and sustain their lives on Krsna&amp;rsquo;s remnants alone; who desire only Krsna&amp;rsquo;s pleasure andserve the servants of Krsna; whose hearts burn in separation of Krsna and overflow with ecstasy in the association of Krsna; whose relative and friend is Krsna; and whose one and only beloved is Krsna.&#xA;Along with these expressions of the devotees are carefully collected the words of supreme nectar - springing directly from the lotus mouth of Lord Govinda - which vanquish the heartbreak of the devotees; which fulfill the devotee&amp;rsquo;s hopes and earnest aspirations; which destroy all doubt and sever the knot of ignorance; which are dazzling with transcendental wisdom and astonish the heart by miraculous waves of divine rapture, which are the great panacea for the devotee&amp;rsquo;s heart afflicted with the piercing pangs of separation; which are incited wholly for the devotee irrespective of his qualification or disqualification, so much so, that the Lord is bound by His pledge to give Himself to His devotee; and which openly proclaim with great ecstasy that His very nature is to be subjugated solely by the affection of His devotee, reassuring His devotees in all circumstances.&#xA;O pure and spotless devotees, may you drink deeply the quintessence of these divine elixirs.&#xA;1.23&#xA;adhyaya-paricayah -&#xA;atraiva prathamadhyaye, upakramamrtabhidhe mangalacaranan catma-, vijnaptir vastu-nirnayah grantha-paricayo &amp;lsquo;dhyaya-, visayas ca nivesitah&#xA;Chapter summary -&#xA;An auspicious invocation, a humble petition, an introduction to the book and its chapters, and the theme of the philosophy of the book have, to the best of my ability, all been entered within this first chapter named Upakramamrtam or Prelude to Approaching Nectar.&#xA;1.24&#xA;dvitiyadhyayake nama, sri-sastra-vacanamrte&#xA;prapatti-visaya nana-, sastroktih sannivesita&#xA;In the second chapter, entitled Sri Sastra-vacanamrtam, The Nectar of Scriptural Word, various scriptural quotations regarding surrender to the Supreme Lord have been compiled.&#xA;1.25&#xA;trtiyato &amp;lsquo;stamam yavat, sri-bhakta-vacanamrte&#xA;prapattih sad-vidha prokta, bhagavata-ganodita&#xA;Chapters three to eight inclusive are entitled Sri Bhakta- vacanamrtam, Words of Nectar from the Devotees. Beautifully expressed by the lotus lips of the pure devotees of the Lord, many stanzas describing the six limbs of exclusive surrender are quoted therein.&#xA;1.26-27&#xA;anakulyasya sankalpah, pratikulya-vivarjanam raksisyatiti visvaso, goptrtve varanam tatha atma-niksepa karpanye, sad-vidha saranagatih evam paryayatas casminn, ekaikadhyaya-sangrahah&#xA;These six chapters have been compiled, each consecutively dealing with the six limbs of surrender, which are as follows: 1. To accept everything favorable for devotion to Krsna 2. To reject everything unfavorable for devotion to Krsna 3. To be confident that Krsna will grant His protection 4. To embrace Krsna&amp;rsquo;s guardianship&#xA;5. To offer oneself unto Him&#xA;6. To consider oneself lowly and bereft&#xA;1.28&#xA;adhyaye navame nama, bhagavad-vacanamrte slokamrtam samahrtam, saksad-bhagavatoditam&#xA;In the ninth chapter entitled Sri Bhagavad-vacanamrtam, Words of Nectar from the Supreme Lord, nectarean stanzas emanating directly from the lotus mouth of the Supreme Lord have been compiled.&#xA;1.29&#xA;dasame caramadhyaye, cavasesamrtabhidhe&#xA;guru-krsna-smrtau grantha-, syopasamharanam krtam&#xA;Absorbed in thought of the Divine Master and Lord Sri Krsna, the tenth and final chapter entitled Sri Avasesamrtam, The Divine Remnants of Nectar, was composed as the epilogue of the book.&#xA;1.30&#xA;uddhrta-sloka-purve tu, tad artha-suprakasakam&#xA;vakyan ca yatnatas tatra, yatha-jnanam nivesitam&#xA;Prior to each stanza quoted, an aphorism illuminating its inner purport has been carefully entered according to my best insight.&#xA;1.31&#xA;bhagavad-gauracandranam, vadanendu-sudhatmika bhaktoktair vesita sloka, bhakta-bhavodita yatah&#xA;Being revealed by the Lord Himself adopting the heart of a devotee, the stanzas of pure nectar emanating from the moon of Sri Gauracandra have been entered along with the stanzas of the devotees.&#xA;1.32&#xA;prapattya saha cananya-, bhakter naikatya-hetutah ananya-bhakti-sambandham, bahu-vakyam ihoddhrtam&#xA;Many expressions of exclusive devotion (ananya-bhakti) have been recorded herein, since exclusive devotion is most intimately&#xA;related to surrender.&#xA;1.33&#xA;bhagavad-bhakta-sastranam, sambandho &amp;lsquo;sti parasparam tat tat pradhanyato namnam, prabbeda-karanam smrtam&#xA;Actually, Words of Nectar from the Supreme Lord, Words of Nectar from the Devotees, and The Nectar of Scriptural Word are all seen to be interrelated. Still, they have been portrayed separately due to their individual importance.&#xA;1.34&#xA;praty-adhyaya-visesas tu, tatra tatraiva vaksyate mahajana-vicarasya, kincid alocyate &amp;lsquo;dhuna&#xA;The unique characteristic of each chapter will be accordingly expressed therein. Now (in this respect), we may have some general deliberation, in the line of the great devotees of the Lord.&#xA;1.35&#xA;vastu-nirnayah -&#xA;bhagavad-bhaktitah sarvam, ity utsrjya vidher api kainkaryam krsna-padaika-, srayatvam saranagatih&#xA;Theme of the work -&#xA;Being governed by the faith that all success is achieved by serving the Supreme Lord, to abandon servitude to even scriptural injunctions and take exclusive refuge in the lotus feet of Sri Krsna in every time, place, and circumstance, is known as saranagati - unconditional surrender.&#xA;1.36&#xA;sarvantaryamitam drstva, hareh sambandhato &amp;lsquo;khile&#xA;aprthag-bhava-tad-drstih, prapattir jnana-bhaktitah&#xA;Some consider saranagati to be that God consciousness which is realization of the one non-differentiated nature in all beings and objects, by seeing the Supreme Lord as the indwelling Supersoul of everything. However, such a conception falls within the category of calculative devotion (jnana-bhakti). It is not in the line of unadulterated pure devotion (suddha-bhakti).&#xA;1.37&#xA;nityatvan caiva sastresu, prapatter jnayate budhaih aprapannasya nr-janma-, vaiphalyoktes tu nityata&#xA;By scriptural reference, the learned know of the eternality of surrender to the Lord, since the futility of human life without that surrender is elucidated therein. In this way, the eternal constitution of surrender is established.&#xA;1.38&#xA;nanyad icchanti tat pada-, rajah-prapanna-vaisnavah&#xA;kincid apiti tat tasyah, sadhyatvam ucyate budhaih&#xA;Because the devotees who have surrendered unto the dust of the lotus feet of the Lord never aspire for anything else whatsoever, the learned affirm that surrender is the attainable goal of all endeavors.&#xA;1.39&#xA;bhava-duhkha-vinasas ca, para-nistara-yogyata&#xA;param padam prapattyaiva, krsna-sampraptir eva ca&#xA;Only by surrender to the Lord can one gain freedom from the miseries of birth, death, disease, and infirmity; fitness to deliver others from those miseries; the holy abode of Lord Visnu; and the devotional service of Lord Krsna.&#xA;1.40&#xA;sravana-kirtanadinam, bhakty-anganam hi yajane&#xA;aksamasyapi sarvaptih, prapattyaiva harav iti&#xA;Everything is accomplished by surrendering unto the lotus feet of Sri Hari, even for one who is unable to execute the integral practices of devotional service based on hearing and chanting.&#xA;1.41&#xA;sakhya-rasasrita-praya, seti kecit vadanti tu&#xA;madhuryadau prapannanam, praveso nasti ceti na&#xA;Some claim that surrender is generally in the relationship of friendship (sakhya-rasa). But it is complete fallacy to think that surrendered souls have no entrance into divine relationships headed by consorthood (madhura-rasa).&#xA;1.42&#xA;sakrt pravrtti-matrena, prapattih sidhyatiti yat lobhotpadana-hetos tad, alocana-prayojanam&#xA;Since surrender is achieved by turning to the refuge of the Lord just once, we should earnestly discuss the subject to enable the longing for surrender to be born in us.&#xA;1.43&#xA;api tad anakulyadi-, sankalpady-anga-laksanat tad anusilaniyatvam, ucyate hi mahajanaih&#xA;Furthermore, since the constituent parts of surrender - based on acceptance of the favorable and rejection of the unfavorable - have been referred to by authorities and cited in the Scriptures, the great devotees of the Lord teach us the necessity of studying and culturing the art of surrender.&#xA;1.44&#xA;bhavarti-pidyamano va, bhakti-matrabhilasy api&#xA;vaimukhya-badhyamano &amp;rsquo;nya-, gatis tac charanam vrajet&#xA;One who is severely afflicted by fear of living in the material world, or, one who, despite having an aspiration for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s service is nonetheless bound with adversity - such persons, finding no alternative, surrender to the Supreme Personality of Godhead.&#xA;1.45&#xA;asrayantara-rahitye, vanyasraya-visarjane ananya-gati-bhedas tu, dvi-vidhah parikirtitah&#xA;The state of finding no other alternative occurs in two ways: in the event of having no other shelter, or in the event of abandoning one&amp;rsquo;s existing shelter.&#xA;1.46&#xA;mano-vak-kaya-bhedac ca, tri-vidha saranagatih&#xA;tasam sarvanga-sampanna, sighram purna-phala-prada nyunadhikyena caitasam, taratamyam phale &amp;lsquo;pi ca&#xA;One surrenders by thought, word, and deed. Complete surrender in all these aspects promptly affords full success. Otherwise, the fruit attained will be proportionate to the degree of one&amp;rsquo;s surrender.&#xA;1.47&#xA;apurva-phalatvam -&#xA;vinasya sarva-duhkhani, nija-madhurya-varsanam karoti bhagavan bhakte, saranagata-palakah&#xA;The unprecedented, gracious reward of surrender -&#xA;Being most affectionate toward His surrendered souls, the Supreme Lord totally dispels their unhappiness, graciously filling their hearts with His sweet absolute presence.&#xA;1.48&#xA;apy asiddham tadiyatvam, vine ca saranagatim&#xA;ity apurva-phalatvam hi, tasyah samsanti panditah&#xA;Without unconditional surrender (saranagati), one cannot conceive of oneself as &amp;lsquo;belonging to Him.&amp;rsquo; And this is why the learned sing (par excellence) the glories of surrender&amp;rsquo;s ability to yield her unprecedented, gracious fruit.&#xA;1.49&#xA;athava bahubbir etair, uktibhih kim prayojanam sarva-siddhir bhaved eva, govinda-caranasrayat&#xA;Otherwise, what would have been the need for so abundantly singing her praises? Only by unconditional surrender unto the lotus feet of Govinda is all perfection attained - nothing remains to be attained.&#xA;1.50&#xA;sri-sanatana-jivadi-, mahajana-samahrtam.&#xA;api cen nica-samsprstam, piyusam piyatam budhah&#xA;Even though touched by one as lowly as me, please, O learned devotees, drink this nectar gathered by the great souls headed by Srila Sanatana and Sri Jiva.&#xA;iti sri-prapanna-jivanamrte upakramamrtam nama prathamo &amp;lsquo;dhyayah&#xA;thus ends the first chapter Prelude to Approaching Nectar&#xA;in&#xA;Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls Positive and Progressive Immortality&#xA;2.1&#xA;Chapter 2&#xA;Sri Sastra-vacanamrtam The Nectar of Scriptural Word&#xA;sruti-smrty-adi-sastresu, prapattir yan nirupyate&#xA;tad uktam dvitiyadhyaye, sri-sastra-vacanamrte&#xA;This second chapter, Sri Sastra-vacanamrtam, The Nectar of Scriptural Word, describes surrender as corroborated in the Revealed Scriptures headed by the Vedas (Sruti) and the Religious Codes (Smrti).&#xA;2.2&#xA;prapattih srutau -&#xA;yo brahmanam vidadhati-purvam yo brahma-vidyam tasmai gah palayati sma krsnah tam hi devam atma-vrtti-prakasam mumuksur vai saranam amum vrajet&#xA;Tapanyam (Brahma-Samhita, tika)&#xA;Surrender is firmly established by the Vedas -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;In the beginning of creation, He who created the universal creator, Brahma, and then imparted to Brahma knowledge of Brahman, the Absolute - He is the selfsame Lord Krsna who tends the cows (or nourishes the Vedas [gah means both &amp;lsquo;cows&amp;rsquo; and Vedas]). Those desirous of liberation should surrender unto that Lord, who reveals the innate function of the soul.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.3-4&#xA;tadatmya-yatharthyam smrtau&#xA;ahankrtir ma-karah syan, na-karas tan nisedhakah tasmat tu namasa ksetri-, svatantryam pratisidhyate bhagavat-paratantro &amp;lsquo;sau, tad ayattatma-jivanah tasmat sva-samarthya-vidhim, tyajet sarvam asesatah&#xA;Padma-uttara-khanda&#xA;The cause of the tangible reality of surrender is expounded in the Standard Codes of Religion (Smrti) -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The syllable ma means &amp;lsquo;self-asserting ego&amp;rsquo; (the misconception of considering oneself to be a &amp;lsquo;doer&amp;rsquo;), and the syllable na indicates its prevention. Thus, the act of offering obeisances (namah) nullifies the offerer&amp;rsquo;s independence. The soul is naturally subordinate to the Almighty, his intrinsic nature and innate function being servitude to the Supreme Lord. Therefore, all actions performed thinking, &amp;lsquo;I am the doer,&amp;rsquo; should be utterly abandoned.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.5&#xA;ahankarad-aprapattih -&#xA;ahankara-nivrttanam, kesavo nahi duragah ahankara-yutanam hi, madhye parvata-rasayah&#xA;Brahma-vaivartta Purana&#xA;The only obstacle to surrender is self-asserting ego -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Supreme Lord Kesava remains in the company of persons who are free from a mundane conception of life; but there appears to be a great mountain range between the self-asserting egotists and the Lord.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.6&#xA;advaya-jnanam anasritanam eva jagad-darsanam - yavat prthaktvam idam atmana indriyartha-&#xA;maya-balam bhagavato jana isa pasyet tavan na samsrtir asau pratisankrameta&#xA;vyarthapi duhkha-nivaham vahati kriyarthaBhagavatam, 3.9.9&#xA;Persons who do not take shelter of the One without a second, the Supreme Lord, simply loiter in the world of birth and death&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harer-eva-sarvoddharitvam-&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;O Lord, Soul of all souls, the conditioned soul sees this universe as separate from You, and thinks it is meant for his sense enjoyment. But this is only a creation of Your deluding potency (maya). As long as the living being clings to such an illusory separate interest, he does not give up the miserable world of action and reaction, birth and death, despite its utter meaninglessness.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.7&#xA;tan nityatvam, tad abhave atmano vancitatvat - prapyapi durllabhataram,.manusyam vibudhepsitam yair asrito na govindas, tair atma vancitas ciram&#xA;Brahma-vaivartta Purana&#xA;The unsurrendered soul is perpetually deceived; thus, the state of surrender is eternal -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;A birth in the human species is so valuable that it is aspired for by the demigods. Those who, despite having taken such a birth, do not take shelter of the lotus feet of Govinda - they deceive themselves perpetually.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.8-9&#xA;aprapannanam jivana-vaiphalyac ca -&#xA;asitin caturas caiva, laksams tan jiva-jatisu&#xA;bhramyadbhih purusaih prapya, manusyam janma-paryayat tad apy aphalatam yatam, tesam atmabhimaninam&#xA;varakanam anasritya, govinda-carana-dvayam&#xA;Brahma-vaivartta Purana&#xA;The utter futility of life without surrender -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;After wandering throughout 8,400,000 species, the soul&#xA;eventually takes a human birth. But that human birth is rendered worthless by those miserable fellows who are so proud of their bodies that they refuse to take shelter of the lotus feet of Lord Govinda.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.10&#xA;sarvadhamesv api mukti-datrtvam -&#xA;sarvacara-vivarjitah satha-dhiyo vratya jagad-vancaka dambhahankrti-pana-paisuna-parah papantyaja nisthurah ye canye dhana-dara-putra-niratah sarvadhamas te &amp;lsquo;pi hi sri-govinda-padaravinda-sarana mukta bhavanti dvija&#xA;Even the lowest of men are liberated by surrender -&#xA;Nrsimha Purana&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O twice-born, persons who are devoid of all virtuous practices, who are outcast, rogues, deceitful, audacious, egotistic, addicted to intoxicants, hotbeds of sin, malicious, cruel-natured, grossly infatuated with son, wife, wealth, etc. - even such extremely fallen persons are liberated by surrendering unto the lotus feet of Sri Govinda.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.11&#xA;tan nisthasya nadho-gatih -&#xA;paramartham asesasya, jagatam adi karanam saranyam saranam yato, govindam navasidati&#xA;Brhan-Naradiya Purana&#xA;A surrendered soul never falls down -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Sri Govinda is the origin of all the universes, the Supreme Truth, and the shelter of all. One who surrenders unto His lotus feet can never be cast asunder.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.12-13&#xA;duhkha-haratvam mano-haratvan ca -&#xA;sthitah priya-hite nityam, ya eva purusarsabhah&#xA;rajams tava yadu-srestho, vaikunthah purusottamah ya enam samsrayantiha, bhaktya narayanam harim te tarantiha durgani, na me &amp;rsquo;trasti vicarana&#xA;Mahabharata, Santi-parva&#xA;Surrender unto the Supreme Lord Hari vanquishes misery and charms the heart with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s divine sweetness -&#xA;O King, what more can I say? The foremost of the Yadu dynasty, the unassailable great personality who is full of goodwill for you and always your dear friend - He is none other than the Supreme Lord Narayana, Sri Hari. Those who devotedly take full refuge in Him cross over this insurmountable ocean of material existence.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.14&#xA;abhayamrta-datrtvan ca -&#xA;ye sankha-cakrabja-karam hi sarnginam khagendra-ketum varadam sriyah patim samasrayante bhava-bhiti-nasanam tesam bhayam nasti vimukti-bhajam&#xA;Completely vanquishing all fear, surrender bestows the life of eternal nectar -&#xA;Vamana&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Lord of the Goddess of Fortune bears a conchshell, disc, lotus flower, and bow; He is the Master of Garuda, He is the vanquisher of the fear of mundane existence, He is the bestower of all benedictions. No trace of apprehension remains for those who take refuge in Him, since they qualify for positive immortality.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.15&#xA;sarvartha-sadhakatvam&#xA;samsare &amp;lsquo;smin maha-ghore, moha-nidra-samakule&#xA;ye harim saranam yanti, te krtartha na samsayah&#xA;Brhan-Naradiya Purana&#xA;A surrendered soul is successful in all endeavors -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;In the dense darkness of this material world which is engulfed in ignorance and sleep, those who surrender unto the holy lotus feet of Lord Hari are successful in all their endeavors. Of this there is no doubt.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.16&#xA;ajitendriyanam api siva-datvam -&#xA;kim durapadanam tesam, pumsam uddama-cetasam yair asritas tirtha-padas, carano vyasanatyayah&#xA;Bhagavatam, 3.23.42&#xA;By surrender, even persons of uncontrolled senses attain all good fortune -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The lotus feet of Lord Hari vanquish material existence. By surrendering unto His lotus feet, nothing remains difficult to achieve, even for a person of agitated mind.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.17&#xA;samsara-klesa-haritvam -&#xA;sarira manasa divya, vaiyase ye ca manusah&#xA;bhautikas ca katham klesa, badheran hari-samsrayam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 3.22.37&#xA;All worldly suffering is vanquished for the surrendered soul -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O Vidura, how can a person who has taken shelter of the lotus feet of Sri Hari be stricken with bodily and mental tribulation arising from the elements, other persons, or unfavorable astrological circumstances?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.18&#xA;saranagatanam ayatna-siddham eva param padam - samasrita ye pada-pallava-plavam&#xA;mahat-padam punya-yaso murareh bhavambudhir vatsa-padam param padam&#xA;padam padam yad vipadam na tesam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 10.14.53&#xA;The Supreme Abode of Lord Visnu is effortlessly attainable for the surrendered souls -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;This ocean of material existence is as insignificant as the water in a cow&amp;rsquo;s hoofprint to those persons who have taken full refuge in the supreme shelter - the boat of the lotus feet of Lord Sri Krsna, whose glories are universally sung as purity&amp;rsquo;s own self. Their destination is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s supreme abode, never this mundane abode of calamities.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.19&#xA;sarvatmasritanam vivarta nivrttih -&#xA;yesam sa eva bhagavan dayayed anantah sarvatmanasrita-pado yadi nirvyalikam te dustaram atitaranti ca deva-mayam naisam mamaham iti dhih sva-srgala-bhaksye&#xA;Bhagavatam, 2.7.42&#xA;The illusion of bodily identification and mundane possessiveness is dispelled for the souls surrendered to the Lord in all respects -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Due to their taking shelter of His lotus feet in all respects, those persons upon whom the Infinite Supreme Lord bestows His unreserved grace surpass the insurmountable illusory energy of the Lord. He does not favor those who ascribe the conceptions of &amp;lsquo;I and mine&amp;rsquo; to this material body, which is food for jackals and hounds.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.20&#xA;tad upeksitanam duhkha-pratikarah ksanika eva - balasya neha saranam pitarau nrsimha nartasya cagadam udanvati majjato nauh taptasya tat-pratividhir ya ihanjasestas&#xA;tavad vibho tanu-bhrtam tvad-upeksitanam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 7.9.19&#xA;For persons devoid of a relationship with the Supreme Lord Hari, prevention of suffering cannot but be transitory -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O Nrsimha, O Almighty Lord, precautions and remedies are only short-lived when attempted by the suffering embodied souls who are not favored by You. Parents are not the guardians of their child, medicine is not the cure for the diseased, and a boat is not the savior of a man drowning in the ocean.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.21&#xA;anasritanam asad avagrahad eva vividharttih - tavad bhayam dravina-deha-suhrn-nimittam sokah sprha paribhavo vipulas ca lobhah tavan mamety asad-avagraha arti-mulam yavan na te &amp;rsquo;nghrim abhayam pravrnita lokah&#xA;Bhagavatam, 3.9.6&#xA;The various tribulations of the unsurrendered souls are simply due to their obsession with the unreal -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O Lord, as long as the people of the world do not take the safe and sound shelter of Your lotus feet, they remain full of anxiety about their wealth, their bodies, and their friends; overwhelmed with lamentation, hankering, obsession, and intense greed, they cannot obtain relief from the suffering which is deeply rooted in their imaginary conceptions of I and mine.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.22&#xA;paripurna-kamo harir evasrayaniyo &amp;rsquo;nyad-heyam - avismitam tam paripurna-kamam, svenaiva labhena samam&#xA;prasantam&#xA;vinopasarpaty aparam hi balisah, sva-langulenatititartti sindhum&#xA;Bhagavatam, 6.9.22&#xA;One should take refuge in the fully self-satisfied Supreme Lord Hari; the shelter of &amp;lsquo;other gods&amp;rsquo; yields a lamentably inferior result -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Lord Krsna is perfectly replete in everything desirable, fully self-sufficient, poised and tranquil. Nothing can be astonishing for Him. Only a fool disregards Him to take shelter in any demigod whose propitiation may be prescribed for the accomplishment of worldly benefits. Such a person may be compared to one who seizes a dog&amp;rsquo;s tail in order to cross the ocean.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.23&#xA;harer eva sarvoddharitvam ·&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-the-sri-krsna-sankirtana-be-all-victorious-in-its-pristine-glory-this-congregational-chanting-of-the-holy-names-of-the-lord-cleanses-the-looking-glass-of-consciousness-extinguishes-the-raging-forest-fire-of-material-existence-and-spreads-the-benediction-moonrays-that-cause-the-lotus-of-the-heart-to-bloom-this-chanting-is-the-life-and-soul-of-divine-consorthood-expanding-the-ocean-of-pure-ecstasy-it-is-the-flavor-of-full-nectar-at-every-moment-bathing-and-cooling-the-entire-self&#34;&gt;kirata-hunandhra-pulinda-pulkasa abhira-sumbha yavanah khasadayah ye &amp;rsquo;nye ca papa yad-upasrayasrayah sudhyanti tasmai prabhavisnave namah&#xA;Bhagavatam, 2.4.18&#xA;Only Sri Hari is capable of delivering the living being in all circumstances -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Persons such as those belonging to the races known as Kirata, Huna, Andhra, Pulinda, Pulkasa, Abhira, Sumbha (Kanka), Yavana, and Khasa - nay, persons of each and every sinful birth are perfectly purified without a doubt, by taking shelter of the devotees surrendered to Lord Visnu, the Almighty. I do offer my respectful obeisances unto Him.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.24&#xA;hari-caranasrita eva sara-grahino &amp;rsquo;nyatha karma-yogadibhir atma- ghatitvam -&#xA;athata ananda-dugham padambujam hamsah srayerann aravinda-locana sukham nu visvesvara yoga-karmabhis tan mayayami vihata na maninah&#xA;Bhagavatam, 11.29.3&#xA;Only surrendered souls can properly distinguish substance from form; those who disregard Lord Hari to seek happiness on the empirical paths based on yoga and karma are simply on a suicidal&#xA;course -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O lotus-eyed one, the swans (topmost pure devotees, paramahamsas) take refuge in Your ecstasy-yielding lotus feet. O Universal Lord, those who do not accept the joy of the shelter of Your lotus feet and pursue the paths of abstract liberation and mundane acquisition - such persons are devastated by Your deluding potency.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.25&#xA;krsna-carana-saranagateh parama-sadhyatvam -&#xA;na naka-prstham na ca sarva-bhaumam na paramesthyam na rasadhipatyam na yoga-siddhir apunar-bhavam va vanchanti yat pada-rajah prapannah&#xA;Bhagavatam, 10.16.37&#xA;Full refuge in the lotus feet of Sri Krsna is the supreme objective - &amp;ldquo;Those souls who have taken refuge in the dust of Your lotus feet have no desire to attain heaven, universal dominion, the post of Lord Brahma, sovereignty over the earth, yogic perfections, or liberation.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.26&#xA;hari-prapannanam anya-nistara-samarthyam-atmaramanam api hari- pada-prapattis ca -&#xA;yat pada-samsrayah suta, munayah prasamayanah sadyah punanty upasprstah, svardhuny-apo &amp;rsquo;nusevaya&#xA;Bhagavatam, 1.1.15&#xA;Souls surrendered unto the lotus feet of the Lord Hari are competent to deliver others, and the fully self-satisfied souls also surrender to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s lotus feet -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The slightest association with the supremely tranquil sages who have surrendered unto the lotus feet of the Lord purifies the people of the world; but the river Ganga purifies only those who bathe in it.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.27&#xA;sri-krsnaika-sarana naiva vidhi-kinkarah -&#xA;devarsi-bhutapta-nrnam pitrnam&#xA;na kinkaro nayam rni ca rajan sarvatmana yah saranam saranyam gato mukundam parihrtya karttam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 11.5.41&#xA;Those souls who have exclusively surrendered unto Krsna are not subservient to scriptural injunctions and prohibitions -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O King, one who abandons all worldly obligations and wholeheartedly surrenders unto Mukunda, the exclusive shelter of all beings in every respect - such a person is no longer indebted to the demigods, sages, other life-forms, friends and relatives, mankind, and ancestors.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.28&#xA;tad anugrhita veda-dharmatita eva -&#xA;yada yasyanugrhnati, bhagavan atma-bhavitah sa jahati matim loke, vede ca parinisthitam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 4.29.45&#xA;The recipients of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mercy are transcendental to Vedic religiosity -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Because of the intense love of His surrendered soul, the Supreme Lord bestows His grace upon that devotee by ushering divine inspiration into his heart. Such a devotee then abandons the preoccupation with adhering to worldly obligations and Vedic religiosity.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.29&#xA;sri-krsna-svarupam eva paramasraya-padam -&#xA;dasame dasamam laksyam, asritasraya-vigraham&#xA;sri-krsnakhyam param dhama, jagad-dhama namami tat&#xA;Bhavartha-dipika, Bhagavatam, 10.1.1&#xA;As the epitome of divine ecstasy (rasa), the Supreme Lord&amp;rsquo;s original form - Krsna - is the highest refuge -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;In the tenth canto of Srimad-Bhagavatam, Sri Krsna has been distinguished as the embodiment of shelter for the surrendered souls. I bow down unto that supreme refuge of the universe, who is known as, Krsna&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.30&#xA;sriman-mahaprabhoh padasraya-mahatmyam -&#xA;dhyeyam sada paribhava-ghnam abhista-doham tirthaspadam siva-virinci-nutam saranyam bhrtyarti-ham pranata-pala-bhavabdhi-potam vande maha-purusa te caranaravindam&#xA;Bhagavatam, 11.5.33&#xA;The matchless, unsurpassable gift of surrender unto the lotus feet of Lord Sri Caitanya Mahaprabhu, the Golden Avatara who enacts His pastimes as a great devotee -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O guardian of the surrendered, O great personality (the Supreme Personality of Godhead Himself, who enacts His divine pastimes as a pure devotee [maha-bhagavata]), You alone are the reality to be constantly meditated upon by the pure souls. You are the destroyer of the soul&amp;rsquo;s illusion, You are the divine wish-fulfilling tree, the refuge of all devotees. Worshippable by Siva and Virinci (Sadasiva in the form of Sri Advaita Acarya, and Brahma in the form of Haridasa Thakura), You are the shelter of all and everything, and You are the dispeller of Your devotee&amp;rsquo;s suffering which originates in offenses to the holy name (nama-aparadha). You are the only boat for crossing the ocean of this material world ofsuffering. I do worship Your holy lotus feet.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.31&#xA;sri-caitanya-carana-sarane cid-eka-rasa-vilasa-labhah -&#xA;samsara-sindhu-tarane hrdayam yadi syat&#xA;sankirtanamrta-rase ramate manas cet premambudhau viharane yodi citta-vrttis caitanya-candra-carane saranam prayatu&#xA;Caitanya-candramrta 8.93&#xA;The souls surrendered unto the lotus feet of Sri Caitanyadeva bathe in the ocean of divine love -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If you have a desire to cross the ocean of material existence, an aspiration to taste the ecstasy of the nectarean congregational chanting of the holy names (sankirtana), and a longing to sport in the ocean of divine love - then please surrender unto the lotus feet of Sri Caitanyacandra.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.32&#xA;sad-vidha-saranagatih -&#xA;anukulyasya-sankalpah, pratikulya-vivarjjanam raksisyatiti visvaso, goptrtve varanam tatha atma-niksepa-karpanye, sad-vidha saranagatih&#xA;Vaisnava-tantra&#xA;Six divisions of surrender -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Acceptance of the favorable, rejection of the unfavorable, the faith that &amp;lsquo;He will surely protect me,&amp;rsquo; embracing the Lord&amp;rsquo;s guardianship, complete dependence on Him, and the perception of one&amp;rsquo;s utter helplessness without Him - these six are the essential limbs of exclusive surrender to the Lord (saranagati).&amp;rdquo;&#xA;2.33&#xA;sa ca kaya-mano-vakyaih sadhya -&#xA;tavasmiti vadan vaca, tathaiva manasa vidan&#xA;tat sthanam asritas tanva, modate saranagatah&#xA;Vaisnava-tantra&#xA;Saranagati should be practiced in thought, word, and deed -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;By his power of speech, the surrendered soul declares, &amp;lsquo;I am Yours&amp;rsquo;; in his thoughts, he knows the same; and in person, he takes refuge in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s holy abode. In this way the surrendered soul passes his life, his heart filled with joy.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;iti sri-prapanna-jivanamrte&#xA;sri-sastra-vacanamrtam nama dvitiyo &amp;lsquo;dhyayah&#xA;thus ends the second chapter The Nectar of Scriptural Word&#xA;in&#xA;Life-Nectar of the Surrendered Souls Positive and Progressive Immortality&#xA;3.1&#xA;Chapter 3&#xA;Sri Bhakta-vacanamrtam - Words of Nectar from the Devotees Anakulyasya Sankalpah - Acceptance of the Favorable&#xA;krsna-karsnaga-sad-bhakti-, prapannatvanukulake krtyatva-niscayas-canu-, kulya-sankalpa ucyate&#xA;Everything should be done that encourages the service of Sri Krsna and His devotee, and whatever is conducive to the state of exclusive surrender must be executed: such a firm conviction is called anukulyasya-sankalpah - Acceptance of the Favorable.&#xA;3.2&#xA;sri-krsna-sankirtanam eva tat padasritanam paramanukulam -&#xA;ceto-darpana-marjanam bhava-mahadavagni-nirvapanam sreyah-kairava-candrika-vitaranam vidya-vadhujivanam anandambudhi-vardhanam prati-padam purnamrtasvadanam&#xA;sarvatma-snapanam param vijayate sri-krsna-sankirtanam&#xA;Sri Sri Bhagavatas Caitanyacandrasya&#xA;Of everything favorable, Hari-sankirtana performed by souls surrendered unto the lotus feet of Lord Hari is paramount -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;May the Sri Krsna Sankirtana be all-victorious in its pristine glory! This congregational chanting of the holy names of the Lord cleanses the looking-glass of consciousness, extinguishes the raging forest fire of material existence, and spreads the benediction moonrays that cause the lotus of the heart to bloom. This chanting is the life and soul of divine consorthood. Expanding the ocean of pure ecstasy, it is the flavor of full nectar at every moment, bathing and cooling the entire self.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the Supreme Lord Sri Caitanyacandra&#xA;3.3&#xA;tatra sampatti-catustayam paramanukulam - trnad api sunicena, taror api sahisnuna amanina manadena, kirtaniyah sada harih Sri Sri Bhagavatas Caitanyacandrasya&#xA;These four jewels are accepted as the greatest treasure favorable to the performance of Hari-kirtana -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;One who knows himself more insignificant than a blade of grass, who is as forbearing as a tree, and who gives due honor to others without desiring it for himself, is qualified to sing the glories of Lord Hari constantly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Supreme Lord Sri Caitanyacandra&#xA;3.4&#xA;karsnanam adhikaranurupa sevaiva bhajananukula -&#xA;krsneti yasya giri tam manasadriyeta diksasti cet pranatibhis ca bhajantam isam susrusaya bhajana-vijnam ananyam anya nindadi-sunya-hrdam ipsita-sanga-labdhya&#xA;Sri Rupapadanam&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
