<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Daily worship on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Daily worship on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/00_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/00_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Vaikhānasas are a group of South Indian Vişnuite Brahmans who are traditionally engaged in conducting worship in temples. Various temples in Tamilnad and Andhra Pradesh had (or have) their worship organized according to the Vaikhānasa method and with officiants belonging to the Vaikhanasa sect.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fact is noteworthy that the Vaikhanasa sect can trace its origin up to a period in which the Vedic religion of sacrifice still occupied the main position in Brāhmanic circles of India. Thus it is not surprising that the traditions of the sect show a great number of ancient (often, Vedic) elements, persistently preserved also in later periods when other ideas and cult methods had arisen. This is not to say, however, that the Vaikhanasas had not the bulk of their philosophy and ritual in common with other Vişnuite, and sometimes also Šivaite, circles.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Entering the temple</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/01_Entering_the_temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/01_Entering_the_temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;02-circumambulation&#34;&gt;02 CIRCUMAMBULATION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(pradakşiṇa).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A circumambulation of the temple is to be made by the priest before he enters. While doing thus, he should say the mantra &lt;em&gt;pra tad viṣṇuḥ॑ stavate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;All authorities agree about this mantra, but while A, BK and K say that it should accompany the circumambulation proper, BKh, BY and M ordain that it should be uttered while the priest goes towards the temple or enters the temple precincts (the last in BKh); after that, he should perform the circumambulation (according to BKh with* ato devā)*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Assistants&#39; duties (fetching water etc )</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/02_Assistants_duties_fetching_water_et/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/02_Assistants_duties_fetching_water_et/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-an-assistant-or-disciple-takes-a-pot&#34;&gt;11 AN ASSISTANT (OR DISCIPLE) TAKES A POT.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assistant (&lt;em&gt;paricaraka&lt;/em&gt;) is called &lt;em&gt;śişya &lt;em&gt;(disciple) by BY and K. He should have bathed himself (A, BY) and bowed to the Lord (BY). The mantra which he says while taking the pot is&lt;/em&gt; duhatam divam&lt;/em&gt;. VMP 8,13 &lt;em&gt;duhatam divam indras savitemam duhatám medinim / tad ubhayam prajānam niritaye nirudvegaya&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Indra must milk heaven, Savitar must milk this earth; both these acts are for freedom from calamities and freedom from disturbance for the creatures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Meditation (Brahmanyäsa)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/03_Meditation_Brahmanysa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/03_Meditation_Brahmanysa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before worship of the Universal Lord is possible, it is necessary that the human and the divine should be brought into contact with each other. To this end, the worshipper should leave the ordinary, human level of consciousness and enlarge it into cosmic size. He should become Visnu Himself (BY 20 &lt;em&gt;atmânam bhavayed dharim&lt;/em&gt;). Besides, the utensils are to be hallowed with divine names (see 48), so that the whole ritual will become a cosmic process, in which Vişnu Näräyaņa by His divine will power sets all other powers in motion. The other deities are His attendants, all fit to do their own duty. The worshipper as the Divinity Itself, is purified in the highest degree by this process of identifying himself with God as Brahman (Brahman is a purifier and stabilizer) and collects an enormous amount of power into himself. By steady performance of this ritual, the life-process on earth will go on steadily (and an interruption would have bad results, as the texts regularly warn; see e.g. K, ch. 1).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Bathing the image</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/04_Bathing_the_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/04_Bathing_the_image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the description given by the handbooks the movable image is bathed and cleaned now, before the Lord is invoked into it. This order is found also in the description of the Saiva ritual by Diehl. There *Lingaśuddhi *&amp;ldquo;cleaning the Linga&amp;rdquo; occurs as element 30 on p. 115, where it precedes the invocation of the God. K, ch. 73: this bathing (&lt;em&gt;abhiseka&lt;/em&gt;) is done in the morning only. The bath of the image during the *püja *(68), is done also at other times. In the ritual of bathing of the Vaikhanasas two remarkable tendencies are to be observed: (1) The ritual, which is not found described in V, grows more intricate. This is already seen in the &lt;em&gt;Bhrgu Samhita&lt;/em&gt;: both BK and BKh (remarkably enough, not BY) discuss the bathing ceremony more elaborately than the others. Yet these two do not agree at all with each other; the new elements they give tend to differ from each other and are found in different places. The elaboration is continued by VMP, BP and the monographs in a manner deviating from both BK and BKh. (2) In BP and the monographs the sequence of the ceremonies has been changed; the bathing there is done within the cadre of the *püja *only. Thus it comes after the invocation of Visņu and after the Lord has been worshipped already with some rites combined under the word &lt;em&gt;mantrasana&lt;/em&gt;. The bathing is in these texts, called *snanāsana *&amp;ldquo;bathing-seat&amp;rdquo;. This sequence is found also in Rangachari&amp;rsquo;s descrip- tion (The &lt;em&gt;Sri Vaisnava Brahmans&lt;/em&gt;, p. 148). In a sense this change is perfectly comprehensible. After the priest has made himself fit for worship by identifying himself with God, the thing to be expected now, in the first place, is that the worship will be inaugurated by His invocation. The question is if the modification in the order of the elements is due to a revision made by the Vaikhanasas of their own accord or under the influence of the Päñcarätrins or Śrī Vaisnavas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Some preparations; worship of Attendant Deities</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/05_Some_preparations_worship_of_Attenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/05_Some_preparations_worship_of_Attenda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The movable image is now prepared for receiving the presence of the Lord Himself, i.a. by connecting it with the immovable image. Around the images a great number of minor deities are thought to be present; these are all honoured with flowers. Worship is also directed to all the other deities residing in various parts of the temple. In KA and KAV (but not in the other monographs) the worship with flowers has been transferred to a later stage, during the worship of Viṣṇu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Invocation of Viṣṇu (Āvāhana)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/06_Invocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/06_Invocation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;48-preparation-of-the-vessels-and-other-materials&#34;&gt;48 PREPARATION OF THE VESSELS AND OTHER MATERIALS.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This subject is handled best by BKh. The vessels were already said to be cleaned in 19. They are called &amp;ldquo;conches&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;śaṅkha&lt;/em&gt;-) by some authorities (A, BK, BKh). There are four of them: one for the invocation (the *pranidhi *proper); it is placed to the right; one for water for Viṣṇu&amp;rsquo;s feet; one for water to sip (&lt;em&gt;ācamana&lt;/em&gt;), and one for bathing. The four vessels are placed successively to the north of each other. They are filled with water mixed with flowers, kuśa grass, grains, and perfumes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 RETROSPECT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/08_RETROSPECT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kriyA/goudriaan/daily-worship/08_RETROSPECT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In conclusion it seems desirable to make a few observations of a more general character about the method of worship described here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first conclusion may be that the temple worship described in the handbooks of Atri, Bhrgu, Kāśyapa and Marici is essentially based on the domestic worship found in the* Vaikhānasagṛhyasūtra*. There are many additions, and in some cases the order of the elements has been changed, but these are for the main part due to the more elaborate character of the worship in the temple and not to fundamental changes in outlook. In the worship proper, the &lt;em&gt;pūjā &lt;em&gt;directed to Vişņu (57ff.), the number of attendances has been increased to a total of thirty-two, but one is still able to recognize the original character of this pūjā: the invocation and reception of a divine guest and his entertainment. (For some further observations on the original character of the pūjā, one may be referred to Fausta Nowotny, in&lt;/em&gt; Indo-Iranian Journal&lt;/em&gt;, I, 1957, p. 110f.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
