<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Agamas SI-vaiShNavism on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Agamas SI-vaiShNavism on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 INTRODUCTORY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/01_INTRODUCTORY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/01_INTRODUCTORY/</guid>
      <description>The Vedas represent the earliest extant literature in the world They are four, under the names of Rgveda, Yajurveda, Samaveda and Atharvaveda They record many aspects of the life of the people of ancient India whose religious beliefs and aspirations left an indelible mark on their social life.
Indeed, the religions and social aspects became inextricably mixed up with each other But it must not be forgotten that the Vedas deal primarily with the religious beliefs and practices of ancient India</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 VALIDITY OF THE AGAMAS’</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/02_VALIDITY_OF_THE_AGAMAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/02_VALIDITY_OF_THE_AGAMAS/</guid>
      <description>The authenticity of the Agamas has been questioned from about the beginning of the Christian era. There was objection to their validity in a general way and also to that of particular kinds of Agamas The whole objection is based only on one point, namely, worship of God.
4
These who raise this objection, rest their arguments on the supposed non-Vedic character of the Agamas The word non-Vedic means that which is not Vedic, not based on what the Vedas stand for By Vedic the Vedas and the Vedāngas are meant These are concerned with the performance of the rituals enjoined in the Kalpasutras in accordance with the procedures recommended therein on the basis of the Brahmanas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 CLASSIFICATION OF AGAMAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/03_CLASSIFICATION_OF_AGAMAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/03_CLASSIFICATION_OF_AGAMAS/</guid>
      <description>The Agamas advocate the adoration of particular deitles to the exclusion of others who form part of the retinue of the principal deity. More than one deity enjoys the privilege of such prominence The Valspava, Sakta, Saiva, Ganapatya, Svayambhuva and Candra are most well known kinds glorifying particular deities. The Pasupata, Kālāmukha, Cina and Jaina are also held to be types of Ågamas, The Saura also is added to the list Of these, Pasupata and Kalamukha are to be brought under Saiva, and Cina and Jaina are of the nastika kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 VAIKHANASA AGAMA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/04_VAIKHANASA_AGAMA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/04_VAIKHANASA_AGAMA/</guid>
      <description>The Vaikhanasa Agama describes the method of worshipping Vişņu and prescribes the way of life for those who adopt the Vaikhānasa-sütra. This is based upon the Vedic sources and derives support, for the doctrines which it preaches, solely from Vedic texts The worship of Visnu in the area form is
stressed
.
The word, Vaikhānasa&amp;rsquo;, is very old, occurring in the early literature of Sanskrit It signifies the vanaprasthāṣrama which a student who had completed the study of the Vedas could take up even without getting married 259 The sage, Saubhari, who entered into the householder&amp;rsquo;s life to be happy with a family, though he used to practise meditation, renounced it and entered into the vanaprastha order and followed the way of life prescrib- ed in the Vaikhānasa mode and became a recluse 260 Here the word,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 THE PĀNCARĀTRA AGAMA:</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/05_THE_pAncharAtra_AGAMA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/05_THE_pAncharAtra_AGAMA/</guid>
      <description>Validity and Antiquity
The Pancarātra Agama, which is mainly concerned with the worship of God in temples and houses, treats also of philosophy, linguistic occultism (mantra) and the theory of mystical diagrams (yantra), It is based on the Ekāyana recension of the Sukle Tajurveda and so is Vedic in its foundations. Vedic mantras are frequently used. Yet it reveals a liberal and progressive out- look in throwing open its portals to all, irrespective of caste and sex, thus bringing within its fold even those who are excluded by tradition from the study of the Vedas Conse- quently, mantras are created for their use and also for others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 PĀNCARĀTRA AGAMA DOCTRINES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/06_pAncharAtra_AGAMA_DOCTRINES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/06_pAncharAtra_AGAMA_DOCTRINES/</guid>
      <description>The Pañcarātra system is called also as the Sattvataśāstra. There are other systems also having the name ‘Pāñcarātra&amp;rsquo; with some attributes, such as &amp;lsquo;Gaṇesapāñcarātra&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Devīpāñcară îrā&amp;rsquo; and others 586 There is also a system called &amp;lsquo;Saptarātra&amp;rsquo;
Vide.
favoaretai ofagıfą açû ada wyca # | ब्रह्मन् में । Àtarfa qxcıerfor eacrarfor à ¤ar i पञ्चरात्राणि सप्तरात्राणि
Agnipurāna XXXIX-1
Io all these cases the word &amp;lsquo;rätra&amp;rsquo; must be taken to stand for day and night (ahoratra) This indicates that the explanation for the name ‘Pāñcarātra&amp;rsquo; should be traced to sources other than that which is suggested by Prof Buitenen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 PĀNCARĀTRA TEXTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/07_pAncharAtra_TEXTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/07_pAncharAtra_TEXTS/</guid>
      <description>The Pancarätra doctrines ware preached by five teachers- Sandilya, Aupagayana, Mauñjyāyana, Kausika and Bharadvaja 751 The works of the first and the last, among these, are available, while that of the second gets only reference in some works 752 The other two left no works. The works of the two writers mentioned above, have more than one text with the same name. They treat matters like worship of God, bhakti and prapatti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 AGAMAS AND VAISNAVA LITERATURE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/08_AGAMAS_AND_VAISNAVA_LITERATURE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/08_AGAMAS_AND_VAISNAVA_LITERATURE/</guid>
      <description>The system of Visistadvalta represents the philosophical side of Vaisnavism. The term came to be used to refer to a system of philosophy which is based primarily on the Upaniṣads and was developed by a long line of writers like Bodhayans, Nathamuni, Yamunacarya and Ramanuja. Because of its tenets, It was referred to by expressions like vidıştadraoyaikya,914 dravyaikya and others. Sudarsana Sürl (1300 A.D) was the earliest writer to use the expression, &amp;lsquo;visíṣṭādvaita&amp;rsquo;, to refer to the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 AGAMAS AND TEMPLES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/09_AGAMAS_AND_TEMPLES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/09_AGAMAS_AND_TEMPLES/</guid>
      <description>The Agamas, as a whole, are based on the Vedas, and their concept of God is derived from them It is but natural that the Supreme Deity should be depicted as formless and beyond comprehension The finite Instruments of man and of his powers are totally inadequate to measure God and His powers 1159 God becomes an object of adoration, and so He is represented as an embodiment of lovable qualities and bliss, 1160 thus indicating the result of a development that is only of Agamic origin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 AGAMAS AND THE WAY OF LIFE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/10_AGAMAS_AND_THE_WAY_OF_LIFE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/10_AGAMAS_AND_THE_WAY_OF_LIFE/</guid>
      <description>Every society has codes of ethics helpful to its well-being. The standards of good conduct and moral behaviour enjoined by them vary from individual to Individual and from one stratum of society to another All such codes and standards among the Hindus derive from the Vedas
Moral goodness is a question of behaviour 1410 Everlasting happiness is the goal of good conduct The lawbooks (Smplis) and the conduct of those steeped in Vedic traditions are also authoritative 1411 Moral behaviour is alone held to contribute to Individual progress and social welfare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/11_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/11_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>To the preceding pages, the Vaisnavism of South India has been shown as being based on the Vedas, epics and other ancient works and as later developing under the Influence of the Puranas and Agamas. The variety of sources and influences makes it inevitable that the leading concepts like those relating to the avatara or the vyuha evolved a&amp;rsquo; different times in different ways There does not seem to be any uniformity in treating them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/12_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/12_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</guid>
      <description>Agama Texts: Abirbudhnya Samhita I &amp;amp; II, 1966 Adyar, Madras 2. Aniruddha Samhita Isvara Samhita, 4 Jayakbya Samhlia, G.O S., Baroda 1931 Jnanakanda of Kasyapa, T.T.D., Tirupati 1948 Khlladhikara, T T.D., Tirupati Kriyadhikara, T.T.D, Tirupati 1953 Laksmitantra with commentary, Adyar, Madras 1959 9. Laksmitantra English Translation Samyukta Gupta Leiden 1974 Padma Sambita I &amp;amp; II, Pancaratra Parlshodhana Parishad, Madras 1974, 1982 Parama Samhita, G.O.S. with English translation, Baroda 1940 Paramesvara Samhita, Srirangam 1953 Pauskara Samhita, Bangalore 1934 Prakiraadhikara, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 LIST OF ABBREVIATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/13_LIST_OF_ABBREVIATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/13_LIST_OF_ABBREVIATIONS/</guid>
      <description>ABr. Abs. AV. BBRAS. Bh. BbG. BrUp. Chand Up } Altareyabrahmana Ahlrbudhnyasamhita Atharva Veda Bombay Branch of Royal Asiatic Society- Journal of Bhagavatapurana Bhagavadgita Brhadaranyakopanisst Chandogyopanisat Commentary Gaekwad Oriental Series Isvarasambita Ch,U Com GOS IS JK Jnanakanda (of Kasyapa) JS KA Jayakhya Samhita Kriyadhikara LT Mbh Laksmitantra Mahabharata Ms Np Pars Manusmrti Nyayaparisuddhi Paramasamhita Pars Paramesvarasambita Pas Padmasambita Paus Pauskarasambita PR Pancaratra Raksa R Ramayana RTS Rahasyatrayasara RV SA SBr SpBr } Rgveda Samurtarcanadhikarana Satapatha brahmana524 Sks Sprs SR SS SV SVOI SY TA TBr AGAMAS AND SOUTH INDIAN VAISNAVISM Sanatkumarasamhita Sriprasnasamhita Saccaritraraksa Sattvatasambita Samaveda Sri Venkateswara Oriental Institute Sukla Yajurveda Taittiriyaranyaka Taittiriya Brahmana TS TU Talttirlya Samhita Taittiriyopanisat VK VP VS VIS Vimanarcanakalpa Visnupurana Visnusambita Visvamitrasamhita VISS YS Visvaksenasambita Yogasutra</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 GLOSSARY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/15_GLOSSARY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/15_GLOSSARY/</guid>
      <description>$45 aradhana: worship of God. * arani piece of wood for kindling fire. aratrika waving of light before the idol. arca : Idol for worship. areaka: priest officlating for offering worship to God in temple. arghya : water offered to the deity or guest as the first item of attendance. · arthavada glorificatory passage not to be taken literally. asana : posture: sitting posture of the Idol. avabrtha: ceremonial bath in the concluding session of a sacrifice performed on the last or ninth day of festival in the temples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 ERRATA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/16_ERRATA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/16_ERRATA/</guid>
      <description>Bagchi for Bagchi 435 VISS IS read J. N. Banerjee: development of Hindu iconography 198 4 &amp;amp; 6 AL TA 227 3 Abe AbS 231 1 delete JS 241 .L.27 kata kala 254 1 VIS VISS 308 ( Z 30 ogvapakarana bhogopakaiana 343 2 SVVORI SVWORI 346 18 X 72 XIII. 48 351 9 TS IS 13 ParS Pas 354 7 SKA SKS 360 4 ISS VISS 361 9 delete VS XII.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
