<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 rāmānuja&#39;s srībhāshya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 rāmānuja&#39;s srībhāshya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/02/</guid>
      <description>(Brahman is that) from which the origin, &amp;amp;c., of this (world proceed). The expression &amp;rsquo;the origin&amp;rsquo;, &amp;amp;c., means &amp;lsquo;creation, subsistence, and reabsorption&amp;rsquo;. The &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo; (in &amp;lsquo;of this&amp;rsquo;) denotes this entire world with its manifold wonderful arrangements, not to be fathomed by thought, and comprising within itself the aggregate of living souls from Brahmā down to blades of grass, all of which experience the fruits (of their former actions) in definite places and at definite times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/03/</guid>
      <description>Because Scripture is the source (of the knowledge of Brahman). Because Brahman, being raised above all contact with the senses, is not an object of perception and the other means of proof, but to be known through Scripture only; therefore the text &amp;lsquo;Whence these creatures are born,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., has to be accepted as instructing us regarding the true nature of Brahman.&amp;ndash;But, our opponent points out, Scripture cannot be the source of our knowledge of Brahman, because Brahman is to be known through other means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/04/</guid>
      <description>But that (i.e. the authoritativeness of Scripture with regard to Brahman) exists on account of the connexion (of Scripture with the highest aim of man). The word &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; is meant to rebut the objection raised. That, i.e. the authoritativeness of Scripture with regard to Brahman, is possible, on account of samanvaya, i.e. connexion with the highest aim of man&amp;ndash;that is to say because the scriptural texts are connected with, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/05/</guid>
      <description>On account of seeing (i.e. thinking) that which is not founded on Scripture (i.e. the Pradhāna) is not (what is taught by the texts referring to the origination of the world). We have maintained that what is taught by the texts relative to the origination of the world is Brahman, omniscient, and so on. The present Sūtra and the following Sūtras now add that those texts can in no way refer to the Pradhāna and similar entities which rest on Inference only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/06/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that (the word &amp;lsquo;seeing&amp;rsquo;) has a secondary (figurative) meaning; we deny this, on account of the word &amp;lsquo;Self&amp;rsquo; (being applied to the cause of the world). The contention that, because, in passages standing close by, the word &amp;lsquo;seeing&amp;rsquo; is used in a secondary sense, the &amp;lsquo;seeing&amp;rsquo; predicated of the Sat (&amp;lsquo;Being&amp;rsquo;) is also to be taken in a secondary sense, viz. as denoting (not real thought but) a certain condition previous to creation, cannot be upheld; for in other texts met with in the same section (viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/07/</guid>
      <description>The next following Sūtra confirms the same view.
Because release is taught of him who takes his stand on it. Svetaketu, who is desirous of final release, is at first&amp;ndash;by means of the clause &amp;lsquo;Thou art that&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;instructed to meditate on himself as having his Self in that which truly is; and thereupon the passage &amp;lsquo;for him there is delay&amp;rsquo; only as long as &amp;lsquo;I shall not be released, then I shall</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/08/</guid>
      <description>The Pradhāna is not the cause of the world for the following reason also:
And because there is no statement of its having to be set aside. If the word &amp;lsquo;Sat&amp;rsquo; denoted the Pradhāna as the cause of the world, we should expect the text to teach that the idea of having his Self in that &amp;lsquo;Sat&amp;rsquo; should be set aside by Śvetaketu as desirous of Release; for that idea would be contrary to Release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/09/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the contradiction of the initial statement. The Pradhāna&amp;rsquo;s being the cause of the world would imply a contradiction of the initial statement, viz. that through the knowledge of one thing all things are to be known. Now, on the principle of the non-difference of cause and effect, this initial statement can only be fulfilled in that way that
through the knowledge of the &amp;lsquo;Sat&amp;rsquo;, which is the cause, there is known the entire world, whether sentient or non-sentient, which constitutes the effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/10/</guid>
      <description>On account of (the individual soul) going to the Self. With reference to the &amp;lsquo;Sat&amp;rsquo; the text says, &amp;lsquo;Learn from me the true nature of sleep. When a man sleeps here, he becomes united with the Sat, he is gone to his own (Self). Therefore they say he sleeps (svapiti), because he is gone to his own (sva-apīta)&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up.VI, 8, 1). This text designates the soul in the state of deep sleep as having entered into, or being merged or reabsorbed in, the Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/11/</guid>
      <description>On account of the uniformity of view. &amp;lsquo;In the beginning the Self was all this; there was nothing else whatsoever thinking. He thought, shall I send forth worlds? He sent forth these worlds&amp;rsquo; (Ait. Ār. II, 4, 1, 1); &amp;lsquo;From that Self sprang ether, from ether air, from air fire, from fire water, from water earth&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 1); &amp;lsquo;From this great Being were breathed forth the R̥g-veda,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/12/</guid>
      <description>And because it is directly stated in Scripture. The text of the same Upanishad directly declares that the being denoted by the word &amp;lsquo;Sat&amp;rsquo; evolves, as the universal Self, names and forms; is all-knowing, all-powerful, all-embracing; is free from all evil, &amp;amp;c.; realises all its wishes and purposes. &amp;lsquo;Let me, entering those beings with this living; Self, evolve names and forms&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VI, 3, 2); &amp;lsquo;All these creatures have their root in the Sat, they dwell in the Sat, they rest in the Sat&amp;rsquo; (VI, 8, 4); &amp;lsquo;All this has that for its Self; it is the True, it is the Self (VI, 8, 7);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/13/</guid>
      <description>The Self consisting of Bliss (is the highest Self) on account of multiplication. We read in the text of the Taittirīyas, &amp;lsquo;Different from this Self, which consists of Understanding, is the other inner Self which consists of bliss&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 5).&amp;ndash;Here the doubt arises whether the Self consisting of bliss be the highest Self, which is different from the inner Self subject to bondage and release, and termed &amp;lsquo;jīva.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/14/</guid>
      <description>If, on account of its being a word denoting an effect, (ānandamaya be said) not (to denote the highest Self); (we say) no, on account of abundance. We deny the conclusion of the Pūrvapakshin, on the ground of there being abundance of bliss in the highest Brahman, and &amp;lsquo;abundance&amp;rsquo; being one of the possible meanings of -maya.&amp;ndash;Since bliss such as described in the Taitt. Up.&amp;ndash;bliss which is reached by successively multiplying by hundred all inferior kinds of bliss&amp;ndash;cannot belong to the individual soul, we conclude that it belongs to Brahman; and as Brahman cannot be an effect, and as -maya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/15/</guid>
      <description>And because he is declared to be the cause of thatra. &amp;lsquo;For who could breathe, who could breathe forth, if that bliss existed not in the ether? He alone causes bliss&amp;rsquo;
(Taitt. Up. II, 7). This means&amp;ndash;He alone is the cause of bliss on the part of the individual souls.&amp;ndash;Some one is here designated as the cause of bliss enjoyed by the souls; and we thus conclude that the causer of bliss, who must be other than the souls to which bliss is imparted, is the highest Self abounding in bliss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/16/</guid>
      <description>And because that (Brahman) which is referred to in the mantra is declared (to be the ānandamaya). That Brahman which is described in the mantra, &amp;lsquo;True Being, knowledge, infinite is Biahman,&amp;rsquo; is proclaimed as the Self abounding in bliss. And that Brahman is the highest Brahman, other than the individual soul; for the passage &amp;lsquo;He who knows Brahman attains the Highest&amp;rsquo; refers to Brahman as something to be obtained by the individual soul, and the words &amp;lsquo;On this the following verse is recorded&amp;rsquo; show that the verse is related to that same Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/17/</guid>
      <description>Not the other, on account of impossibility. The other than the highest Self, i.e. the one called jīva, even in the state of release, is not that Self which the mantra describes; for this is not possible. For to a Self of that kind unconditioned intelligence (such as is, in the mantra, ascribed to Brahman; cp. the term &amp;lsquo;vipaścitā&amp;rsquo;) cannot belong. Unconditioned intelligence is illustrated by the power of all one&amp;rsquo;s purposes realising themselves; as expressed in the text &amp;lsquo;He desired, may I be many, may I grow forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/18/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the declaration of difference. The part of the chapter&amp;ndash;beginning with the words &amp;lsquo;From that same Self there sprang ether&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which sets forth the nature of the Brahman referred to in the mantra, declares its difference from the individual soul, no less than from the Selfs consisting of food, breath, and mind, viz. in the clause &amp;lsquo;different from this which consists of knowledge, is the other inner Self which consists of bliss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/19/</guid>
      <description>And on account of desire, there is no regard to what is inferred (i.e. matter). In order that the individual soul which is enthralled by Nescience may operate as the cause of the world, it must needs be connected with non-sentient matter, called by such names as pradhāna, or ānumānika (that which is inferred). For such is the condition for the creative energy of Brahmā and similar beings. Our text, on the other hand, teaches that the creation of the aggregate of sentient and non-sentient things results from the mere wish of a being free from all connexion with non-sentient matter, &amp;lsquo;He desired, may I be many, may I grow forth;&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;He sent forth all, whatever there is&amp;rsquo; (Taitt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/20/</guid>
      <description>And Scripture teaches the joining of this (i.e. the individual soul) with that (i.e. bliss) in that (i.e. the ānandamaya). &amp;lsquo;A flavour he is indeed; having obtained a flavour this one enjoys bliss&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 7). This text declares that this one, i.e. the so-called individual soul, enjoys bliss through obtaining the ānandamaya, here called &amp;lsquo;flavour.&amp;rsquo; Now to say that any one is identical with that by obtaining which he enjoys bliss, would be madness indeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/21/</guid>
      <description>The one within (the sun and the eye); on account of his qualities being declared. It is said in the Cḥāndogya: &amp;lsquo;Now that person bright as gold, who is seen within the sun, with beard bright as gold and hair bright as gold, golden altogether to the very tips of his nails, whose eyes are like blue lotus; his name is Ut, for he has risen (udita) above all evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/22/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the declaration of difference (the highest Self is) other (than the individual souls of the sun, &amp;amp;c.). There are texts which clearly state that the highest
Self is different from Āditya and the other individual souls: &amp;lsquo;He who, dwelling within Aditya (the sun), is different from Āditya, whom Āditya does not know, of whom Āditya is the body, who rules Āditya from within; who dwelling within the Self is different from the Self,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/23/</guid>
      <description>Ether (is Brahman), on account of the characteristic marks. We read in the Cḥāndogya (I, 9), &amp;lsquo;What is the origin of this world?&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Ether,&amp;rsquo; he replied. &amp;lsquo;For all these beings spring from the ether only, and return into the ether. Ether is greater than these; ether is their rest.&amp;rsquo; Here there arises the doubt whether the word &amp;rsquo;ether&amp;rsquo; denotes
the well-known element or Brahman.&amp;ndash;The Pūrvapakshin maintains the former alternative. For, he says, in the case of things to be apprehended through words we must accept that sense of the word which, proved by etymology, is immediately suggested by the word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/24/</guid>
      <description>For the same reason breath (is Brahman). We read in the Cḥāndogya (I, 10; ii), &amp;lsquo;Prastotr̥, that deity which belongs to the Prastāva,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.; and further on, &amp;lsquo;which then is that deity? He said&amp;ndash;Breath. For all these beings merge into breath alone, and from breath they arise. This is the deity belonging to the Prastāva. If without knowing that deity you had sung forth, your head would have fallen off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/25/</guid>
      <description>The light (is Brahman), on account of the mention of feet. We read in the Cḥāndogya. (III, 13, 7), &amp;lsquo;Now that light which shines above this heaven, higher than everything, in the highest worlds beyond which there are no other worlds, that is the same light which is within man.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Here a doubt arises, viz. whether the brightly shining thing here called &amp;rsquo;light&amp;rsquo; is the well-known light of the sun and so on, viewed as a causal universal principle (Brahman); or the all-knowing, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/26/</guid>
      <description>If it be objected that (Brahman is) not (denoted) on account of the metre being denoted; (we reply) not so, because thus the direction of the mind (on Brahman) is declared; for thus it is seen. The previous section at first refers to the metre called Gāyatrī, &amp;lsquo;The Gāyatrī indeed is everything&amp;rsquo; (III, 12, 1), and then introduces&amp;ndash;with the words &amp;rsquo;this is also declared by a Rik verse&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the verse, &amp;lsquo;Such is the greatness of it (viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/27/</guid>
      <description>And thus also, because (thus only) the designation of the beings, and so on, being the (four) feet is possible. The text, moreover, designates the Gāyatrī as having four feet, after having referred to the beings, the earth, the body, and the heart; now this has a sense only if it is Brahman, which here is called Gāyatrī.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/28/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that (Brahman is) not (recognised) on account of the difference of designation; (we say) not so, on account of there being no contradiction in either (designation). In the former passage, &amp;rsquo;three feet of it are what is immortal in heaven,&amp;rsquo; heaven is referred to as the abode of the being under discussion; while in the latter passage, &amp;rsquo;that light which shines above this heaven,&amp;rsquo; heaven is mentioned as marking its boundary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/29/</guid>
      <description>Prāṇa is Brahman, on account of connexion. We read in the Pratardana-vidyā in the Kaushītaki-brāhmaṇa that &amp;lsquo;Pratardana, the son of Divodāsa, came, by fighting and strength, to the beloved abode of Indra.&amp;rsquo; Being asked by Indra to choose a boon he requests the God to bestow on him that boon which he himself considers most beneficial to man; whereupon Indra says, &amp;lsquo;I am prāṇa (breath), the intelligent Self, meditate on me as Life, as Immortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/30/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that (Brahman is) not (denoted) on account of the speaker denoting himself; (we say, not so), because the multitude of connexions with the inner Self (is possible only) in that (speaker if viewed as Brahman). An objection is raised.&amp;ndash;That the being introduced as Indra and Prāṇa should be the highest Brahman, for the reason that it is identical with him who, later on, is called &amp;lsquo;blessed,&amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo;non-ageing, &amp;lsquo;immortal&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;this we cannot admit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/31/</guid>
      <description>The instruction (given by Indra about himself) (is possible) through insight based on Scripture, as in the case of Vāmadeva. The instruction which, in the passages quoted, Indra gives as to the object of meditation, i.e. Brahman constituting his Self, is not based on such an insight into his own nature as is established by other means of proof, but on an intuition of his own Self, mediated by Scripture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/1/32/</guid>
      <description>If it be said (that Brahman is not meant) on account of characteristic marks of the individual soul and the chief vital air; we say no, on account of the threefoldness of meditation; on account of (such threefold meditation) being met (in other texts also); and on account of (such threefold meditation) being appropriate here (also). An objection is raised. &amp;lsquo;Let none try to find out what speech is, let him know the speaker&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;I slew the three-headed son of Tvash_tri_; I delivered the Arunmukhas, the devotees, to the wolves&amp;rsquo;; these passages state characteristic marks of an individual soul (viz.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
