<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ मध्य on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ मध्य on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 The Later Pastimes of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter there is a summary description of all the pastimes performed by Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu during the middle period of His activities as well as the six years at the end of His activities. All of these are described in brief. There is also a description of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s ecstasy that occurred when He recited the verse beginning &lt;em&gt;yaḥ kaumāra-haraḥ,&lt;/em&gt; as well as a description of how that ecstasy was explained in the verse beginning &lt;em&gt;priyaḥ so ’yaṁ kṛṣṇaḥ,&lt;/em&gt; by Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī. Because he wrote that verse, Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī was specifically blessed by the Lord. There is also a description of the many books written by Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī, Śrīla Sanātana Gosvāmī and Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī. There is also a description of the meeting between Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī and Śrīla Sanātana Gosvāmī in the village known as Rāmakeli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 The Ecstatic Manifestations of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the second chapter of the &lt;em&gt;Madhya-līlā,&lt;/em&gt; the author describes the pastimes the Lord performed during the last twelve years of His life. Thus he has also described some of the pastimes of the &lt;em&gt;antya-līlā.&lt;/em&gt; Why he has done so is very difficult for an ordinary person to understand. The author expects that reading the pastimes of the Lord will gradually help a person awaken his dormant love of Kṛṣṇa. Actually this &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt; was compiled by the author during very old age. Fearing he might not be able to finish the book, he has included a synopsis of the &lt;em&gt;antya-līlā&lt;/em&gt; here in the second chapter. Śrīla Kavirāja Gosvāmī has confirmed that the opinion of Svarūpa Dāmodara is authoritative in the matter of devotional service. Over and above this are the notes of Svarūpa Dāmodara, memorized by Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī, who also helped in the compilation of the &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-caritāmṛta.&lt;/em&gt; After the disappearance of Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī, Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī went to Vṛndāvana. At that time the author, Śrīla Kavirāja Gosvāmī, met Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī, by whose mercy he also could memorize all the notes. In this way the author was able to complete this transcendental literature, &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s Stay at the House of Advaita Ācārya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THREE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the third chapter. After accepting the &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; order at Katwa, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu traveled continuously for three days in Rāḍha-deśa and, by the trick of Nityānanda Prabhu, eventually came to the western side of Śāntipura. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was induced to believe that the river Ganges was the Yamunā. When He was worshiping the sacred river, Advaita Prabhu arrived in a boat. Advaita Prabhu asked Him to take His bath in the Ganges and took Him to His (Advaita’s) house. There all the Navadvīpa devotees, along with mother Śacīdevī, came to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. This house was located at Śāntipura. Mother Śacīdevī cooked for Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Nityānanda Prabhu, and at that time there were many joking exchanges between Advaita Prabhu and Nityānanda Prabhu. In the evening there was a mass &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana&lt;/em&gt; at the house of Advaita Prabhu, and mother Śacīdevī gave Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu permission to leave. She requested Him to make Jagannātha Purī, Nīlācala, His headquarters. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu granted His mother’s request and, followed by Nityānanda, Mukunda, Jagadānanda and Dāmodara, left Śāntipura. Bidding farewell to mother Śacīdevī, they all proceeded toward Jagannātha Purī, following the path of Chatrabhoga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Śrī Mādhavendra Purī’s Devotional Service</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the fourth chapter. Passing along the path of Chatrabhoga and coming to Vṛddhamantreśvara, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu reached the border of Orissa. On His way He enjoyed transcendental bliss by chanting and begging alms in different villages. In this way He reached the celebrated village of Remuṇā, where there is a Deity of Gopīnātha. There He narrated the story of Mādhavendra Purī, as He had heard it from His spiritual master, Īśvara Purī. The narration is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Activities of Sākṣi-gopāla</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the fifth chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; After passing through Yājapura, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu reached the town of Kaṭaka (Cuttack) and there went to see the temple of Sākṣi-gopāla. While there, He heard the story of Sākṣi-gopāla from the mouth of Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once there were two &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas,&lt;/em&gt; one elderly and the other young, who were inhabitants of a place known as Vidyānagara. After touring many places of pilgrimage, the two &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas&lt;/em&gt; finally reached Vṛndāvana. The elderly &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; was very satisfied with the service of the young &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa,&lt;/em&gt; and he wanted to offer him his youngest daughter in marriage. The young &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; received the promise of his elder before the Gopāla Deity of Vṛndāvana. Thus the Gopāla Deity acted as a witness. When the two &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas&lt;/em&gt; returned to Vidyānagara, the younger &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; raised the question of this marriage, but the elderly &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa,&lt;/em&gt; due to obligations to his friends and wife, answered that he could not remember his promise. Because of this, the younger &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; returned to Vṛndāvana and narrated the whole story to Gopālajī. Thus Gopālajī, being obliged by the young man’s devotional service, accompanied him to southern India. Gopālajī followed the younger &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa,&lt;/em&gt; who could hear the tinkling sound of Gopālajī’s ankle bells. When all the respectable gentlemen of Vidyānagara were assembled, Gopālajī testified to the promise of the elderly &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa.&lt;/em&gt; Thus the marriage was performed. Later, the king of that country constructed a fine temple for Gopāla.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Liberation of Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the sixth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu entered the temple of Jagannātha, He immediately fainted. Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya then took Him to his home. Meanwhile, Gopīnātha Ācārya, the brother-in-law of Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya, met Mukunda Datta and talked to him about Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s acceptance of &lt;em&gt;sannyāsa&lt;/em&gt; and His journey to Jagannātha Purī. After hearing about Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s fainting and His being carried to the house of Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya, people crowded there to see the Lord. Śrīla Nityānanda Prabhu and other devotees then visited the Jagannātha temple, and when they came back to the house of Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu returned to external consciousness. Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya received everyone and distributed &lt;em&gt;mahā-prasādam&lt;/em&gt; with great care. The Bhaṭṭācārya then became acquainted with Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and arranged accommodations at his aunt’s house. His brother-in-law, Gopīnātha Ācārya, established that Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu was Kṛṣṇa Himself, but Sārvabhauma and his many disciples could not accept this. However, Gopīnātha Ācārya convinced Sārvabhauma that no one can understand the Supreme Personality of Godhead without being favored by Him. He proved by śāstric quotation, quotations from the revealed scriptures, that Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was Kṛṣṇa Himself in person. Still, Sārvabhauma did not take these statements very seriously. Hearing all these arguments, Caitanya Mahāprabhu told His devotees that Sārvabhauma was His spiritual master and that whatever he said out of affection was for everyone’s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Lord Begins His Tour of South India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura summarizes the seventh chapter as follows. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu accepted the renounced order of life in the month of Māgha (January-February) and went to Jagannātha Purī in the month of Phālguna (February-March). He saw the Dola-yātrā festival during the month of Phālguna, and in the month of Caitra He liberated Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya. During the month of Vaiśākha, He began to tour South India. When He proposed to travel to South India alone, Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu gave Him a &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; assistant named Kṛṣṇadāsa. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was beginning His tour, Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya gave Him four sets of clothes and requested Him to see Rāmānanda Rāya, who was residing at that time on the bank of the river Godāvarī. Along with other devotees, Nityānanda Prabhu accompanied the Lord to Ālālanātha, but there Lord Caitanya left them all behind and went ahead with the &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; Kṛṣṇadāsa. The Lord began chanting the &lt;em&gt;mantra&lt;/em&gt; “&lt;em&gt;kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa kṛṣṇa he.&lt;/em&gt;” In whatever village He spent the night, whenever a person came to see Him in His shelter, the Lord implored him to preach the Kṛṣṇa consciousness movement. After teaching the people of one village, the Lord proceeded to other villages to increase devotees. In this way He finally reached Kūrma-sthāna. While there, He bestowed His causeless mercy upon a &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; called Kūrma and cured another &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa,&lt;/em&gt; named Vāsudeva, who was suffering from leprosy. After curing this &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; leper, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu received the title Vāsudevāmṛta-prada, meaning “one who delivered nectar to the leper Vāsudeva.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Talks Between Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Rāmānanda Rāya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The summary of the eighth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; After visiting the temple of Jiyaḍa-nṛsiṁha, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu went to the banks of the river Godāvarī, to a place known as Vidyānagara. When Śrīla Rāmānanda Rāya went there to take his bath, they met. After introducing himself, Śrī Rāmānanda Rāya requested Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu to remain in the village for some days. Honoring his request, Caitanya Mahāprabhu stayed there in the home of some Vedic &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas.&lt;/em&gt; In the evening, Śrīla Rāmānanda Rāya used to come to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Rāmānanda Rāya, who was clothed in ordinary dress, offered the Lord respectful obeisances. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu questioned him on the object and process of worship and also asked him to recite verses from the Vedic literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s Travels to the Holy Places</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विश्वास-टिप्पनी&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a weird account - chaitanya convinces venkaTa (who admits to being a sentimental dimwit) to become a follower. then defeats bhaTTatiris who physically came to attack him by magic. Then he goes to uDupi and berates some mAdhva AchArya for stressing on varNAshramadharma rather than nAma-sankIrtana.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mentions meeting some Rāmānanda Rāya in vidyAnagara - no such vijayanagara or kalinga king or governor is known.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the ninth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura. After leaving Vidyānagara, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu visited such places of pilgrimage as Gautamī-gaṅgā, Mallikārjuna, Ahovala-nṛsiṁha, Siddhavaṭa, Skanda-kṣetra, Trimaṭha, Vṛddhakāśī, Bauddha-sthāna, Tirupati, Tirumala, Pānā-nṛsiṁha, Śiva-kāñcī, Viṣṇu-kāñcī, Trikāla-hasti, Vṛddhakola, Śiyālī-bhairavī, the Kāverī River and Kumbhakarṇa-kapāla.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Lord’s Return to Jagannātha Purī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was traveling in South India, Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya had many talks with King Pratāparudra. When Mahārāja Pratāparudra requested the Bhaṭṭācārya to arrange an interview with the Lord, the Bhaṭṭācārya assured him that he would try to do so as soon as Caitanya Mahāprabhu returned from South India. When the Lord returned to Jagannātha Purī from His South Indian tour, He lived at the home of Kāśī Miśra. Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya introduced many Vaiṣṇavas to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu after His return. The father of Rāmānanda Rāya, Bhavānanda Rāya, offered another son named Vāṇīnātha Paṭṭanāyaka for the Lord’s service. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu informed His associates about the pollution of Kṛṣṇadāsa brought about by his association with the Bhaṭṭathāris, and thus the Lord proposed to give him leave. Nityānanda Prabhu sent Kṛṣṇadāsa to Bengal to inform the Navadvīpa devotees about the Lord’s return to Jagannātha Purī. All the devotees of Navadvīpa thus began arranging to come to Jagannātha Purī. At this time Paramānanda Purī was at Navadvīpa, and immediately upon hearing news of the Lord’s return, he started for Jagannātha Purī accompanied by a &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; named Kamalākānta. Puruṣottama Bhaṭṭācārya, a resident of Navadvīpa, was educated at Vārāṇasī. He accepted the renounced order from Caitanyānanda, but he took the name of Svarūpa. Thus he arrived at the lotus feet of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. After the demise of Śrī Īśvara Purī, his disciple Govinda, following his instructions, went to serve Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Due to his relationship with Keśava Bhāratī, Brahmānanda Bhāratī was also respectfully received by Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. When he arrived at Jagannātha Purī, he was advised to give up the deerskin clothing he wore. When Brahmānanda understood Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu correctly, he accepted Him as Kṛṣṇa Himself. However, when Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya addressed Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu as Kṛṣṇa, the Lord immediately protested. In the meantime, Kāśīśvara Gosvāmī also came to see Caitanya Mahāprabhu. In this chapter, devotees from many different areas come to see Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and they are exactly like many rivers that come from many places to finally flow into the sea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Beḍā-kīrtana Pastimes of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura summarizes the eleventh chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; When Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya tried his best to arrange a meeting between Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and King Pratāparudra, the Lord flatly denied his request. At this time Śrī Rāmānanda Rāya returned from his governmental post, and he praised King Pratāparudra highly in Lord Caitanya’s presence. Because of this, the Lord became a little soft. The King also made promises to Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya, who hinted how the King might meet the Lord. During Anavasara, while Lord Jagannātha was resting for fifteen days, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, being unable to see Lord Jagannātha, went to Ālālanātha. Later, when the devotees from Bengal came to see Him, He returned to Jagannātha Purī. While Advaita Ācārya and the other devotees were coming to Jagannātha Purī, Svarūpa Dāmodara and Govinda, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s two personal assistants, went to receive all the devotees with garlands. From the roof of his palace, King Pratāparudra could see all the devotees arriving. Gopīnātha Ācārya stood on the roof with the King, and, following Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya’s instructions, identified each and every devotee. The King discussed the devotees with Gopīnātha Ācārya, and he mentioned that the devotees were accepting &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; without observing the regulative principles governing pilgrimages. They accepted &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; without having shaved, and they neglected to fast in a holy place. After Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya had explained to the King why the devotees had apparently violated the scriptural injunctions for visiting a place of pilgrimage, the King arranged residential quarters for all the devotees and saw to their &lt;em&gt;prasādam.&lt;/em&gt; Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu talked very happily with Vāsudeva Datta and other devotees. Haridāsa Ṭhākura also came, and due to his humble and submissive attitude, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu gave him a nice solitary place near the temple. After this, the Lord began performing &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana,&lt;/em&gt; dividing all the devotees into four groups. After &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana,&lt;/em&gt; all the devotees left for their residential quarters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Cleansing of the Guṇḍicā Temple</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya,&lt;/em&gt; Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura summarizes this chapter as follows. The King of Orissa, Mahārāja Pratāparudra, tried his best to see Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Śrīla Nityānanda Prabhu and the other devotees informed the Lord about the King’s desire, but Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu would not agree to see him. At that time Śrī Nityānanda Prabhu devised a plan, and He sent a piece of the Lord’s outward garment to the King. The next day, when Rāmānanda Rāya again entreated Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu to see the King, the Lord, denying the request, asked Rāmānanda Rāya to bring the King’s son before Him. The prince visited the Lord dressed like a Vaiṣṇava, and this awakened remembrance of Kṛṣṇa. Thus Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu delivered the son of Mahārāja Pratāparudra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Ecstatic Dancing of the Lord at Ratha-yātrā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of this chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. After bathing early in the morning, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu saw the deities (Jagannātha, Baladeva and Subhadrā) get aboard their three cars. This function is called Pāṇḍu-vijaya. At that time, King Pratāparudra took a broom with a golden handle and began to cleanse the road. Lord Jagannātha took permission from the goddess of fortune and then started in the car for the Guṇḍicā temple. The road to the temple led along a broad, sandy beach, and on both sides of the road were residential quarters, houses and gardens. Along that road the servants called &lt;em&gt;gauḍas&lt;/em&gt; began to pull the cars. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu divided His &lt;em&gt;saṅkīrtana&lt;/em&gt; party into seven divisions. With two &lt;em&gt;mṛdaṅgas&lt;/em&gt; in each division, there were altogether fourteen &lt;em&gt;mṛdaṅgas.&lt;/em&gt; While performing &lt;em&gt;kīrtana,&lt;/em&gt; Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu exhibited various symptoms of transcendental ecstasy, and Jagannātha and Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu exchanged Their feelings very blissfully. When the cars reached the place known as Balagaṇḍi, the devotees offered the deities simple food. At this time, in a nearby garden, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and His devotees took a brief rest from the dancing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Performance of the Vṛndāvana Pastimes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dressing himself as a Vaiṣṇava, Mahārāja Pratāparudra entered the garden at Balagaṇḍi alone and began reciting verses from &lt;em&gt;Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam.&lt;/em&gt; He then took the opportunity to massage the lotus feet of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The Lord, in His ecstatic love for Kṛṣṇa, immediately embraced the King and thus bestowed mercy upon him. When there was an offering of &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; in the garden, Lord Caitanya also partook of it. After this, when Lord Jagannātha’s &lt;em&gt;ratha&lt;/em&gt; car stopped moving, King Pratāparudra called for many elephants to pull it, but they were unsuccessful. Seeing this, Lord Caitanya began to push the car from behind with His head, and the car began moving. Then the devotees began pulling the car with ropes. Near the Guṇḍicā temple is a place known as Āiṭoṭā. This place was fixed up for Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu to rest in. When Lord Jagannātha was seated at Sundarācala, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu saw it as Vṛndāvana. He performed sporting pastimes in the water of the lake known as Indradyumna. For nine continuous days during Ratha-yātrā, the Lord remained at Sundarācala, and on the fifth day He and Svarūpa Dāmodara observed the pastimes of Lakṣmī, the goddess of fortune. During that time, there was much talk about the pastimes of the &lt;em&gt;gopīs.&lt;/em&gt; When the &lt;em&gt;ratha&lt;/em&gt; was again being drawn and the chanting resumed, two devotees from Kulīna-grāma — Rāmānanda Vasu and Satyarāja Khān — were requested to bring silk ropes every year for the Ratha-yātrā ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Lord Accepts Prasādam at the House of Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of this chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; After the Ratha-yātrā festival, Śrī Advaita Ācārya Prabhu worshiped Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu with flowers and &lt;em&gt;tulasī.&lt;/em&gt; Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, in return, worshiped Advaita Ācārya with the flowers and &lt;em&gt;tulasī&lt;/em&gt; that remained on the offered plate and said a &lt;em&gt;mantra, yo ’si so ’si namo ’stu te&lt;/em&gt; (“Whatever You are, You are — but I offer My respects unto You”). Then Advaita Ācārya Prabhu invited Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu for &lt;em&gt;prasādam.&lt;/em&gt; When Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and His devotees performed the Nandotsava ceremony, the Lord dressed Himself as a cowherd boy. Thus the ceremony was very jubilant. Then the Lord and His devotees observed Vijayā-daśamī, the day of victory when Lord Rāmacandra conquered Laṅkā. The devotees all became soldiers of Lord Rāmacandra, and Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, in the ecstasy of Hanumān, manifested various transcendentally blissful activities. Thereafter, the Lord and His devotees observed various other ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The Lord’s Attempt to Go to Vṛndāvana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of this chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu wanted to go to Vṛndāvana, Rāmānanda Rāya and Sārvabhauma Bhaṭṭācārya indirectly presented many obstructions. In due course of time, all the devotees of Bengal visited Jagannātha Purī for the third year. This time, all the wives of the Vaiṣṇavas brought many types of food, intending to extend invitations to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu at Jagannātha Purī. When the devotees arrived, Caitanya Mahāprabhu sent His blessings in the form of garlands. In that year also, the Guṇḍicā temple was cleansed, and when the Cāturmāsya period was over, all the devotees returned to their homes in Bengal. Caitanya Mahāprabhu forbade Nityānanda to visit Nīlācala every year. Questioned by the inhabitants of Kulīna-grāma, Caitanya Mahāprabhu again repeated the symptoms of a Vaiṣṇava. Vidyānidhi also came to Jagannātha Purī and saw the festival of Oḍana-ṣaṣṭhī. When the devotees bade farewell to the Lord, the Lord was determined to go to Vṛndāvana, and on the day of Vijaya-daśamī, He departed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The Lord Travels to Vṛndāvana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVENTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of the seventeenth chapter is given by Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; After attending the Ratha-yātrā ceremony of Śrī Jagannātha, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu decided to start for Vṛndāvana. Śrī Rāmānanda Rāya and Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī selected a &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; named Balabhadra Bhaṭṭācārya to personally assist Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Early in the morning before sunrise, the Lord started for the town of Kaṭaka (Cuttack). North of Kaṭaka, He penetrated a dense forest and came upon many tigers and elephants, whom He engaged in chanting the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mahā-mantra.&lt;/em&gt; Whenever the Lord had a chance to visit a village, Balabhadra Bhaṭṭācārya would beg alms and acquire some rice and vegetables. If there were no village, Balabhadra would cook whatever rice remained and collect some spinach from the forest for the Lord to eat. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was very pleased with the behavior of Balabhadra Bhaṭṭācārya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s Visit to Śrī Vṛndāvana</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of the eighteenth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; In the village of Āriṭ-grāma, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu discovered the transcendental lakes known as Rādhā-kuṇḍa and Śyāma-kuṇḍa. He then saw the Deity Harideva at Govardhana Village. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu had no desire to climb Govardhana Hill because the hill is worshiped as Kṛṣṇa. The Gopāla Deity could understand the mind of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu; therefore on the plea of being attacked by Muslims, Gopāla transferred Himself to the village of Gāṅṭhuli-grāma. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu then went to Gāṅṭhuli-grāma to see Lord Gopāla. Some years later, Lord Gopāla also went to Mathurā, to the house of Viṭhṭhaleśvara, and stayed there for one month just to give an audience to Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu Instructs Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINETEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of this chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Meeting Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu in a village called Rāmakeli, two brothers, Rūpa and Sanātana, began to devise means to get out of their government service. They appointed some &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas&lt;/em&gt; to perform &lt;em&gt;puraścaraṇa&lt;/em&gt; ceremonies and chant the holy name of Kṛṣṇa. Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī deposited ten thousand gold coins with a grocer, and the balance he brought in two boats to a place called Bāklā Candradvīpa. There he divided this money among the &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇas,&lt;/em&gt; Vaiṣṇavas and his relatives, and a portion he kept for emergency measures and personal needs. He was informed that Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was going to Vṛndāvana from Jagannātha Purī through the forest of Jhārikhaṇḍa (Jharkhand); therefore he sent two people to Jagannātha Purī to find out when the Lord would leave for Vṛndāvana. In this way Rūpa Gosvāmī retired, but Sanātana Gosvāmī told the Nawab that he was sick and could not attend to his work. Giving this excuse, he sat at home and studied &lt;em&gt;Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam&lt;/em&gt; with learned &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; scholars. The Nawab Hussain Shah first sent his personal physician to see what the real facts were; then he personally came to see why Sanātana was not attending to official business. Knowing that he wanted to resign his post, the Nawab had him arrested and imprisoned. The Nawab then went off to attack Orissa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu Instructs Sanātana Gosvāmī in the Science of the Absolute Truth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of this chapter is given by Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; When Śrīla Sanātana Gosvāmī was imprisoned by Nawab Hussain Shah, he received news from Rūpa Gosvāmī that Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu had gone to Mathurā. Sanātana Gosvāmī thereafter satisfied the superintendent of the jail by sweet solicitations and bribery. After giving the jailer seven thousand gold coins, Sanātana Gosvāmī was released. He then crossed the Ganges and fled. One of his servants, Īśāna, followed him, carrying eight gold coins. Sanātana Gosvāmī and his servant then spent the night in a small hotel on the way to Benares. The hotel owner knew that Sanātana Gosvāmī and his servant had eight gold coins, and he decided to kill them and take the money. Making plans in this way, the hotel owner received them as honorable guests. Sanātana Gosvāmī, however, asked his servant how much money he had, and taking seven of the gold coins, Sanātana offered them to the hotel owner. Thus the owner helped them cross the hilly tract and proceed toward Vārāṇasī. On the way, Sanātana Gosvāmī met his brother-in-law, Śrīkānta, at Hājipura, and Śrīkānta helped him after he had heard about all Sanātana’s troubles. Thus Sanātana Gosvāmī finally arrived at Vārāṇasī and stood before the door of Candraśekhara. Caitanya Mahāprabhu called him in and ordered him to change his dress so that he would look like a gentleman. For his garment, he used an old cloth of Tapana Miśra’s. Later, he exchanged his valuable blanket for a torn quilt. At this time Caitanya Mahāprabhu was very pleased with him, and thus Śrī Sanātana Gosvāmī received knowledge of the Absolute Truth from the Lord Himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 The Opulence and Sweetness of Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the twenty-first chapter. In this chapter Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu fully describes Kṛṣṇaloka, the spiritual sky, the Causal Ocean and the material world, which consists of innumerable universes. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu then describes Lord Brahmā’s interview with Kṛṣṇa at Dvārakā and the Lord’s curbing the pride of Brahmā. There is also a description of one of Kṛṣṇa’s pastimes with Brahmā. In this chapter the author of the &lt;em&gt;Caitanya-caritāmṛta&lt;/em&gt; has presented some nice poems about the pastimes of Kṛṣṇa and Kṛṣṇa’s superexcellent beauty. Throughout the rest of the chapter, our intimate relationship (&lt;em&gt;sambandha&lt;/em&gt;) with Kṛṣṇa is described.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The Process of Devotional Service</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-TWO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the twenty-second chapter, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu describes the process of devotional service. In the beginning He describes the truth about the living entity and the superexcellence of devotional service. He then describes the uselessness of mental speculation and mystic &lt;em&gt;yoga.&lt;/em&gt; In all circumstances the living entity is recommended to accept the path of devotional service as personally explained by Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The speculative method of the so-called &lt;em&gt;jñānīs&lt;/em&gt; is considered a waste of time, and that is proved in this chapter. An intelligent person should abandon the processes of &lt;em&gt;karma-kāṇḍa, jñāna-kāṇḍa&lt;/em&gt; and mystic &lt;em&gt;yoga.&lt;/em&gt; One should give up all these useless processes and take seriously to the path of Kṛṣṇa consciousness. In this way one’s life will be successful. If one takes to Kṛṣṇa consciousness fully, even though he may sometimes be agitated due to having previously practiced mental speculation and yogic mysticism, he will be saved by Lord Kṛṣṇa Himself. The fact is that devotional service is bestowed by the blessings of a pure devotee (&lt;em&gt;sa mahātmā su-durlabhaḥ&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; A pure devotee is the supreme transcendentalist, and one has to receive his mercy for one’s dormant Kṛṣṇa consciousness to be awakened. One has to associate with pure devotees. If one has firm faith in the words of a great soul, pure devotional service will awaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Life’s Ultimate Goal — Love of Godhead</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-THREE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of the twenty-third chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; In this chapter Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu describes the symptoms of emotion and love and the awakening of one’s original loving relationship with the Lord, as well as the characteristics of a devotee who has actually attained that stage. He then describes the gradual increase of love of God up to the point of &lt;em&gt;mahābhāva.&lt;/em&gt; He then describes the five divisions of attraction and how they continue. He also describes the mellow derived from conjugal love, which is the supreme emotion. Conjugal love is divided into two categories — &lt;em&gt;svakīya&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;parakīya. Svakīya&lt;/em&gt; refers to loving affairs between husband and wife, and &lt;em&gt;parakīya&lt;/em&gt; refers to loving affairs between two lovers. There are a number of descriptions in this connection. There is also a description of the sixty-four transcendental qualities of Kṛṣṇa and the twenty-five transcendental qualities of Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The Sixty-One Explanations of the Ātmārāma Verse</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FOUR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of this chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; According to Śrī Sanātana Gosvāmī’s request, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu explained the well-known &lt;em&gt;Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam&lt;/em&gt; verse beginning &lt;em&gt;ātmārāmāś ca munayaḥ.&lt;/em&gt; He explained this verse in sixty-one different ways. He analyzed all the words and described each word with its different connotations. Adding the words &lt;em&gt;ca&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;api,&lt;/em&gt; He described all the different meanings of the verse. He then concluded that different classes of transcendentalists (&lt;em&gt;jñānīs, karmīs, yogīs&lt;/em&gt;) utilize this verse according to their own interpretation, but if they would give up this process and surrender to Kṛṣṇa, as indicated by the verse itself, they would be able to comprehend the real meaning of the verse. In this regard, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu narrated a story about how the great sage Nārada converted a hunter into a great Vaiṣṇava, and how this was appreciated by Nārada’s friend Parvata Muni. Sanātana Gosvāmī then offered a prayer to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu explained the glory of &lt;em&gt;Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam.&lt;/em&gt; After this, the Lord gave Sanātana Gosvāmī a synopsis of &lt;em&gt;Hari-bhakti-vilāsa,&lt;/em&gt; which Sanātana Gosvāmī later developed into the guiding principle of all Vaiṣṇavas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 How All the Residents of Vārāṇasī Became Vaiṣṇavas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/02_madhya/25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is a summary of chapter twenty-five. A Maharashtriyan &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; who was living in Benares was a great devotee of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. He was always very happy to hear the glories of the Lord, and it was by his arrangement that all the &lt;em&gt;sannyāsīs&lt;/em&gt; of Vārāṇasī became devotees of Lord Caitanya Mahāprabhu. He invited all the &lt;em&gt;sannyāsīs&lt;/em&gt; to his house to meet Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and this incident has been described in the seventh chapter of the &lt;em&gt;Ādi-līlā.&lt;/em&gt; From that day, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu became famous in the city of Vārāṇasī, and many important men in that city became His followers. By and by, one of the disciples of the great &lt;em&gt;sannyāsī&lt;/em&gt; Prakāśānanda Sarasvatī became devoted to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and this devotee explained Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu to Prakāśānanda Sarasvatī and supported His views with various arguments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
