<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;३ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/01/</guid>
      <description>THIRD PĀDA. The abode of heaven, earth, &amp;amp;c. (is the highest Self), on account of terms which are its own. The followers of the Atharva-veda have the following text, &amp;lsquo;He in whom the heaven, the earth and the sky are woven, the mind also, with all the vital airs, know him alone as the Self, and leave off other words; he is the bank (setu) of the Immortal&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. II, 2, 5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/02/</guid>
      <description>And on account of its being declared that to which the released have to resort. The Person who is the abode of heaven, earth, and so
on, is also declared by the text to be what is to be reached by those who are released from the bondage of Saṁsāra existence. &amp;lsquo;When the seer sees the brilliant maker and Lord as the Person who has his source in Brahman, then possessing true knowledge he shakes off good and evil, and, free from passion, reaches the highest oneness&amp;rsquo; (Mu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/03/</guid>
      <description>Not that which is inferred, on account of the absence of terms denoting it, and (so also not) the bearer of the Prāṇas (i. e. the individual soul). As the section under discussion does not treat of the Pradhāna, there being no terms referring to that, so it is with regard to the individual soul also. In the text of the Sūtra we have to read either anumānam, i. e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/04/</guid>
      <description>On account of the declaration of difference. &amp;lsquo;On the same tree man sits immersed in grief, bewildered
by &amp;ldquo;anīśā&amp;rdquo;; but when he sees the other one, the Lord, contented, and his glory; then his grief passes away&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. III, 1, 2). This, and similar texts, speak of that one, i.e. the one previously described as the abode of heaven, earth, &amp;amp;c., as different from the individual soul.&amp;ndash;The text means&amp;ndash;the individual soul grieves, being bewildered by her who is not &amp;lsquo;īśa,&amp;rsquo; i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/05/</guid>
      <description>On account of the subject-matter. It has been already shown, viz. under I, 2, 21, that the highest Brahman constitutes the initial topic of the Upanishad. And by the arguments set forth in the previous Sūtras of the present Pāda, we have removed all suspicion as to the topic started being dropped in the body of the Upanishad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/06/</guid>
      <description>And on account of abiding and eating. &amp;lsquo;Two birds, inseparable friends, cling to the same tree. One of them eats the sweet fruit; without eating, the other looks on&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. III, 1, 1). This text declares that one enjoys the fruit of works while the other, without enjoying, shining abides within the body. Now this shining being which does not enjoy the fruit of works can only be the being previously described as the abode of heaven, earth, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/07/</guid>
      <description>The bhūman (is the highest Self), as the instruction about it is additional to that about serenity. The Cḥandogas read as follows: &amp;lsquo;Where one sees nothing
else, hears nothing else, knows nothing else, that is fulness (bhūman). Where one sees something else, hears something else, knows something else, that is the Little&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VII, 23, 24).
The term &amp;lsquo;bhūman&amp;rsquo; is derived from bahu (much, many), and primarily signifies &amp;lsquo;muchness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/08/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the suitability of the attributes. The attributes also which the text ascribes to the bhūman suit the highest Self only. So immortality (&amp;lsquo;The Bhūman is immortal,&amp;rsquo; VII, 24, 1); not being based on something else (&amp;lsquo;it rests in its own greatness&amp;rsquo;); being the Self of all (&amp;rsquo;the bhūman is below,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., &amp;lsquo;it is all this&amp;rsquo;); being that which produces all (&amp;lsquo;from the Self there springs breath,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/09/</guid>
      <description>The Imperishable (is Brahman), on account of its supporting that which is the end of ether. The Vājasaneyins, in the chapter recording the questions asked by Gārgī, read as follows: &amp;lsquo;He said, O Gārgī, the Brāhmaṇas call that the Imperishable. It is neither coarse nor fine, neither short nor long, it is not red, not fluid, it is without a shadow,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Br̥. Up. III, 8, 8). A doubt here arises whether that Imperishable be the Pradhāna, or the individual soul, or the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/10/</guid>
      <description>And this (supporting) (springs) from command. The text declares that this supporting of ether and all other things proceeds from command. &amp;lsquo;In the command of that Imperishable sun and moon stand, held apart; in the command of that Imperishable heaven and earth stand, held apart,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. Now such supreme command, through which all things in the universe are held apart, cannot possibly belong to the individual soul in the state either of bondage or of release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/11/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the exclusion of (what is of) another nature (than Brahman). Another nature, i. e. the nature of the Pradhāna, and so on. A supplementary passage excludes difference on the part of the Imperishable from the supreme Person. &amp;lsquo;That Imperishable, O Gārgī, is unseen but seeing; unheard but hearing; unthought but thinking; unknown but knowing. There is nothing that sees but it, nothing that hears but it, nothing that thinks but it, nothing that knows but it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/12/</guid>
      <description>On account of his being designated as the object of seeing, he (i.e. the highest Self) (is that object). The followers of the Atharva-veda, in the section containing the question asked by Satyakāma, read as follows: &amp;lsquo;He again who meditates with this syllable Aum of three Mātrās on the highest Person, he comes to light and to the sun. As a snake frees itself from its skin, so he frees himself from evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/13/</guid>
      <description>The small (ether) (is Brahman), on account of the subsequent (arguments). The Cḥandogas have the following text, &amp;lsquo;Now in that city of Brahman there is the palace, the small lotus, and in it that small ether. Now what is within that small ether that is to be sought for, that is to be understood&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 1, 1).&amp;ndash;The question here arises whether that small ether (space) within the lotus of the heart be the material clement called ether, or the individual Self, or the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/14/</guid>
      <description>On account of the going and of the word; for thus it is seen; and (there is) an inferential sign. &amp;lsquo;As people who do not know the country walk again and again over a gold treasure&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., &amp;rsquo;thus do all these creatures day after day go into that Brahma-world&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VIII, 3, 2). The circumstance, here stated, of all individual souls going to a place which the qualification &amp;rsquo;that&amp;rsquo; connects with the subject-matter of the whole chapter, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/15/</guid>
      <description>And on account of there being observed in that (small ether), supporting which is a greatness of that (i. e. Brahman). In continuation of the passage &amp;lsquo;It is the Self free from Sin,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., which refers to the small ether, the text says: &amp;lsquo;it is a bank, a limitary support, that these worlds may not be confounded.&amp;rsquo; What the text here says about the small ether supporting the world proves it to be the highest Brahman; for to support the world is the glory of Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/16/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the settled meaning. The word &amp;rsquo;ether,&amp;rsquo; moreover, is known to have, among
other meanings, that of Brahman. Compare &amp;lsquo;For who could breathe, who could breathe forth, if that ether were not bliss?&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 7); &amp;lsquo;All these beings take their rise from the ether&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. I, 9, 1). It has to be kept in view that in the text under discussion the meaning &amp;lsquo;Brahman&amp;rsquo; is supported by what is said about the qualities of the small ether&amp;ndash;viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/17/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that on account of reference to the other one he is meant; we say no, on account of impossibility. An objection is raised to the argumentation that, on account of complementary passages, the small ether must be explained to mean the highest Self.
For, the objector says, a clear reference to him who is &amp;lsquo;other&amp;rsquo; than the highest Self, i.e. to the individual soul, is contained in the following passage (VIII, 12, 3): &amp;lsquo;Thus does that serenity (samprasāda), having risen from this body and approached the highest light, appear in its own form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/18/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that from a subsequent passage (it appears that the individual Soul is meant); rather (the soul) in so far as its true nature has become manifest. The Pūrvapakshin now maintains that we ascertain from a subsequent declaration made by Prajāpati that it is just the individual Soul that possesses freedom from sin and the other qualities enumerated. The whole teaching of Prajāpati, he says, refers to the individual Soul only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/19/</guid>
      <description>And the reference has a different meaning. The text in question declares that the released individual soul when reaching the highest light, i.e. Brahman, which is free from all sin, and so on, attains its true nature, which is characterised by similar freedom from sin, and so on. Now this reference to the individual soul, as described in the teaching of Prajāpati, has the purpose of giving instruction (not about the qualities of the individual soul, but) about the nature of that which is the cause of the qualities of the individual soul, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/20/</guid>
      <description>If it be said, owing to the scriptural declaration of smallness; that has been explained. The text describes the ether within the heart as being of small compass, and this agrees indeed with the individual soul which elsewhere is compared to the point of an awl, but not with Brahman, which is greater than everything.&amp;ndash;The reply to this objection has virtually been given before, viz. under I, 2, 7, where it is said that Brahman may be viewed as of small size, for the purpose of devout meditation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/21/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the imitation of that. The individual soul, free from bondage, and thus possessing the qualities of freedom from sin, &amp;amp;c., cannot be the small ether, i.e. the highest Brahman, because it is stated to &amp;lsquo;imitate,&amp;rsquo; i.e. to be equal to that Brahman. The text making that statement is Mu. Up. III, 1, 3, &amp;lsquo;When the seer (i.e. the individual soul) sees the brilliant maker, the Lord, the Person who has his source in Brahman; then becoming wise and shaking off good and evil, he reaches the highest equality, free from passions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/22/</guid>
      <description>The same is declared by Smr̥ti also. Smr̥ti also declares that the transmigrating soul when reaching the state of Release &amp;lsquo;imitates,&amp;rsquo; i.e. attains supreme equality of attributes with the highest Brahman. &amp;lsquo;Abiding by this knowledge they, attaining to equality of attributes with me, are not born again at the time of creation, nor are they affected by the general dissolution of the world&amp;rsquo; (Bha. Gī. XIV, 2).
Some maintain that the last two Sūtras constitute a separate adhikaraṇa (head of discussion), meant to prove that the text Mu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/23/</guid>
      <description>On account of the term, the one measured. We read in the Kaṭḥavallī &amp;lsquo;The Person of the size of a thumb stands in the middle of the Self, as lord of the past and the future, and henceforward fears no more&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;That Person of the size of a thumb is like a light without smoke,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Ka. Up. II, 4, 1; 13). And &amp;lsquo;The Person not larger than a thumb, the inner Self, is always settled in the heart of men&amp;rsquo; (Ka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/24/</guid>
      <description>But with reference to the heart, men being qualified. In so far as the highest Self abides, for the purpose of devout meditation, in the heart of the devotee&amp;ndash;which heart is of the measure of a thumb&amp;ndash;it may itself be viewed as having the measure of a thumb. The individual soul also can be said to have the measure of a thumb only in so far as dwelling within the heart; for scripture directly states that its real size is that of the point of a goad, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/25/</guid>
      <description>Also beings above them (i.e. men), Bādarāyaṇa thinks, on account of possibility. In order to prove that the highest Brahman may be
viewed as having the size of a thumb, it has been declared that the scriptural texts enjoining meditation on Brahman are the concern of men. This offers an opportunity for the discussion of the question whether also other classes of individual souls, such as devas, are qualified for knowledge of Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/26/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that there results a contradiction to work; we deny this, on account of the observation of the assumption of several (bodies). An objection here presents itself. If we admit the gods to have bodies, a difficulty arises at the sacrifices, as it is impossible that one and the same corporeal Indra&amp;ndash;who is at the same time invited by many sacrificers &amp;lsquo;come,
O Indra&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;come, O Lord of the red horses,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/27/</guid>
      <description>If it be said (that a contradiction will result) with regard to words; we say no, since beings originate from them (as appears) from perception and inference. Well then let us admit that there is no difficulty as far as sacrifices are concerned, for the reason stated in the preceding Sūtra. But another difficulty presents itself with regard to the words of which the Veda consists. For if Indra and the other gods are corporeal beings, it follows that they are made up of parts and hence non-permanent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/28/</guid>
      <description>And for this very reason eternity (of the Veda). As words such as Indra and Vasishṭḥa, which denote gods and R̥shis, denote (not individuals only, but) classes, and as the creation of those beings is preceded by their being suggested to the creative mind through those words; for this reason the eternity of the Veda admits of being reconciled with what scripture says about the mantras and kāṇḍas (sections) of the sacred text having &amp;lsquo;makers&amp;rsquo; and about R̥shis seeing the hymns; cp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/29/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the equality of names and forms there is no contradiction, even in the renovation (of the world); as appears from&amp;ndash;Sruti and Smr̥ti. On account of the sameness of names and forms, as stated before, there is no difficulty in the way of the origination of the world, even in the case of total pralayas. For what actually takes place is as follows. When the period of a great pralaya draws towards its close, the divine supreme Person, remembering the constitution of the world previous to the pralaya, and forming the volition &amp;lsquo;May I become manifold&amp;rsquo; separates into its constituent</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/30/</guid>
      <description>On account of the impossibility (of qualification for the madhuvidyā, &amp;amp;c.) (Jaimini maintains the non-qualification (of gods, &amp;amp;c.). So far it has been proved that also the gods, and so on, are qualified for the knowledge of Brahman. But a further point here presents itself for consideration, viz. whether the gods are qualified or not to undertake those meditations of which they themselves are the objects. The Sūtra states as a pūrvapaksha view held by Jaimini, that they are not so qualified, for the reason that there are no other Ādityas, Vasus, and so on, who could be meditated on by the Ādityas and Vasus themselves; and that moreover for the Ādityas and Vasus the qualities and position of those classes of deities cannot be objects of desire, considering that they possess them already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/31/</guid>
      <description>And on account of (meditating on the part of the gods) being in the Light. &amp;lsquo;Him the devas meditate upon as the light of lights, as
immortal time&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. IV, 4, 16). This text declares that the meditation of the gods has for its object the Light, i.e. the highest Brahman. Now this express declaration as to the gods being meditating devotees with regard to meditations on Brahman which are common to men and gods, implies a denial of the gods being qualified for meditations on other objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/33/</guid>
      <description>(That) grief of him (arose), this is intimated by his (Jānaśruti&amp;rsquo;s) resorting to him (Raikva) on hearing a disrespectful speech about himself. From what the text says about Jānaśruti Pautrāyaṇa having been taunted by a flamingo for his want of knowledge of Brahman, and having thereupon resorted to Raikva, who possessed the knowledge of Brahman, it appears that sorrow (śuc) had taken possession of him; and it is with a view to this that Raikva addresses him as Śūdra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/34/</guid>
      <description>And on account of (Jānaśruti ) kshattriya-hood being understood. The first section of the vidyā tells us that Jānaśruti bestowed much wealth and food; later on he is represented as sending his door-keeper on an errand; and in the end, as bestowing on Raikva many villages&amp;ndash;which shows him to be a territorial lord. All these circumstances suggest Jānaśruti&amp;rsquo;s being a Kshattriya, and hence not a member of the lowest caste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/35/</guid>
      <description>On account of the inferential sign further on, together with Caitraratha. The kshattriya-hood of Jānaśruti is further to be accepted on account of the Kshattriya Abhipratārin Caitraratha, who is mentioned further on in this very same Saṁvargavidyā which Raikva imparts to Jānaśruti.&amp;ndash;But why?&amp;ndash;As follows. The section beginning &amp;lsquo;Once a Brahmacārin
begged of Saunaka Kāpeya and Abhipratārin Kākshaseni while being waited on at their meal,&amp;rsquo; and ending &amp;rsquo;thus do we, O Brahmacārin, meditate on that being,&amp;rsquo; shows Kāpeya, Abhipratārin, and the Brahmacārin to be connected with the Saṁvarga-vidyā.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/36/</guid>
      <description>On account of the reference to ceremonial purifications, and on account of the declaration of their absence. In sections the purport of which is to give instruction about Brahman the ceremony of initiation is referred to, &amp;lsquo;I will initiate you; he initiated him&amp;rsquo; (Kh. Up. IV, 4).
And at the same time the absence of such ceremonies in the case of Śūdras is stated: &amp;lsquo;In the Śūdra there is not any sin, and he is not fit for any ceremony&amp;rsquo; (Manu X, 126); and &amp;lsquo;The fourth caste is once born, and not fit for any ceremony&amp;rsquo; (Manu X, 4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/37/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the procedure, on the ascertainment of the non-being of that. That a Śūdra is not qualified for knowledge of Brahman appears from that fact also that as soon as Gautama has convinced himself that Jābāla, who wishes to become his pupil, is not a Śūdra, he proceeds to teach him the knowledge of Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/38/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the prohibition of hearing, studying, and performance of (Vedic) matter. The Śūdra is specially forbidden to hear and study the Veda and to perform the things enjoined in it. &amp;lsquo;For a Śūdra is like a cemetery, therefore the Veda must not be read in the vicinity of a Śūdra;&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Therefore the Śūdra is like a beast, unfit for sacrifices.&amp;rsquo; And he who does not hear the Veda recited cannot learn it so as to understand and perform what the Veda enjoins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/39/</guid>
      <description>And on account of Smr̥ti. Smr̥ti also declares this prohibition of hearing, and so on. &amp;lsquo;The ears of him who hears the Veda are to be filled with molten lead and lac; if he pronounces it his tongue is to be slit; if he preserves it his body is to be cut through.&amp;rsquo; And &amp;lsquo;He is not to teach him sacred duties or vows.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;It is thus a settled matter that the Śūdras are not qualified for meditations on Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/40/</guid>
      <description>On account of the trembling. In the part of the Kaṭḥa-Upanishad which intervenes between the passage &amp;lsquo;The Person of the size of a thumb
stands in the middle of the Self (II, 4, 12), and the passage &amp;lsquo;The Person of the size of a thumb, the inner Self&amp;rsquo; (II, 6, 17), we meet with the text &amp;lsquo;whatever there is, the whole world, when gone forth, trembles in its breath. A great terror, a raised thunderbolt; those who knew it became immortal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/41/</guid>
      <description>On account of light being seen (declared in the text). Between the two texts referring to the Person of the size of a thumb, there is a text declaring that to that Person there belongs light that obscures all other light, and is the cause and assistance of all other light; and such light is characteristic of Brahman only. &amp;lsquo;The sun does not shine there, nor the moon and the stars, nor these lightnings, and much less this fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/42/</guid>
      <description>The ether, on account of the designation of something different, and so on. We read in the Cḥāndogya. &amp;lsquo;The ether is the evolver of forms and names. That within which these forms and names are (or &amp;ldquo;that which is within&amp;ndash;or without&amp;ndash;these forms and names&amp;rdquo;) is Brahman, the Immortal, the Self&amp;rsquo; (VIII, 14). A doubt here arises whether the being here called ether be the released individual soul, or the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/43/</guid>
      <description>On account of difference in deep sleep and departing. We have to supply &amp;lsquo;on account of designation&amp;rsquo; from the preceding Sūtra. Because the text designates the highest Self as something different from the individual Self in the state of deep sleep as well as at the time of departure, the highest Self is thus different. For the Vājasaneyaka, after having introduced the individual Self in the passage &amp;lsquo;Who is that Self?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/3/44/</guid>
      <description>And on account of such words as Lord. That embracing highest Self is further on designated by terms such as Lord, and so on. &amp;lsquo;He is the Lord of all, the master of all, the ruler of all. He does not become greater by good works, nor smaller by evil works. He is the lord of all, the king of beings, the protector of beings. He is a bank and a boundary so that these worlds may not be confounded.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
