<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Three Jewels \(ratnatraya\) on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Three Jewels \(ratnatraya\) on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) The Jayākhyasaṃhitā, the Sātvatasaṃhitā, and the Pauṣkarasaṃhitā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/1_i_The_jayAkhyasaMhitA_the_sAtvatasaMhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/1_i_The_jayAkhyasaMhitA_the_sAtvatasaMhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Jayākhyasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (JS), the &lt;em&gt;Sātvatasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (SS), and the &lt;em&gt;Pauṣkarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (PauṣS) are assigned by modern scholars to the earliest stratum of extant Pāñcarātra scriptural literature. This earliest stratum has recently been enlarged with the discovery of several Pāñcarātra texts in Nepalese palm-leaf manuscripts. Four of these as yet unpublished works have been named by Alexis Sanderson (2009: 62 &lt;em&gt;ff&lt;/em&gt;) as the &lt;em&gt;Svāyambhuvapañcarātra&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Devāmṛtapañcarātra&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Vāsudevakalpa&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Mahālakṣmīsaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;Jayottaratantra&lt;/em&gt;.27&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) The three jewels</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/2_ii_The_three_jewels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/2_ii_The_three_jewels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;General introductions to the Pāñcarātra literature commonly emphasise the exalted status of the JS, SS and PauṣS as the so-called “three jewels” ( &lt;em&gt;ratnatraya&lt;/em&gt;) of the scriptural corpus.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; However, despite its ubiquity in oral traditions and in the secondary Indological literature, the claim that these three works are supreme in the Pāñcarātra canon is itself contained in only four of the 35 published Saṃhitās, namely the &lt;em&gt;Pārameśvarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Īśvarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Śrīpraśnasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, and a late, interpolated section of the JS entitled &lt;em&gt;Adhikaḥ Pāṭhaḥ&lt;/em&gt;. Further, as we will see below, only the latter among these works actually refers to the the JS, SS and PauṣS as the “three jewels”. Before proceeding to discuss ideas of textual hierarchy and canon in the Pāñcarātra literature in general, I will offer in this chapter a brief synopsis of the relevant passages from these four texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/3_iii_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/2_The_Three_Jewels_ratnatraya/3_iii_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The JS, SS and PauṣS appear to be the oldest of the published Pāñcarātra Saṃhitās, though I will argue below that each of these works most likely achieved their present form at a later date in South India. With the recent discovery of several early Pāñcarātra works in Nepalese palm-leaf manuscripts, we can be fairly certain, at any rate, that the JS, SS and PauṣS were not the earliest Pāñcarātra scriptures. Indeed, it is very likely that the scriptural literature of the Pāñcarātra is considerably older than the works which are currently available to us. A clue to this is contained in the &lt;em&gt;Brahmasūtrabhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; of Śaṅkara, generally assigned by modern scholars to the early eighth century (Suthren Hirst 2005: 13-26). In his comments on 2.2.45 (418.4-5), Śaṅkara quotes a statement which he believes shows the ‘Pañcarātra’ to be in conflict with the Veda. The statement reads “Not finding the supreme good in the four Vedas, Śāṇḍilya learnt this teaching” ( &lt;em&gt;caturṣu vedeṣu paraṃ śreyo ’labdhvā śāṇḍilya idaṃ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
