<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;रामानुज-नित्य-ग्रन्थः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;रामानुज-नित्य-ग्रन्थः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clooney</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/Clooney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/Clooney/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Rāmānuja’s Nityagrantham (“Manual of Daily Worship”): A Translation
Francis X. Clooney
0 Translator’s Preface Rāmānuja (1017–1137) was a philosopher and theologian; a saint and mystic, a lover of God; a proponent of the harmony of Tamil and Sanskrit traditions; and a premier leader of the South Indian Hindu Śrīvaiṣṇava community and a reformer of its ritual practices. Nine works are attributed to him:
Vedārtha-saṃgraha, on the right interpretation of the Upaniṣads and the right use of them in the theological and spiritual practice of the devotee; the Gītā-bhāṣya, commentary on the Bhagavad Gītā; the Śrī-bhāṣya, commentary on the Brahmasūtras; 4–5) the Vedānta-dīpā and the Vedāntasāra (summaries of Rāmānuja’s reading the Brahmasūtras); (6–8) three long prose prayers of surrender to Nārāyaṇa with the Goddess Śrī— surrender to God within oneself: Śaraṇāgati-gadya, surrender at the temple: Śrīraṅga-gadya, and surrender eschatologically, in heaven: Śrīvaikuṇṭha-gadya; and the Nitya-grantham or Nityam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रामभद्राचार्य-विवृतिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/rAmabhadrAchArya-vivRtiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/rAmabhadrAchArya-vivRtiH/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
0 भगवद्रामानुजाचार्यविरचितः
नित्यग्रन्थः
संस्कृत संशोधन संसत्
प्रधानसम्पादकः
डा. प्रो. भाष्यम् स्वामी, एम. ए. पिठेय्.डि., डि.लिट् निर्देशकः सहकार्यदर्शी च संस्कृत-संशोधन- संसत्, मेलुकोटे
Ack 1 My special thanks are due to the members of the Managing Committee for their support and the Government of Karnataka for their timely financial aid without which the Academy could not have undertaken such monumental works.
I am sure the edition will be well received by the Sanskrit Scholarly World and would be used as a useful guide in any oftheir related research activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>सर्व-प्रस्तुतिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/sarva-prastutiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/kriyA/rAmAnuja-nitya-granthaH/sarva-prastutiH/</guid>
      <description>विश्वास-टिप्पनी क्रियाचोदनम् एतावद् भावर्द्रम् अन्यस्य कस्यचनाचार्यस्य प्रसिद्धस्य वर्तते वा? न हि दृष्टम् एतावत् (गौडीयानां तु स्यात्)। यथा -
&amp;ldquo;मधुपर्कम् अवनतशिराः हर्षोत्फुल्लनयनः हृष्टमनाः भूत्वा प्रदाय&amp;rdquo; देव-वाम-पादाङ्गुष्ठ-नख-शीतांशु-मण्डलाद् गलद्-दिव्यामृत-रसैर् आत्मानम् अभिषिञ्चेत् । क्रियाविवरणान्य् अपि नितराम् भावभरितानि। न कस्माच्चन नाटकाज् जातुचिद् +हीनं तया दृष्ट्या।
FX Clooney - Notes I. The Purpose of the Nityam: The Daily Practice of the Person Who Has Already Taken Refuge
विश्वास-प्रस्तुतिः अथ परमैकान्तिनो+++(=विष्णु-पूजैक-चित्तस्य)+++ भगवद्-आराधन-प्रयोगं वक्ष्ये ।
FX Clooney I will now set forth (the performance of) the adoration of the Lord by the person single-mindedly focused on the Highest1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
