<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/04/</guid>
      <description>…
For we do not observe that in
pots and jars which are fashioned out of a lump of clay there persists the quality of &amp;lsquo;being a lump&amp;rsquo; which belongs to the causal substance. And should you say that it suffices that there should be equality in some or any attribute, we point out that such is actually the case with regard to Brahman and the world, both of which have the attribute of &amp;rsquo;existence&amp;rsquo; and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/05/</guid>
      <description>But (there is) denotation of the superintending (deities), on account of distinction and entering. The word &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; is meant to set aside the objection started. In texts such as &amp;rsquo;to him the earth said,&amp;rsquo; the terms &amp;rsquo;earth&amp;rsquo; and so on, denote the divinities presiding over earth and the rest.&amp;ndash;How is this known?&amp;ndash;&amp;rsquo; Through distinction and connexion.&amp;rsquo; For earth and so on are denoted by the distinctive term &amp;lsquo;divinities&amp;rsquo;; so e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/07/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that (the effect is) non-existing; we say no, there being a mere denial. But, an objection is raised, if Brahman, the cause, differs in nature from the effect, viz. the world, this means that cause and effect are separate things and that hence the effect does not exist in the cause, i.e. Brahman; and this again implies that the world originates from what has no existence!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/08/</guid>
      <description>On account of such consequences in reabsorption (the Vedānta-texts would be) inappropriate. The term &amp;lsquo;reabsorption&amp;rsquo; here stands as an instance of all the states of Brahman, reabsorption, creation, and so on&amp;ndash;among which it is the first as appears from the texts giving instruction about those several states &amp;lsquo;Being only was this in the beginning&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;The Self only was this in the beginning.&amp;rsquo; If we accept the doctrine of the oneness of substance of cause and effect, then, absorption, creation, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/09/</guid>
      <description>Not so; as there are parallel instances. The teaching of the Vedānta-texts is not inappropriate, since there are instances of good and bad qualities being separate in the case of one thing connected with two
different states. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; in the Sūtra indicates the impossibility of Brahman being connected with even a shadow of what is evil. The meaning is as follows. As Brahman has all sentient and non-sentient things for its body, and constitutes the Self of that body, there is nothing contrary to reason in Brahman being connected with two states, a causal and an effected one, the essential characteristics of which are expansion on the one hand and contraction on the other; for this expansion and contraction belong (not to Brahman itself, but) to the sentient and non-sentient beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/10/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the objections to his view. The theory of Brahman being the universal cause has to be accepted not only because it is itself free from objections, but also because the pradhāna theory is open to objections, and hence must be abandoned. For on this latter theory the origination of the world cannot be accounted for. The Sānkhyas hold that owing to the soul&amp;rsquo;s approximation to Prakr̥ti the attributes of the latter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/11/</guid>
      <description>Also in consequence of the ill-foundedness of reasoning. The theory, resting on Scripture, of Brahman being the universal cause must be accepted, and the theory of the Pradhāna must be abandoned, because all (mere) reasoning is ill-founded. This latter point is proved by the fact that the arguments set forth by Buddha, Kaṇāda, Akshapāda, Jina, Kapila and Patañjali respectively are all mutually contradictory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/12/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that inference is to be carried on in a different way; (we reply that) thus also it follows that (the objection raised) is not got rid of. Let us then view the matter as follows. The arguments actually set forth by Buddha and others may have to be considered as invalid, but all the same we may arrive at the Pradhāna theory through other lines of reasoning by which</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/13/</guid>
      <description>Thereby also the remaining (theories) which are not comprised (within the Veda) are explained. Not comprised means those theories which are not known to be comprised within (countenanced by) the Veda. The Sūtra means to say that by the demolition given above of the Sānkhya doctrine which is not comprised within the Veda the remaining theories which are in the same position, viz. the theories of Kaṇāda, Akshapāda, Jina, and Buddha, must likewise be considered as demolished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/14/</guid>
      <description>If it be said that from (Brahman) becoming an enjoyer, there follows non-distinction (of Brahman and the individual soul); we reply&amp;ndash;it may be as in ordinary life. The Sānkhya here comes forward with a new objection. You maintain, he says, that the highest Brahman has the character either of a cause or an effect according as it has for its body sentient and non-sentient beings in either their subtle or gross state; and that this explains the difference in nature between the individual soul and Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/15/</guid>
      <description>The non-difference (of the world) from that (viz. Brahman) follows from what begins with the word ārambhana. Under II, 1, 7 and other Sūtras the non-difference of the effect, i.e. the world from the cause, i.e. Brahman was assumed, and it was on this basis that the proof of Brahman being the cause of the world proceeded. The present Sūtra now raises a primā facie objection against that very non-difference, and then proceeds to refute it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/16/</guid>
      <description>And because (the cause) is perceived in the existence of the effect. This means&amp;ndash;because gold which is the cause is perceived in the existence of its effects, such as earrings and the like; i.e. on account of the recognition of gold which expresses itself in the judgment &amp;rsquo;this earring is gold.&amp;rsquo; We do not on the other hand perceive the presence of clay, and so on, in gold, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/17/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the existence of that which is posterior. On account of the existence of the posterior, i.e. the effect existing in the cause&amp;ndash;for this reason also the effect is non-different from the cause. For in ordinary language as well as in the Veda the effect is spoken of in terms of the cause; as when we say, &amp;lsquo;all these things&amp;ndash;jars, platters, &amp;amp;c.&amp;ndash;were clay only this morning&amp;rsquo;; or when the Veda says, &amp;lsquo;Being only was this in the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/19/</guid>
      <description>And like a piece of cloth. As threads when joined in a peculiar cross-arrangement are called a piece of cloth, thus acquiring a new name, a new form, and new functions, so it is with Brahman also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/20/</guid>
      <description>And as the different vital airs. As the one air, according as it undergoes in the body
different modifications, acquires a new name, new characteristics, and new functions, being then called prāṇa, apāna, and so on; thus the one Brahman becomes the world, with its manifold moving and non-moving beings.&amp;ndash;The non-difference of the world from Brahman, the highest cause, is thus fully established.
Here terminates the &amp;lsquo;ārambhaṇa&amp;rsquo; adhikaraṇa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/21/</guid>
      <description>From the designation of the &amp;lsquo;other&amp;rsquo; (as non-different from Brahman) there result (Brahman&amp;rsquo;s) not creating what is beneficial, and other imperfections. &amp;lsquo;Thou art that&amp;rsquo;; &amp;rsquo;this Self is Brahman&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;these and similar texts which declare the non-difference of the world from Brahman, teach, as has been said before, at the same time the non-difference from Brahman of the individual soul also. But an objection here presents itself. If these texts really imply that the &amp;lsquo;other one,&amp;rsquo; i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/22/</guid>
      <description>But (Brahman is) additional, on account of the declaration of difference. The word &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; sets aside the primā facie view. To the individual soul capable of connexion with the various kinds of pain there is additional, i.e. from it there is different, Brahman.&amp;ndash;On what ground?&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Owing to the declaration of difference.&amp;rsquo; For Brahman is spoken of as different from the soul in the following texts:&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;He who dwells in the Self and within the Self, whom the Self does not know, of whom the Self is the body, who rules the Self within, he is thy Self, the ruler within, the immortal&amp;rsquo; (Br̥.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/23/</guid>
      <description>And as in the analogous case of stones and the like, there is impossibility of that. In the same way as it is impossible that the different non-sentient things such as stones, iron, wood, herbs, &amp;amp;c., which are of an extremely low constitution and subject to constant change, should be one in nature with Brahman, which is faultless, changeless, fundamentally antagonistic to all that is evil, &amp;amp;c. &amp;amp;c.; so it is also impossible that the individual soul, which is liable to endless suffering, and a mere wretched glowworm as it were, should be one with Brahman who, as we know from the texts, comprises within himself the treasure of all auspicious qualities, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/24/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that (it is) not, on account of the observation of employment; we say, not so; for as in the case of milk. We have so far determined that it is in no way unreasonable to hold that the highest Brahman, which is all-knowing, capable of realising its purposes, &amp;amp;c., has all beings, sentient and non-sentient, for its body, and hence constitutes the Self of all and differs in nature from everything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/25/</guid>
      <description>And as in the case of the gods and so on, in (their) world. As the gods and similar exalted beings create, each in his own world, whatever they require by their mere volition, so the Supreme Person creates by his mere volition the entire world. That the gods about whose powers we know from the Veda only (not through perception) are here quoted as supplying a proving instance, is done in order to facilitate the comprehension of the creative power of Brahman, which</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/26/</guid>
      <description>Or the consequence of the entire (Brahman entering into the effect), and stultification of (Brahman&amp;rsquo;s) being devoid of parts. &amp;lsquo;Being only was this in the beginning&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;This indeed was in the beginning not anything&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;The Self alone indeed was this in ihe beginning&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;these and other texts state that in the beginning Brahman was one only, i.e. without parts&amp;ndash;that means: Brahman, in its causal state, was without parts because then all distinction of matter and souls had disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/27/</guid>
      <description>But on account of Scripture; (Brahman&amp;rsquo;s possession of various powers) being founded upon the word. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; sets aside the difficulty raised. There is no
inappropriateness; &amp;lsquo;on account of Scripture.&amp;rsquo; Scripture declares on the one hand that Brahman is not made up of parts, and on the other that from it a multiform creation proceeds. And in matters vouched for by Scripture we must conform our ideas to what Scripture actually says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/28/</guid>
      <description>And thus in the Self; for (there are) manifold (powers). If attributes belonging to one thing were on that account to be ascribed to other things also, it would follow that attributes observed in non-sentient things, such as jars and the like, belong also to the intelligent eternal Self, which is of an altogether different kind. But that such attributes do not extend to the Self is due to the variety of the essential nature of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/29/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the defects of his view also. On his view, i.e. on the view of him who holds the theory of the Pradhāna or something similar, the imperfections observed in ordinary things would attach themselves to the Pradhāna also, since it does not differ in nature from those things. The legitimate conclusion therefore is that Brahman only which differs in nature from all other things can be held to be the general cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/30/</guid>
      <description>And (the divinity is) endowed with all powers, because that is seen. The highest divinity which is different in nature from all other things is endowed with all powers; for scriptural texts show it to be such, &amp;lsquo;His high power is revealed as manifold, as essential, and so his knowledge, force, and action&amp;rsquo; (Śvet. Up. VI, 8). In the same way another text first declares the highest divinity to differ in nature from everything else, &amp;lsquo;Free from sin, from old age, from death and grief, from hunger and thirst&amp;rsquo;,and then goes on to represent it as endowed with all powers, &amp;lsquo;realising all its wishes, realising all its intentions&amp;rsquo;,&amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/31/</guid>
      <description>Not, on account of the absence of organs; this has been explained (before). Although the one Brahman is different from all other beings and endowed with all powers, we yet infer from the text &amp;lsquo;Of him there is known no effect and no instrument,&amp;rsquo; that as it is destitute of instruments it cannot produce any effect.&amp;ndash;To this objection an answer has already been given in II, 1, 27; 28, &amp;lsquo;on account of its being founded on the word,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;for there are manifold (powers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/32/</guid>
      <description>(Brahman is) not (the cause); on account of (the world) having the nature of what depends on a motive. Although the Lord, who before creation is alone, is endowed with all kinds of powers since he differs in nature
from all other beings, and hence is by himself capable of creating the world; we all the same cannot ascribe to him actual causality with regard to the world; for this manifold world displays the nature of a thing depending on a motive, and the Lord has no motive to urge him to creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/33/</guid>
      <description>But (it is) mere sport, as in ordinary life. The motive which prompts Brahman&amp;ndash;all whose wishes are fulfilled and who is perfect in himself&amp;ndash;to the creation of a world comprising all kinds of sentient and non-sentient beings dependent on his volition, is nothing else but sport, play. We see in ordinary life how some great king, ruling this earth with its seven dvīpas, and possessing perfect strength, valour, and so on, has a game at balls, or the like, from no other motive than to amuse himself; hence there is no objection to the view that sport only is the motive prompting Brahman to the creation, sustentation, and destruction of this world which is easily fashioned by his mere will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/34/</guid>
      <description>Not inequality and cruelty, on account of there being regard; for so (Scripture) declares. It must indeed be admitted that the Lord, who differs in nature from all other beings, intelligent and non-intelligent,
and hence possesses powers unfathomable by thought, is capable of creating this manifold world, although before creation he is one only and without parts. But the assumption of his having actually created the world would lay him open to the charge of partiality, in so far as the world contains beings of high, middle, and low station&amp;ndash;gods, men, animals, immovable beings; and to that of cruelty, in so far as he would be instrumental in making his creatures experience pain of the most dreadful kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/35/</guid>
      <description>If it be said &amp;rsquo;not so, on account of non-distinction of deeds&amp;rsquo;; we say, &amp;rsquo;not so, on account of beginninglessness&amp;rsquo;; this is reasonable, and it is also observed. But before creation the individual souls do not exist; since Scripture teaches non-distinction &amp;lsquo;Being only this was in the beginning.&amp;rsquo; And as then the souls do not exist, no karman can exist, and it cannot therefore be said that the inequality of creation depends on karman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/2/1/36/</guid>
      <description>And because all the attributes are proved (to be present in Brahman). As all those attributes required to constitute causality which have been or will be shown to be absent in the Pradhāna, the atoms, and so on, can be shown to be present in Brahman, it remains a settled conclusion that Brahman only is the cause of the world. Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;that which has the nature of depending on a motive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
