<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Goudriaan on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/kAshyapaH/goudriaan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Goudriaan on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/kAshyapaH/goudriaan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JÑĀNAKĀṆDAḤ</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/kAshyapaH/goudriaan/jnAna-kANDa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/kAshyapaH/goudriaan/jnAna-kANDa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-w-caland-over-het-vaikhānasasūtra-med-der-kon-ak-v-wet-afd-lett-deel-61-serie-a-no-8-amsterdam-1926-pp-1-ff-the-same-on-the-sacred-books-of-the-vaikhānasas-med-etc-deel-65-serie-a-no-7-1928-pp-4ff-the-same-preface-to-the-ed-of-vkhśrs-calcutta-1941-pp-xiv-xxvff&#34;&gt;KASYAPA&amp;rsquo;S BOOK OF WISDOM&#xA;(KĀŚYAPA-JÑĀNAKĀṆDAḤ)&#xA;DISPUTATIONES&#xA;RHENO-TRAJECTINAE&#xA;DISPUTATIONES INSTITUTI AD LINGUAS&#xA;ORIENTALES&#xA;DOCENDAS ATQUE INVESTIGANDAS&#xA;IN UNIVERSITATE RHENO-TRAJECTINA&#xA;CONDITI&#xA;EDIDIT&#xA;J. GONDA&#xA;X&#xA;1965&#xA;MOUTON &amp;amp; CO.&#xA;LONDON THE HAGUE PARIS&#xA;·&#xA;KĀŚYAPA&amp;rsquo;S&#xA;BOOK OF WISDOM&#xA;(KĀŚYAPA-JÑĀNAKĀNDAH)&#xA;A RITUAL HANDBOOK OF THE VAIKHĀNASAS&#xA;translated and annotated&#xA;by&#xA;T. GOUDRIAAN&#xA;1965&#xA;MOUTON &amp;amp; CO.&#xA;LONDON THE HAGUE PARIS&#xA;·&#xA;© 1965 Mouton &amp;amp; Co., Publishers, The Hague, The Netherlands.&#xA;No part of this book may be translated or reproduced in any form, by print, photoprint, microfilm, or any other means, without written&#xA;permission from the publishers.&#xA;PROEFSCHRIFT UTRECHT 1965&#xA;LIBRARY OF CONGRESS CATALOG CARD NUMBER: 65-28166&#xA;Printed in The Netherlands&#xA;Introduction.&#xA;Abbreviations.&#xA;CONTENTS&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, Proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;·&#xA;.&#xA;7&#xA;16&#xA;21&#xA;Appendix 1. List of Mantras recorded in the Kāśyapa-Jñānakāṇḍdaḥ 313&#xA;Appendix 2. Plants and trees in the Kasyapa-Jñānakāṇḍaḥ&#xA;328&#xA;Appendix 3. Linguistic peculiarities of the text&#xA;·&#xA;336&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;The Kasyapa-Jñānakāṇḍa is not, as one might infer from the title, some philosophical work, but one of the ritual handbooks of the Vaikhānasas. According to tradition, its mythical author, the ancient seer Kasyapa, wrote also two other volumes, called Satyakāṇḍa and Tarkakāṇḍa, which are not available any more (cf. the Sanskrit Introduction of the editor of the text, R. Parthasarathi Bhattachar(ya), p. 1); together, these works formed the Kasyapa-Samhita (a name which is in vogue also for the Jñānakāṇḍa only).&#xA;The Vişnuite Vaikhānasa sect, at home in the S. of India, has a tradi- tion which reaches back to the ancient period of Vedic ritualism, when the Vaikhanasa school with its texts formed a part of the Taittiriya branch of the Black Yajurveda.1 In the later, medieval Hinduistic, period, the Vaikhānasas transformed themselves gradually into an orthodox sect of devout Visņu worshippers, standing out against other groups, mainly the Pañcarātrins, by their maintenance of Vedic traditions, although they are fully in concordance with their contemporaries, Vişnuites as well as Śivaites, in their practices of image and temple worship, pūjā, festivals, etc. They even held a prominent place as temple priests, and, although the Vaikhanasa mode of worship was opposed by Rāmānuja in the first part of the twelfth century, they perform temple worship&#xA;2&#xA;1 W. Caland, Over het Vaikhānasasūtra, Med. der Kon. Ak. v. Wet., Afd. Lett., Deel 61, Serie A, No. 8 (Amsterdam, 1926), pp. 1 ff.; the same, On the sacred books of the Vaikhānasas, Med. etc., Deel 65, Serie A, No. 7, 1928, pp. 4ff.; the same, Preface to the ed. of VkhŚrS. (Calcutta, 1941), pp. XIV, XXVff.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;l3-transcript-of-a-ms-present-in-the-same-library-under-the-number-r-1838-it-is-also-written-in-grantha-characters-and-comprises-the-chs-22-49-it-begins-in-the-first-part-of-ch-22-with--di-nivedya-prokṣayitvā-words-which-are-found-in-the-edited-text-on-p-33-1-9-remarkably-l1-shows-exactly-at-the-same-place-some-pages-of-blank-space-after-mṛṣṭaya--vasatṛṇajalā--after-which-the-first-words-of-l3-come-immediately-after-these-pages-another-hand-continues-the-writing-without-a-lacuna-in-the-text-besides-the-editor-informs-us-of-the-fact-that-in-the-ms-cha-the-chapters-22-49-are-missing-there-are-thus-good-grounds-for-the-assump--tion-that-the-scribe-of-l1-continued-at-this-place-with-l3-which-is-without-doubt-identical-with-the-lost-part-of-cha-while-the-scribe-of-cha-continued-with-l1-i-have-no-explanation-for-the-fact-that-cha-contrary-to-the-editors-assertion-has-been-cited-repeatedly-in-the-chs-31-ff-l3-ends-at-the-end-of-ch-49&#34;&gt;2 Cf. ch. 105; Skt. Introduction by the editor of the text, pp. 7ff.; Eggers, Dharmasutra, p. 16. Yet, there is some Tantric influence in the text (see, e.g., ch. 5, n. 16; ch. 16, n. 13; ch. 106), although in no way so much as in Pañcarātra Samhitas; this Tantric element has increased in later works as the AKh. (see the introduction to ch. 69).&#xA;Eggers, o.c., p. 15. According to Aiyangar, History, I, pp. 288ff., however, Rāmānuja did his best to restore worship in Tirupati according to the Vaikhānasa method, after a temporary Śivaite occupation of the sanctuary.&#xA;3&#xA;8&#xA;Introduction&#xA;even up to the present day in some important S. Indian sanctuaries.4 Their handbooks (in the first place, Marīci&amp;rsquo;s Vimānārcanakalpa or Vaikhānasagama) had authority in matters of temple architecture, iconography, and ritual prescriptions for temple priests. The Vaikhana- sas insist on the fact that their temple worship is nothing but a continua- tion of the Vedic fire-sacrifice.5 Beside temple worship, oblations are offered into the fire in the Vedic way (see, e.g., chs. 44 and 62). In this respect, the prescriptions of the Vaikhānasagṛhyasūtra (VkhS.) remained decisive.&#xA;The Vaikhānasa religion is highly practical. Worship has its effects in this life and hereafter, as is asserted by the author in several places, e.g. in ch. 105; the performer of devoted worship will enjoy success in all respects in earthly life, and reach heaven and communion with Viṣṇu after his death. As in the Veda the desires, in view of which the rituals are performed, are stereotyped: a long life, offspring, social eminence, destruction of the adversary, etc. Vişņu is the origin and maintainer of life and fertility in all its manifestations; sattva or lucid qualities exist by his grace, while rajas or active qualities exist by Śiva&amp;rsquo;s grace (ch. 17). Yet, we find also many signs of the ambivalent nature of even this favourable divine power: every part of the ritual is to be handled very carefully, the image is to be made exactly according to the prescriptions, etc.; if not, dreadful things await the performer (death of the sacrificer, end of ch. 21; death of children, ch. 42; etc.). In case of severe negligence, Vişņu&amp;rsquo;s wrath is to be averted (e.g., in ch. 99).&#xA;Viṣṇu is the cause of the cosmic life-process by means of the activity of Śrī, the individual manifestation of Primeval Nature (see ch. 38). Cosmic evolution is at the same time symbolized by the Fivefold Mani- festation, a special feature of Vaikhānasa cosmology and worship (see ch. 77, introduction). Other remarks of a more or less philosophical&#xA;4 Eggers, Dharmasūtra, p. 15; Rangachari, S.V.B., pp. 99f.; Pandit Parthasarathi Iyangar, cited by Caland in VkhŚrS., p. XXX; Inde Class. I, p. 641; Diehl, Instr. and Purp., p. 44.&#xA;5&#xA;Cf., e.g., ch. 1, n. 9; Gonda, R. Ind., I, p. 328; the same, Het probleem der conti- nuïteit in de oudere Indische geschiedenis, Med. der Kon. Ned. Ak. v. Wet., N.R., Deel 26, No. 6 (Amsterdam, 1963), pp. 8f.&#xA;6&#xA;Devotion is indispensable element. In ch. 1, e.g., it is said: śraddhābhaktiyutasyaiva sarvasamsiddhiḥ &amp;ldquo;only one who possesses faith and devotion has success in all respects&amp;rdquo;. - In the last part of ch. 20, and in ch. 68, säyujyam &amp;ldquo;communion&amp;rdquo; with Vişņu is promised; repeatedly, we find the assertion that Vaikhānasa worship is aihikāmușmi- kapradam &amp;ldquo;granting results in this and the after world&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;7 See, e.g., ch. 16; ch. 90, n. 2; compare also Gonda, Aspects, pp. 11 ff.; 233; 236; in the RV., Visnu is already a giver of success in earthly things, as appears i.a. from RV. 8,68,12: uru ņas tanue tana uru kṣayāya nas kṛdhifuru no yandhi jivase.&#xA;Introduction&#xA;9&#xA;character are found in this work in the chs. 1, 24, 35, 50, 55, 68 (nature of Viṣṇu); 17, 20 (importance of worship and devotion). In ch. 55, an interesting remark is made about the relation of the terms Visņu and Nārāyaṇa; see n. 2 on that chapter.&#xA;Not much is known about the history of the Vaikhānasa sect and its opinions and practices. While the VkhS. has attracted attention by means of Prof. Caland&amp;rsquo;s edition and translation,8 the later works have been neglected. Often, faulty statements about the Vaikhanasas were made.9 Vaikhānasa tradition itself traces its history back to Vikhanas as its mythical founder. He received his knowledge from Brahma and handed it over to the nine primeval Seers, or sons of Brahma,10 but especially to four of them, viz. Bhṛgu, Marīci, Atri, and Kāśyapa;11 they composed the ritual handbooks (samhitas) of the sect. We must consider their names as standing for schools differring in details: in the extant works, they appear to quote each other, so that no decision can be made about chronological precedence. These references are obviously made to traditions, more than to individual authors.&#xA;Thus, the name Kāśyapa also stands for a school of ritual doctrines, although the author is, throughout the work, referred to as being one&#xA;person.&#xA;.12 It is difficult to make definite statements about the time and&#xA;8 VkhS., VkhS.C. (see the list of Abbreviations). Cf. also n. 1.&#xA;9&#xA;Contributions to our knowledge about the Vaikhānasas were made especially by: Th. Bloch, Über das Grhya- und Dharmasūtra der Vaikhānasas (Leipzig, 1886); Farquhar, Outline of the religious literature of India (Oxford, 1920), pp. 181 ff.; 321; Eggers, Dharmasūtra; Caland (cf. notes 1 and 8); Gonda, Aspects, pp. 234ff.; H. D. Smith, in his edition of PadmaS.Kr. Some Vaikhānasa works were edited in the Vaikhānasagranthamālā, published in Telugu characters (Caland, Sacred books, pp. 2f.). VkhS., VkhS.C., VkhŚrS., Atri, Kasyapa, and Marici, have been published by other authorities.&#xA;10 Marïci, Vimānārcanakalpa, according to Eggers, o.t., p. 17. This is found in ch. 96 of Marici&amp;rsquo;s work, but in ch. 97 it is said that the Vaikhānasa doctrine was told by Vişņu.&#xA;11&#xA;Marici, Anandasamhita, according to Caland, Sacred books, p. 4. Bhrgu, how- ever (cf. Eggers, Dharmasūtra, p. 17), mentions Angiras instead of Marici as one of the four main seers and authors of Samhitas, and we find Angiras quoted indeed four times in the text, while no trace of Marici&amp;rsquo;s name is found. Three of these four quo- tations are about details of iconography, a subject in which Marici and his school were proficient. Thus there is some evidence for the assumption that the names of Angiras and Marici stand for the same school. The quotations from Angiras are not found in Marici&amp;rsquo;s Vaikhānasagama, but that is not decisive, because this text represents only a part, written down at a certain time, of the Marici-Samhita. Each school possessed more than one text and each text may have been modified in the course of time. Moreover, Angiras and Marīci are identified in Marici, p. 202.&#xA;12&#xA;The name is written variously as Kasyapa and Kasyapa; the last form is found throughout the text. - - That more than one person was active in shaping the text as it&#xA;—&#xA;10&#xA;Introduction&#xA;place of this author. In any case, he is posterior to the VkhS. (dated about 400 A.D. by Caland, VkhS.C., pp. XV f.).13 We will not be far off the mark, if we place him in one of the two last centuries of the first millennium of our era. Uncertainty also exists about the exact geo- graphical position of the author. The most important centre of Vaikhā- nasa worship during his time was probably Tirupati, but in the work itself&#xA;has come down to us, appears from several facts. Thus, ch. 37 is divisible into two portions, the second of which is clearly a later addition. There are contradictions in the iconographical prescriptions in the chs. 34-37 and 77ff. (see ch. 77, notes 10, 13, 17, and 18); also the fact that some subjects have been handled twice, at first succinctly and later with greater elaboration, points in the same direction. In ch. 72, the japå and kokamāli are mentioned both as auspicious and as inauspicious flowers. The meas- urements of the fire-hearths in the chs. 44 and 62 are not always exactly identical: see ch. 62, n. 4. The discussion of the formula of eight syllables in the chs. 106ff. makes the impression of a kind of appendix, which has been added later; the work of Atri does not contain similar prescriptions for meditation. On the other side, there are many factors (such as the unity in style) which point to the unity of the work, and thus we can safely assume that the bulk of it has been composed by one person. 13 The best way for finding some chronological clues is to consider the architectural and iconographic data offered by the text. The temple described in ch. 31 is of a simple character; no stress has been laid upon construction or adornment of gateways and front-halls, which became so important during the time of the Pandya rulers and later (from about 1100 A.D. on, according to Jouveau-Dubreuil, Arch. I, pp. 56ff.). Both gateway and front-hall are mentioned (resp. in chs. 39 and 77), but this is no reason for dating the work later than 1000 A.D. (Kramrisch, p. 244). Some other details of the ornamentation of the temple remind one of the features of the Pallava and Cola styles of about 700-1000 A.D. (see ch. 32, notes 6, 8, 11, 15). The conch and disk as described at the end of ch. 52 have a relatively simple shape, but no certain chronolog- ical conclusions can be drawn from this; see notes 13 and 14. About the crown: ch. 52, n. 1. No kirtimukha is prescribed on top of the halo, as was done in later times, e.g. in the epoch of Vijayanagar (Banerjea, Icon., p. 298). The fact that images of Rāma and Kṛṣṇa are discussed (in chs. 37, 82, and 83) would be a clue for dating the author not earlier than the twelfth century if the statements of Jouveau-Dubreuil o.c., II, p. 73, on this point are followed; but we may doubt their correctness (see ch. 82, n. 4; ch. 83, n. 4). Instead, the large amount of space devoted to the older incarnations Boar, Man-Lion, and Dwarf, point to a time which lies before 1000 A.D., a period, during which images of these figures were most popular (Rao, Icon., I, 1, p. 39). The author shows his independence from the important handbook of Marici, which is dated in the eight century by Kramrisch, p. 261; Banerjea, Icon., p. 26; does this mean that Kasyapa is even earlier? In many cases, his treatment gives indeed the impression of being older; but he has taken architectural data from the Mayamata (see ch. 31), and this text is said to be an abridgement of the Manasara (P. K. Acharya, Architecture of Mānasāra, Mānasara Ser. IV, Allahabad, 1934). The Manasara has been dated dif- ferently in the fifth (Acharya) and the twelfth century A.D. Although it is not easy to find congruence in all these data, a period which lies between 800 and 1000 A.D. seems the most probable for the author&amp;rsquo;s life-time.&#xA;The fact that no mention is made of the Alvārs and other religious teachers can be no argument for dating, because the Vaikhānasas do not worship them even now (K. A. Nilakanta Sastri, Development of Religion in South India, Orient Longmans, Bombay etc., 1963, p. 67).Introduction&#xA;11&#xA;there are no hints of that place. The dedication above the first page of the text: om namo venkatesvaraya (Venkateśvara = the Visņu wor- shipped at Tirupati), has probably been added later. The image of Harisankara, which was the main image at Tirupati,14 is mentioned, but has by no means a prominent place in the work. In any case, the author must be located in the Tamil or Telugu country, the regions where the Vaikhanasas are represented up to the present time.&#xA;As to the divisions of the work, they agree in the main with those of other samhitās or agamas, in any case with respect to the description of temple worship: the preparatory ploughing on the future temple site, preceded by the inspection of that site (chs. 11-13, 16, 20-22); the provi- sory construction of a miniature temple (in chs. 23-25); collection of materials (chs. 27-29); construction of the temple (chs. 30-33); construc- tion of images (chs. 40-57); consecration of images (chs. 59-68), preceded by the ankurāṛpaṇa (ch. 58); daily worship in the temple (chs. 69 and 70); details about elements of daily worship (chs. 71-76); details about consecration and worship of the divine Manifestations and Incarnations, accompanied by other divinities (chs. 77-85; more concisely already in chs. 34-39); the bathing ceremony (chs. 85-87); the festival (chs. 88-90); corrections (chs. 92-103). A few more subjects are treated in the last five chapters. Besides, chs. 2 and 3 give a description of the world; chs. 4 and 10 a classification of good and evil objects; chs. 5-8 discuss the lotus- fire; in chs. 11-19, data for the construction of houses and villages (chs. 14, 15) are included. For further data about all these parts of the work, the reader is referred to the introductions to the respective chapters.&#xA;More than once, Kāśyapa shows a position which is independent of other schools, e.g. in the discussion of the measures of the image in ch. 50. He is very accurate in recording formulas (see ch. 1, n. 1, and Ap- pendix 1).15 He records, or is elaborating about, some interesting rites&#xA;14 Aiyangar, History, I, pp. 56ff.&#xA;15&#xA;Most of the formulas given in the text by pratika are found in full in the VkhSamh., books (praśna-) 5-8. Many of them are, as far as I know, not recorded elsewhere. Prof. Caland, who studied the VkhSamh., but was not yet acquainted with the Kasyapa- Jñānakāṇḍa, said about praśna 5-8 (VkhS.C., p. XI): &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; their purpose is not in every respect apparent, but a part at least apparently contains the mantras for a certain Vişņupūjā, called arcanakhanda, which must belong to the Vaikhānasīyas; it is attrib- uted, however, to the Rşi Kasyapa&amp;rdquo;. Elsewhere, Prof. Caland cited two formulas from VkhSamh. 5; they are found pratikena in the text, ch. 22, and this led me to the supposition that the praśnas 5-8 were intended to accompany the complete kriyā ritual according to the Kasyapa-Jñānakāṇḍa. This supposition was confirmed, when the VkhSamh. itself became at last accessible to me, thanks to the cooperation of the India Office Library in London. Unfortunately, this was not before the ms. of my&#xA;12&#xA;Introduction&#xA;or theories which are not, or only in a scanty manner, dealt with in the related handbooks: the description of the world in chs. 2 and 3; the worship of the lotus-fire for obtaining all kinds of desires (chs. 5-8); em- phasis on omina and their appeasement (chs. 7, 9, 13, 22, 26, 28, 105, etc.); a very interesting description of the deposit of the &amp;ldquo;embryo&amp;rdquo; into the ground of the site destined for a house, village, or temple (ch. 16); detailed discussion of the preparatory ploughing and the ceremony of the &amp;ldquo;lotus of Brahmā&amp;rdquo; (ch. 22); the enumeration of the deities of the wood in ch. 27; the preparation of the clay for the image with the help of various fragrant materials (chs. 47-49); a nice and elaborate descrip- tion of the consecration of the new image (chs. 59-68), during which, i.a., meditation on the Highest Self (paramātmā) in ch. 65; the sacrifice of a bull of grains as a means for appeasement (ch. 99). Many names of plants and trees are recorded, together with their use in the ritual (see Appendix 2). Other special features of the work have been noted by the editor of the text in his Sanskrit introduction, pp. 10f.16 Thus, the text contains many interesting elements, not only in the field of South Indian religion, social system, and economy, but also from the point of view of the comparative study of religion in general. Often we come across elements which are known to Europeans from their own folklore and traditions. The positive judgment of H. D. Smith, PādmaS. Kr., p. 193, is thus not out of place, although we must say, that the author is not always as detailed and lucid in his descriptions as Mr. Smith suggests.&#xA;On the other hand, the author does not hesitate to record his borrow- ings from others, mostly not mentioned by name.17 Kasyapa was not without influence, as may be inferred from the commentaries and later monographs written according to his prescriptions for daily worship (see the introduction to ch. 69).&#xA;thesis had gone to the printers, and I must excuse myself for not having been able to make full use of the data contained in these formulas.&#xA;16&#xA;About linguistic peculiarities, see Appendix 3.&#xA;17 The following quotations by name are found in the text: Vaikhānasasūtra (passim); Bhrgu (ten times, in chs. 23, 34, 39, 39, 41, 58, 62, 69, 87, 98; usually not found in Bhṛgu&amp;rsquo;s Yajñādhikāra, and probably referring to other works of that author; only the note from ch. 58, about sadyo &amp;rsquo;nkuram, was found in Bhṛgu 22, 48f., although not with the same words); Angiras (four times, chs. 36, 41, 50, 98); Atreya (ch. 42); Atri (ch. 63, found in Atri&amp;rsquo;s work); Puruşa (probably; see ch. 56, n. 2); Vyasa (ch. 91); Dvaipayana (ch. 108); Brahmā (one time). Further, quotations from anonymous authorities: kecit (26 times); eke (7 times); anye (3 times); apare (one time); brahmavādinaḥ (two times); brahmavidaḥ, brahmavettāraḥ, tattvadarsinaḥ, sutra-, tantra-, brāhmaṇam, paurāņika-, sarve, ācāryāḥ, vidyādharāḥ, nāgāḥ, manuşyāḥ (each one time; the last three in ch. 108). A comparative study of Vaikhānasa and other ritual works could probably throw much light on the various standpoints and mutual influences.&#xA;Introduction&#xA;13&#xA;The Sanskrit text has been edited by R. Pārthasarathi Bhattachar(ya) as No. 12 of the Sri Venkateśvara Oriental Series, Tirupati 1948, from a number of 12 mss., with critical notes under each page. These mss. were divided by the editor into four groups: A, comprising the mss. ka, ka-1, gha, and ca; B, comprising the mss. kha, ga, cha, ja, and jha; a group, consisting of the mss. ta and ta-1; and a source called ma, M, or mukhapatram. Despite this relatively great number of mss., the text still shows many difficult readings. At the suggestion of my promoter, Prof, Gonda, I consulted copies of a few other mss., kindly delivered to me by the Government Oriental Mss. Library and the Adyar Library, both in Madras. They appeared to be very closely related to each other, and thus were combined into one group called L:&#xA;L1: Microfilm obtained from the Adyar Library of a ms. present there as no. TR 548. The ms. is written on paper, with 15-17 lines on each page. It is complete in 108 adhyāyas, but has a number of lacunas. It is probably identical with the original, from which kha was transcribed; according to the editor, this original was found in the Adyar Library, and in places where kha has been cited in the critical notes, its readings are usually identical with those of L1. In many cases, where L1 gives a good reading, the ms. kha has apparently not been consulted by the editor.&#xA;L2: Transcript of a ms. existing in the Government Oriental Mss. Library at Madras, under the number R 1446. It is written in Grantha characters, and contains only the chapters 1-19. In ch. 19, it ends with the words ete ca pūjitā yasya. It is very closely related to L1, but has not been copied from it, because it contains some words, which have been omitted in L1.&#xA;L3: Transcript of a ms. present in the same Library under the number R 1838. It is also written in Grantha characters, and comprises the chs. 22-49. It begins in the first part of ch. 22 with: -di nivedya prokṣayitvā, words which are found in the edited text on p. 33, 1. 9. Remarkably, L1 shows exactly at the same place some pages of blank space after: mṛṣṭaya- vasatṛṇajalā- (after which the first words of L3 come immediately); after these pages, another hand continues the writing without a lacuna in the text. Besides, the editor informs us of the fact, that in the ms. cha the chapters 22-49 are missing. There are thus good grounds for the assump- tion, that the scribe of L1 continued at this place with L3, which is without doubt identical with the lost part of cha, while the scribe of cha continued with L1. I have no explanation for the fact that cha, contrary to the editor&amp;rsquo;s assertion, has been cited repeatedly in the chs. 31 ff. L3 ends at the end of ch. 49.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-comparison-of-the-l-readings-with-the-critical-notes-in-the-text-it-appears-that-the-division-of-the-mss-into-classes-as-made-by-the-editor-is-not-confirmed-in-general-there-are-many-inconsequences-in-the-critical-notes-thus-on-p-8-n-6-a-variant-is-cited-from-the-mss-b-and-cha-although-cha-has-been-stated-in-the-sanskrit-introduction-to-belong-to-class-b-on-p-52-notes-18-and-22-we-find-the-same-on-p-14-n-8-bja-on-p-41-n-5-a--ca-l1-has-there-the-reading-of-ca-often-it-seems-that-the-editor-has-consulted-only-one-ms-of-a-certain-class-where-the-whole-class-has-probably-that-reading-because-l-shows-it-also-thus-in-the-chs-36-59-the-ms-cha-has-been-cited-most-often-in-the-chs-59-68-the-ms-ca-in-the-chs-79-ff-the-ms-ka-in-96ff-cha-and-b-in-all-these-cases-l1-usually-agrees-with-these-variant-readings----in-p-123-n-10-l1-agrees-with-gha-class-a-in-starting-a-lacuna-which-ends-on-p-124-n-8-perhaps-gha-is-here-a-mistake-for-kha-originated-from-oral-dictation-in-general-my-impression-is-as-far-as-can-be-judged-from-the-incomplete-data-that-the-ms-ka-is-in-many-respects-independent-of-all-the-other-mss-of-the-classes-a-and-b-eg-in-ch-47-l1-does-not-agree-with-the-readings-of-ka-but-with-those-of-ca-and-cha-if-we-subtract-the-mss-ca-which-very-often-goes-with-the-b-class-and-gha-which-shows-a-remarkable-agreement-with-l1-see-above-and-has-further-not-been-cited-very-much-from-the-a-class-ka-alone-remains&#34;&gt;14&#xA;Introduction&#xA;A reading supported by L1 + L2 or L1+ L3 has been called L.&#xA;In many cases, the L group has preserved excellent readings, although many uncertainties and proofs of misunderstanding remain also here. As appears already from what has been said for L1 and L3, the L group has a position in the B class of mss. Many times, however, the L group goes with the A class, in some cases even with the text against the reading of the B class, e.g., in p. 8, n. 8. In a few cases, L agrees with ma or with ta. In general, the L group shows a tendency to agree with a variant reading, if one has been noted in the critical apparatus, no matter to which class this reading belongs.&#xA;By comparison of the L readings with the critical notes in the text, it appears that the division of the mss. into classes as made by the editor is not confirmed. In general, there are many inconsequences in the critical notes. Thus, on p. 8, n. 6, a variant is cited from the mss. &amp;ldquo;B and cha&amp;rdquo;, although cha has been stated in the Sanskrit Introduction to belong to class B. On p. 52, notes 18 and 22, we find the same. On p. 14, n. 8: &amp;ldquo;B+ja&amp;rdquo;. On p. 41, n. 5: &amp;ldquo;A + ca&amp;rdquo; (L1 has there the reading of ca). Often it seems that the editor has consulted only one ms. of a certain class, where the whole class has probably that reading, because L shows it also. Thus, in the chs. 36-59, the ms. cha has been cited most often; in the chs. 59-68, the ms. ca; in the chs. 79 ff., the ms. ka; in 96ff., cha and B. In all these cases, L1 usually agrees with these variant readings. &amp;ndash; In p. 123, n. 10, L1 agrees with gha (class A!) in starting a lacuna, which ends on p. 124, n. 8 (perhaps, &amp;ldquo;gha&amp;rdquo; is here a mistake for &amp;ldquo;kha&amp;rdquo;, originated from oral dictation). In general, my impression is, as far as can be judged from the incomplete data, that the ms. ka is in many respects independent of all the other mss. of the classes A and B (e.g., in ch. 47, L1 does not agree with the readings of ka, but with those of ca and cha). If we subtract the mss. ca (which very often goes with the B class) and gha (which shows a remarkable agreement with L1, see above, and has further not been cited very much) from the A class, ka alone remains.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;j-wackernagel&#34;&gt;Last remains the pleasant task to acknowledge my indebtedness to those who have helped me in various ways during the writing of this work.&#xA;It would be of no use to try to account for the part played by my teacher and promoter, Prof. Dr. J. Gonda, by means of his many cor- rections, lucid suggestions, advice in practical and theoretical matters, and friendly interest. It was he who suggested the subject and who made it possible for me to study it. To him in the first place, I am very grateful. My thanks are also due to Miss J. L. de Bruyne, Mrs. E. Wiersma-&#xA;Introduction&#xA;15&#xA;te Nijenhuis, Dr. P. Gaeffke, Mr. K. Yoroi, Mr. C. J. G. van der Burg, and Mr. B. Sigtermans for useful advice and help; to Mrs. C. M. Breu- ning-Williamson and Prof. Dr. R. Vleeskruyer for their indispensable correction of my English; to Mr. Zwaan of the Astronomical Observatory in Utrecht, who very kindly discussed with me the problems reflected in ch. 30, n. 4, and who saved me from some errors; to the staff of the Hortus Botanicus at Utrecht; to Prof. V. Raghavan in Madras; to the India Office Library in London; to the Adyar Library in Madras for procuring me a microfilm of a manuscript of the work; to the Govern- ment Oriental Manuscript Library in Madras for procuring me two transcripts of manuscripts, and to their transcribers, Mr. V. Subbiah Sastri and Mr. H. Sthanukrishna Iyer, for their swift and beautiful work; to the staff of the Utrecht University Library for its always friendly and accurate co-operation.&#xA;To my wife I am indebted for her constant encouragement and her help in preparing the appendices.&#xA;ABBREVIATIONS&#xA;AitBr.&#xA;Aiyangar, Hist. AKh.&#xA;AkhVy.&#xA;ang. ÄpMBr. ApŚrs.&#xA;Apte&#xA;AśvGṛhS.&#xA;AśvŚrS Atri&#xA;AV&#xA;Banerjea, Icon.&#xA;Bhagpur. Bhṛgu&#xA;Bloomfield, Conc.&#xA;Bollée, see ŞaḍvBr.&#xA;BṛhĀrUp.&#xA;Aitareyabrāhmaṇa, ed. K. S. Agase, Anandāśrama Sanskrit Ser. 32 (Poona, 1896).&#xA;S. K. Aiyangar, A history of Tirupati, 2 vols. (Madras, 1940). Arcanakhanda of Kāśyapa. Manuscript copy in the University Library, Utrecht (Telugu characters).&#xA;Arcanakhaṇḍavyākhyā. Manuscript copy in Telugu characters in the University Library, Utrecht.&#xA;angula (see ch. 50).&#xA;Apastambamantrabrāhmaṇa (as cited by Bloomfield, Conc.). Apastambaśrautasūtra, ed. R. Garbe, Bibliotheca Indica, Vol. 92 (three parts) (Calcutta, 1882-1902).&#xA;V. S. Apte, A Sanskrit-English Dictionary (new edition by P. K. Gode-C. G. Karve (Poona 1957-1959). Aśvalayanagṛhyasutra, ed. T. Ganapati Sastri, Trivandrum Sanskrit Ser. 78 (1923).&#xA;Aśvalāyanaśrautasūtra (as cited by Bloomfield, Conc.). Samurtarcanādhikaraṇa (Atri-Samhita) by Maharși Atri, ed. P. Raghunathachakravarti Bhattacharya, and M. Ramakrishna Kavi, Tirupati 1943 (Sri Venkatesvara Oriental Series No. 6). Atharvaveda (as cited by Bloomfield, Conc.).&#xA;J. N. Banerjea, The development of Hindu iconography (Calcutta *1956).&#xA;Bhāgavatapurāṇa, ed. V. L. S. Pansikar (Bombay, 1910).&#xA;Yajñādhikāraḥ from the Bhrgusamhita, ed. D. Rangācārya, Vaikhānasagranthamālā, Vol. 19 (1931).&#xA;M. Bloomfield, A Vedic Concordance (1906).&#xA;Bṛhadaraṇyakopanisad, ed. Gorakhpur (*1956).&#xA;Caland, Sacred books W. Caland, On the sacred books of the Vaikhānasas, Med. Kon.&#xA;Caland, Zauberr.&#xA;Caland-Henry&#xA;ch. ChUp.&#xA;Diehl, Instr. and&#xA;Purp. Dowson&#xA;Akad. v. Wet., Afd. Lett., Deel 65, Serie A, nr. 7 (Amsterdam, 1928).&#xA;W. Caland, Altindisches Zauberritual (trsl. with notes of some parts of the Kausikasūtra) (Amsterdam, 1900).&#xA;W. Caland-V. Henry, L&amp;rsquo;Agniştoma (Paris, 1906-1907).&#xA;chapter&#xA;Chandogya-Upanisad, ed. with trsl. E. Senart (Paris, 1930).&#xA;C. G. Diehl, Instrument and Purpose. Studies on rites and rituals in South India, Thesis Lund (1956).&#xA;J. Dowson, A classical dictionary of Hindu mythology etc. (London, 1957).&#xA;E.&#xA;East&#xA;Abbreviations&#xA;17&#xA;Eggers, Dharmasūtra W. Eggers, Das Dharmasūtra der Vaikhānasas (trsl. with notes and introduction), Thesis Göttingen (1929).&#xA;EHA&#xA;Eliade, Traité Gonda, Aspects&#xA;Gonda, Epithets&#xA;Gonda, R. Ind.&#xA;P. K. Acharya, Encyclopaedia of Hindu Architecture, Mānasara Series, Vol. 7 (Allahabad, 1946).&#xA;M. Eliade, Traité de l&amp;rsquo;histoire des religions (Paris, 1949).&#xA;J. Gonda, Aspects of early Vişnuism (&amp;rsquo;s-Gravenhage, 1954). J. Gonda, Epithets in the Rgveda (&amp;rsquo;s-Gravenhage, 1959) (Dispu- tationes Rheno-trajectinae, Vol. 4).&#xA;J. Gonda, Die Religionen Indiens, I and II (Stuttgart 1960-1963). Gonda, sūnuḥ sahasaḥ J. Gonda, Some observations on the relations between &amp;ldquo;gods&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;powers&amp;rdquo; in the Veda, a propos of the phrase sūnuḥ sahasaḥ (&amp;rsquo;s-Gravenhage, 1957) (Disputationes Rheno-trajectinae, Vol. 1). Gṛhyasūtra&#xA;GṛhS.&#xA;Hacker, Prahlada&#xA;P. Hacker, Prahlada, Werden und Wandlungen einer Ideal- gestalt (Mainz, 1959) (Akad. der Wiss. und der Literatur, Abh. der Geistes- und sozialw. Klasse, Jahrgang 1959, nos. 9, 13). Heesterman, Rājasūya J. C. Heesterman, The Ancient Indian Royal Consecration, Thesis (&amp;rsquo;s-Gravenhage, 1957) (Disputationes Rheno-trajectinae, Vol. 2).&#xA;HirGrhS.&#xA;Hiranyakeśigrhyasūtra (as cited by Bloomfield, Conc.) Hohenberger, Fluts. A. Hohenberger, Die indische Flutsage und das Matsya-Purāņa&#xA;(Leipzig 1930).&#xA;Hopkins, Ep. myth. E. Washburn Hopkins, Epic mythology (Strassburg, 1915) (Grundriss der Indo-Arischen Philologie und Altertumskunde, III, 1b).&#xA;Ind. Kew.&#xA;Inde Class.&#xA;JA&#xA;JISOA&#xA;JOIB&#xA;Arch.&#xA;JRAS&#xA;Kām.&#xA;Jouveau-Dubreuil,&#xA;Kane, Dhs. KathS.&#xA;Kirfel, Kosm. Kohlbrugge, AP.&#xA;Kramrisch&#xA;MahāNUp.&#xA;Män.&#xA;MānGṛhS. Marici&#xA;Index Kewensis (recording Latin names of the world&amp;rsquo;s plants and trees; not yet appeared in print).&#xA;L&amp;rsquo;Inde Classique, Manuel des études indiennes, par L. Renou et J. Filliozat, 2 vols. (Paris, 1947-1953).&#xA;Journal Asiatique (Paris).&#xA;Journal of the Indian Society of Oriental Art (Calcutta).&#xA;Journal of the Oriental Institute of Baroda (Baroda).&#xA;G. Jouveau-Dubreuil, Archéologie du Sud de l&amp;rsquo;Inde (Paris, 1914).&#xA;Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society (London). Kāmikāgama (as cited by EHA).&#xA;P. V. Kane, History of Dharmaśāstra (Poona 1930). Kathasamhita of the Yajurveda (as cited by Bloomfield, Conc.). W. Kirfel, Die Kosmographie der Inder (Bonn-Leipzig, 1920). Miss D. J. Kohlbrugge, Atharvavedapariśişta über Omina, Thesis (Utrecht, 1938).&#xA;Stella Kramrisch, The Hindu temple, 2 vols. (Calcutta, 1946). Mahānārāyaṇopaniṣad (ed.: 108 Upanisads, Nirnaya Sāgara Press, Bombay, 1948).&#xA;Mānasāra, ed. and trsl. by P. K. Acharya, Manasăra Series, vols. 3 and 4 (Allahabad, 1934).&#xA;Mänavagṛhyasūtra (trsl. M. J. Dresden, Thesis Utrecht, 1941). Marīciproktasamhitāsu Vimānārcanakalpaḥ, ed. D. Rangācārya, Ākulamaṇṇāḍu or Igavaripalem 1927 (Vaikhānasagranthamālā, vol. 15).&#xA;Note: This edition in Telugu characters, although uncritical, is the best one of Marici&amp;rsquo;s handbook. It contains 100 chapters (patalas). There is another edition, called Vai-&#xA;18&#xA;Abbreviations&#xA;khānasam Marīciproktam or Vaikhānasāgama, by K. Sambasiva Śāstrī, Trivandrum Skt. Series, vol. 121, 1935. This edition, based on only one ms., gives 70 patalas. It abounds in mistakes and must be considered as philologically worthless.&#xA;May.&#xA;Mbh.&#xA;McCann&#xA;Meyer, Tril.&#xA;Mr.gÅg.Kr.&#xA;MS&#xA;ms. MtPur.&#xA;MW&#xA;N.&#xA;PadmaS.Kr.&#xA;Pargiter&#xA;PārUp.&#xA;Pur.&#xA;PW&#xA;The Mayamata of Mayamuni, ed. T. Gaṇapati Šāstrī, Trivandrum Skt. Ser., vol. 65 (1919).&#xA;Mahābhārata, Critical Edition by V. S. Sukthankar and others (Poona).&#xA;Ch. McCann, Trees of India (Bombay, no date).&#xA;J. J. Meyer, Trilogie altindischer Mächte und Feste der Vege- tation (Zürich, 1937).&#xA;Mṛgendrāgama, Kriyāpāda, ed. N. R. Bhatt (Pondicherry, 1962) (Publ. de l&amp;rsquo;Institut français d&amp;rsquo;Indologie, vol. 23).&#xA;Maitrāyaṇīsamhita of the Yajurveda (as cited by Bloomfield,&#xA;Conc.).&#xA;manuscript&#xA;Matsyapurāṇa, Anandāśrama Skt. Ser., vol. 54 (Poona). Sir M. Monier-Williams, ASanskrit-English Dictionary (London). North&#xA;Pāñcarātraprāsādaprasādhanam. Chapter 1-10 of the Kriyāpāda of the Padmasamhita, edited and annotated by H. Daniel Smith (Madras, 1963).&#xA;The Märkandeya Purāņa, trsl. with notes by F. Eden Pargiter (Calcutta, 1904) (Bibl. Indica, vol. 125).&#xA;Pāramātmikopaniṣad, ed. in: Unpublished Upanisads (Adyar, 1933), pp. 86-207.&#xA;Purāņa&#xA;Sanskrit-Wörterbuch by R. Roth and O. Böhtlingk (St. Peters- burg, 1855-1875) (8 vols.).&#xA;Rangachari, S.V.B. Diwan Bahadur K. Rangachari, The Śrī Vaishnava Brahmans (Madras, 1931) (Bull. of the Madras Govt. Museum, New Ser., General Section II, No. 2).&#xA;Rao, Icon.&#xA;Rgvidh.&#xA;Ristas.&#xA;RV. RVKhila&#xA;S. ŞadvBr.&#xA;Schrader, Pañc.&#xA;Shastri, Images&#xA;Skt.&#xA;StpBr.&#xA;ŚvetUp.&#xA;TÃr.&#xA;T. A. Gopinatha Rao, Elements of Hindu iconography, Vol. I, Part 1 (Madras, 1914).&#xA;The Ṛgvidhāna. English trsl. with introd. and notes by J. Gonda (Utrecht, 1951).&#xA;The Riṣṭasamuccaya of Durgadeva. Ed. with trsl., introd. and notes by A. S. Gopani (Bombay, 1945) (Singhi Jain Series, vol. 21). Rgvedasamhita, ed. F. Max Müller (London, 1849-1875) (4 vols.). I. Scheftelowitz, Die Apokryphen des Rgveda (Breslau, 1906). South&#xA;Şadvimśabrāhmaṇa, ed. H. F. Eelsingh, Thesis (Utrecht, 1908); trsl. by W. B. Bollée, Thesis (Utrecht, 1956).&#xA;F. O. Schrader, Introduction to the Pañcarātra and the Ahir- budhnya Samhitā (Adyar, 1916).&#xA;H. Krishna Shastri, South Indian images of gods and goddesses (Madras, 1916).&#xA;Sanskrit&#xA;Satapathabrāhmaṇa, ed. A. Chinnaswami Sastri, Kāśī Skt. Series, vol. 127 (2 parts) (1937).&#xA;Śvetāśvataropanisad, ed. R. Hauschild (Leipzig, 1927) (Abhandl. für die Kunde des Morgenlandes, XVII, 3).&#xA;Taittiriyāraṇyaka, ed. A. M. Sastri and K. Rangacharya (Mysore, 1900-1902) (Bibl. Sanskrita).&#xA;TBr.&#xA;text&#xA;TS&#xA;Tucci, Mandala&#xA;Up.&#xA;VanC.&#xA;V.Brh.&#xA;Viennot&#xA;VkhS.&#xA;VkhS.C.&#xA;VkhSamh.&#xA;VkhŚrS.&#xA;VS. VS.&#xA;VSKāņva&#xA;W.&#xA;WD&#xA;Abbreviations&#xA;19&#xA;Taittiriyabrāhmaṇa, ed. A. M. Sastri and L. Srinivasacharya (Mysore, 1908-1913) (Bibl. Sanskrita).&#xA;Kāśyapajñānakāṇḍa (Kasyapasamhita), ed. R. Parthasarathi Bhattacharya (Tirupati, 1948) (Sri Venkatesvara Oriental Series, vol. 12).&#xA;Taittiriyasamhita of the Black Yajurveda, ed. A. M. Sastri and K. Rangacharya (Mysore, 1894-1898) (Govt. Oriental Library). G. Tucci, Theory and practice of the mandala, trsl. into English by A. Houghton Brodrick (London, 1961).&#xA;Upanisad&#xA;Vanausadhicandrodaya, Kāśī Skt. Series, vol. 161 (2 parts)&#xA;(1959).&#xA;Varähamihira, Bṛhatsamhita, ed. + trsl. V. Subrahmanya Sastri and M. Ramakrishna Bhat (Bangalore, 1947).&#xA;Odile Viennot, Le culte de l&amp;rsquo;arbre dans l&amp;rsquo;Inde ancienne (Paris, 1954) (Annales du Musée Guimet, 59).&#xA;Vaikhānasasmārtasūtra, ed. W. Caland (Calcutta, 1927) (Bibl. Indica, vol. 242).&#xA;Vaikhānasasmārtasūtra, trsl. W. Caland (Calcutta, 1929) (Bibl. Indica, vol. 251).&#xA;Vaikhānasamantrasamhita (as cited in notes by Prof. Caland). This work has been edited in the Vaikhanasagranthamālā as vols. 7 and 14.&#xA;Vaikhānasasrautasūtra, ed. W. Caland and Raghu Vīra (Calcutta, 1941) (Bibl. Indica).&#xA;verse&#xA;Vājasaneyīsamhita of the White Yajurveda (as cited by Bloom- field, Conc.).&#xA;Vājasaneyīsamhitā, Kāṇva recension (as cited by Bloomfield,&#xA;Conc.). West&#xA;J. Wackernagel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;he-said-to-them-man-has-to-worship-viṣṇu-the-lord-of-gods-in-a-method-which-is-in-harmony-with-the-scriptures-with-formulas-from-the-veda-in-order-to-reach-that-highest-abode-of-visņu-3&#34;&gt;A. Debrunner, Altindische Grammatik (Göttingen, 1896-1954).&#xA;Whitehead, Village H. Whitehead, The village gods of South India (Oxford, 1916).&#xA;gods&#xA;WZKSOA&#xA;ZDMG&#xA;Wiener Zeitschrift für die Kunde Süd- und Ostasiens und Archiv für indische Philosophie (Wien).&#xA;Zeitschrift der deutschen Morgenländischen Gesellschaft (Leipzig, later: Wiesbaden).A BOOK OF WISDOM, PROCLAIMED BY KĀŚYAPA&#xA;DEDICATION&#xA;One should, for the atonement of all hindrances, meditate on Viṣṇu, who wears a white garment, whose colour is that of the moon, who has four arms, and whose countenance is friendly.&#xA;At whose command his attendants, led by the god with the elephant&amp;rsquo;s face, are always destroying the hindrances, to him, Vişvaksena, I apply (for help).1&#xA;Visvaksena is known as the exalted king of pure deeds; one should worship no other than him to obtain appeasement of hindrances.&#xA;2&#xA;To him, who composed all the rules about the śrauta and the smärta ritual, the knower of the meaning of the complete Veda, to Vikhanas, honour!&#xA;1 This verse is found in L. Its Sanskrit text is: yasya dviradavaktrādyāḥ pārṣadyāḥ para śāsanam | vighnam vighnanti satatam vişvaksenam tam āśraye //. Visvaksena is the direct attendant of Visņu and may also act as his representative on certain occasions (see, e.g., ch. 24); he is a lower personification of the powers represented by Vişņu, a kind of &amp;ldquo;miniature Vişņu&amp;rdquo;. For his image, see the end of ch. 49. 2 In the Vaikhānasa Śrauta- and Smartasūtras.&#xA;CHAPTER 1&#xA;The Question of the Seers&#xA;When Kasyapa was sitting in his hermitage, the seer who knew the com- plete Veda (by heart), who was acquainted with the real meaning of all the textbooks, and whose mind was benevolent, the sages, who took delight in the happiness of all beings, came to him and asked him: &amp;ldquo;Venerable Sir, which deity has man to worship, and in what method, with which formulas (mantra-),1 in order to reach the highest abode?&amp;ldquo;2&#xA;1 The formulas play a very important part. They are of two kinds: a. Vedic formulas, practically always in verse, cited mainly by way of pratika, i.e., by their first four or&#xA;22&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;He said to them: &amp;ldquo;Man has to worship Viṣṇu, the Lord of gods, in a method which is in harmony with the Scriptures, with formulas from the Veda, in order to reach &amp;rsquo;that highest abode of Visņu&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nārāyaṇa, the Highest Self, Who is standing in the flame of the fire which burns in the heart &amp;lsquo;which occupies only the space of a lotus- corolla&amp;rsquo;, (but) is large, (yea,) has room for everything&amp;rsquo;s - He is &amp;rsquo;the Highest Light&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;the Imperishable Brahman&amp;rsquo;, thus the knowers of Brahman know Him.&#xA;He, Who, being based in Nature, has the states of sleeping, (dreaming, and waking) as His domain,&amp;rsquo; is all that has been, that is, and that will be. For the Scripture says: &amp;ldquo;This Person is all that has been, and that is to be&amp;rsquo;.8&#xA;He, Who is threefold, is satisfied by (three things): Veda-study, śrauta rituals, and asceticism; and as the Lord of Sacrifice He is invoked by sacrifice.&#xA;Therefore the regular worship of Vişņu, performed according to the right method in a temple, grants the results of the sacrifice into the fire, even for people who do not maintain their fires, in the same way as&#xA;five syllables; and b., formulas from later times, mainly in prose, accompanying e.g. the ploughing (ch. 22), the praise of the hotar function (ch. 65), the regular worship (ch. 69f.) and the festival (chs. 88-90). The formulas from the chs. 22 ff. are given in full in the last four prasnas of the Vaikhănasa-Mantra-Samhita (cf. the Introduction). For more about the nature of the Indian mantra, see J. Gonda, The Indian mantra, in: Oriens 15, (Leiden 1963), pp. 244-297, esp. p. 255. The translation &amp;ldquo;formula&amp;rdquo; is only approximate, but necessary for practical reasons.&#xA;2&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;highest abode&amp;rdquo; (paramam padam) is an expression used already in connection with Visnu in the Rgveda (e.g., RV. 1,22,20) and well known throughout the history of Vişnuism. It is thought of as a kind of heaven, inhabited by Vişņu together with His loving adherents. See, e.g., Gonda, Aspects, p. 2; Hohenberger, Flutsage, pp. 98f. 3 RV. 1,22,20a. The question of the seers clearly presupposes the answer. This kind of introduction is very popular; cf., e.g., Marici 1.&#xA;4 I.e., the Soul of the complete cosmos, seen as a living sensible being. Visņu is identical with the whole existence. As such, he is the successor of the Cosmic Person from RV. 10,90, as will appear presently from the text.&#xA;5 padmakośapratikāśe, MahāNUp. 11,7; viśvasyāyatane, MahāNUp. 11,8. The same text, 11,11 and 13, says that Nārāyaṇa is present in a flame. Cf. BṛhĀrUp. 5,9,1; ChUp. 3,13,7 and 8. The Absolute may be seen as a personal or impersonal Principle; it is to be found both in the unending world-space and within the human heart. If adored as a person, it may be called Nārāyaṇa (see also ch. 55, n. 2), if as an impersonal (or supra-personal) principle, it is called Brahman. Both views may supplement each other. Vişņu is called identical with Brahman, here and in ch. 35.&#xA;6&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Highest Light&amp;rdquo;: ChUp. 8,3,4. &amp;ldquo;The Imperishable Brahman&amp;rdquo;: TĀr. 10,26,1b; MahaNUp. 15,1b.&#xA;7&#xA;Translation uncertain. Text: so &amp;lsquo;yam prakṛtisthas san na svapnadyagocaro &amp;lsquo;pi. The B group of mss.: svapnadhiyā(m) ca gocaro &amp;lsquo;pi.&#xA;8 RV. 10,90,2.&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;23&#xA;that sacrifice. And for those who maintain their fires, this is a second (method) causing corrections for all (kinds of faults) and leading to the realization of all their wishes; for temple worship is continued on earth without interruption by others 10 even when the sacrificer11 himself has died. Thus it will stand firm for ever.&#xA;This greatest meritorious work has always to be performed with devo- tion12 and carefully. Indeed, Brahma taught that it is a fire-sacrifice, common to all householders, who live in villages and towns, causing success in all respects. Also the gods, who receive their origin, protection, and dissolution from this Vişņu, worship Him only. When He, the Lord of gods, is worshipped, all the gods are included in this worship.&#xA;The Brāhmaṇa says: &amp;lsquo;Agni is the lowest of the gods, Vişņu the highest; between these two are all the other deities&amp;rsquo;.13 Therefore the seer pre- scribed concisely in the Vaikhānasa Sūtra: &amp;lsquo;Always after sacrificing into the fire (agni-), one should worship Nārāyaṇa&amp;rsquo;.14 His worship, accom- panied by formulas, performed in many varieties, I shall tell at length, in due order.&#xA;Thus, at any place in this (book) where an oblation is enjoined, there always the āghāra and the closing oblations, beginning with those for Agni Sviṣṭakṛt, have to be performed, in the method as indicated in the Vaikhānasa Sūtra.15&#xA;etc.&#xA;—&#xA;One should also choose for his officiants teachers, establishers, and temple priests16 only twice-born who are sanctified by the&#xA;9 This doctrine, which is the theoretical justification of temple worship, is a logical continuation of thoughts expressed already in Vedic texts, where Vişņu is sometimes identified with the sacrifice, and as such is able to bring about the results gained by the sacrifice. See Gonda, Aspects, p. 79; Marīci 1; ViṣṇudharmottaraPur. 3,14: iṣṭā- pürtena labhyante ye lokās tān bubhūṣată devānām ālayaḥ kāryah &amp;ldquo;a temple of the gods should be made by anyone who desires to live in the worlds which are obtained by sacrifice and good works&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;10 This is very important; a break in the worship will have bad results, as appears from ch. 99 and, e.g., Atri 4, 38ff.&#xA;11 yajamānaḥ. This ancient Vedic term is used throughout the book for the organizer and sponsor of the ceremonies.&#xA;12 bhakti-, one of the most salient features of post-Vedic Hinduism. It is a fervent, loving worship of a personally conceived deity.&#xA;13 AitBr. 1,1,1.&#xA;14 VkhS. 4,10, at the beginning of the discussion of Viṣṇu worship.&#xA;15 The āghāra (cf. VkhS. 1,9-15) is the oblation of melted butter which precedes each sacrifice; the closing oblations (antahoma-) at the end of each sacrifice are described in VkhS. 1,19-21.&#xA;16&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;teacher&amp;rdquo; (ācārya- or guru-) and the &amp;ldquo;establishers&amp;rdquo; (sthāpaka-) are indis- pensible functionaries during the construction of a temple (see ch. 21) and the con- secration of an image in a temple (chs. 59ff.); the temple priests (arcaka-) perform the regular worship when the image has been established.&#xA;24&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;personal ceremonies1 from impregnation onwards, by the method as described in this Sūtra.&#xA;Worship of Viṣṇu is traditionally twofold: without and with bodily form. Oblations into the fire as stated above is worship without bodily form; worship with bodily form is performed on an image of Him. Worship with bodily form is pleasant to the eye and mind, and its object remains always visible.18 Devotion (bhakti-) and faith (śraddhā-)19 should accompany it. Only the man who is devoted and faithful, will be successful in all respects.&#xA;Worship with bodily form in a temple is made complete by observances such as the giving of tribute (bali-) and (the organizing of) festivals (utsava-). It will always continue uninterruptedly also when the sacrificer is no more. This worship grants the results of enjoyment in this world and of release in yonder world (i.e., after death); 20 it is everlasting, and of a double nature: causing appeasement (śāntika-) and causing prosperity (pauştika-).21 It causes appeasement because it has the appeasement of all (evils) as its goal; it causes prosperity because it has prosperity in all respects as its goal. The sages should listen attentively to this complete course of religious practice&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;17&#xA;Thus said Kasyapa.&#xA;samskāra-. By these, the brahmans are, as it were, &amp;ldquo;made fit&amp;rdquo; (sams-kṛta-), i.e. sanctified or consecrated for their holy work.&#xA;18 Trsl. of ma and L2: samsthitis ca. Cf. for the two forms of worship, amurta and samurta, &amp;ldquo;without and with bodily form&amp;rdquo;: Atri 1, 28ff.; 27,1ff. Vikhanas described in his sūtras the amurta form, his pupils the samūrta form in their works (Atri 1,32ff.). Thus, changes in the religious practice are reflected in a traditional division of duties between the ancient teachers.&#xA;19&#xA;20&#xA;A preparatory stage. See: P. Hacker, Śraddha, WZKSOA 6, 1963.&#xA;The division of &amp;ldquo;this world&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;yonder world&amp;rdquo; and the results gained there is ancient and occurs regularly in the Brāhmaṇas. See also ch. 105.&#xA;21 For more about these terms, see the chs. 4 and 10. The term santi- was discussed by D. J. Hoens, Santi in the Samhitās, Brāhmaṇas, and Śrautasūtras, Thesis Utrecht, 1951. For bringing about this santi-, the prāyaścittas are prescribed in the chs. 92ff. All kinds of faults and sins, ritual as well as ethical, which enable bad magical influences to do their destructive work, are appeased or expiated in it. puști- means prosperity, welfare, a well-nourished condition.&#xA;CHAPTER 2&#xA;Description of the World&#xA;In this chapter an epitome is given from the Puranic doctrine of universal geography (represented systematically by W. Kirfel, Die Kosmographie der Inder, Bonn/Leipzig 1920, and Das Purāņa vom Weltgebäude, Bonn 1954,&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;25&#xA;where on pp. 1-6 a summary is given of Puranic geography). In the main the same ideas and names recur here, but there are some deviations, viz. in the nomenclature, and the mention of the regions which are to be avoided by Brahmans (ch. 3).&#xA;From the arrangement of seas and continents it appears that Kasyapa agrees here with the Matsya-Purana and a few other texts, called the &amp;ldquo;second group&amp;rdquo; by Kirfel (Kosmographie, p. 56f.). See also: J. Gonda, Über das altjavanische Brahmāṇḍa-Purāṇa, Acta Orientalia 11, 1932, on pp. 247 ff. Curiously enough the description of the world given by one ms. of Atri&amp;rsquo;s work (see the ed. of Atri-Samhită, pp. 504ff.) follows another arrangement (that of Kirfel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;first group&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;In the geographical names there are a number of deviations from the Purānas (see Kirfel, o.c., Index).&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Now we shall explain the objects which cause appeasement.&#xA;In these worlds one produces the results: the enjoyment of results is just for the worlds beyond these.1 Therefore one has to begin his ritual work in this world on a pure and charming place.&#xA;The earth consists of seven continents, called (from the centre to the circumference) after the rose-apple tree (jambu-), the teak tree (śaka-), the kuśa grass, the Curlew (krauñca-) Mountain, the silk-cotton tree (salmali-), the cow-fat gem (gomeda-), and the blue lotus (puşkara-). There are seven oceans between the continents, consisting respectively of salt, sweet milk, clarified butter, curds, honey, sugarcane juice, and cold water.2&#xA;There are seven worlds located above each other, called respectively Bhur, Bhuvar, Suvar, Mahar, Janar, Tapas, and Satya. Below the earth there are seven nether worlds, called Atala, Vitala, Pratala, Dhātaka, Vidrāvaka, Samphullänga, Mahātala. Beyond these the Unmanifest is extending. It is taught by those who have mystical insight into reality,&#xA;3&#xA;1i.e., after death. The author now first gives the description of &amp;ldquo;these worlds&amp;rdquo;, in which good works may be done and results gained. The amusmin loke in the next sentence must be a mistake for asmiml loke.&#xA;2 The MtPur. gives sura- instead of madhu-, and svādūda- instead of sitodadhi-. We have to imagine the first continent, jambudvipa-, as circular, and the other six lying as kinds of rings around it, separated by the respective oceans.&#xA;3 The first three names and the last one occur also in Puranic lists (Kirfel, Kosm., pp. 143 ff.) with variations in their sequence. Most near comes the list of the Bhāgavata- and a few other Puranas: Atala, Vitala, Sutala, Talatala, Mahātala, Rasātala, Pātāla. Rasātala occurs in the ms. ka (see n. 4 on p. 3, text). Dhataki is, in Jaina cosmography, the name for the second continent. No parallels were found for the names Vidrāvaka and Samphullänga,&#xA;26&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;4&#xA;that in this Unmanifest Kapila is dwelling, having the colour of coral, with three eyes, sustaining the world, unarmed, wearing a garment of the colour of parrots&amp;rsquo; feathers, bracelets, a necklace, a breast-string hanging down from the neck (pralamba-), and a sacred thread, marked with the Śrīvatsa, with four arms,&amp;rdquo; sitting in the Brahma-postures and absorbed in meditation on account of his desire to know the Highest Principle, which is eternal, beginningless, everlasting, Whose form is unimaginable, and Which is unique (kūtastha-).&#xA;The measure of the Rose-Apple Continent is from S. to N. and from E. to W.: 800.000.000.000 yojanas.&amp;rdquo; The thickness of its earth is 320 million yojanas; it is surrounded by the ocean of salt. The measures become twice as large from continent to continent, going in an outward direction, from ocean to ocean, up to the ocean of cold water, while each surrounding ocean has the same width as the world surrounded by it, and in its turn is surrounded completely (by the next continent). This all together forms one (universal) egg. It is said that there are several tens of millions of such universal eggs.&#xA;8&#xA;9&#xA;The Rose-Apple Continent has nine sections, called varṣaḥ, named from S. to N.: Bharata-, Haimavata-, Naiṣadha-, Meru-, Daiva-, Vai- ḍūrya-, Śveta-, Śṛnga-, and Gandharvavarṣa. Six boundary ranges, called Himavat, Hema, Niṣadha, Nīla, Śveta, and Śriga, reach into the eastern and western ocean. Bharata lies to the S. of Himavat down to the sea; Haimavata between Himavat and Hema; Naiṣadha extends from Hema to Niṣadha; Meru lies between Niṣadha and Nila; to the E.&#xA;▲ jagadādhāraḥ; acc. to the A class of mss.: jaṭādhāraḥ &amp;ldquo;wearing matted locks&amp;rdquo;. - KurmaPur. 4,44 mentions the avyaktam (&amp;ldquo;Unmanifest&amp;rdquo;) as the outermost shell of the world-eggs.&#xA;5&#xA;These are qualities and attributes of Visņu himself. The Srivatsa is a curl of hair on the breast of Visņu and his incarnations. Prescriptions for an image of Kapila: Rao, Icon., I,1, p. 247, according to whom he should be represented as a bearded ascetic. In the Epics, he is regarded as a manifestation of Visņu (Hopkins, Ep. myth., p. 218). In the Purāņas, Kapila appears also as sitting in the nether world and meditating (H. H. Wilson, Trsl. of VişņuPur., London, 1840, p. 378). He is mostly known as the mythical founder of the Samkhya system.&#xA;6 A particular way of sitting, in which meditation is often practised. 7 One yojana yojanas.&#xA;9&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;about seven miles. The normal figure in the Purāņas is only 100.000&#xA;8 dvipād dvipād dviguṇitam bāhyād bāhyam samudrac ca samudram sitodadhitas ca bahyam apy evam lokāl lokāntaram tāvatpramāṇam vivaram. Cf. MatsyaPur. 123,27. Otherwise Kirfel Kosm., pp. 57f. Only Bharatavarșa (= the &amp;ldquo;Indian Subcontinent&amp;rdquo; in modern times) occurs there. Haimavata is found also in Mbh. and Padmapur. According to Kirfel, o.c., p. 61, Gandharvadvipa is one of the regions in Bharata. The names of the mountain ranges following now in the text correspond with those given by Kirfel.&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kāśyapa&#xA;27&#xA;and W. of Meru lie Daiva and Vaiḍūrya; Śveta lies between Nīla and Śveta; Śṛnga between Sveta and Sataśṛnga; Gandharva from Mt. Śriga down to the (northern) sea.&#xA;It is taught that in Saka there are 20 varṣas, in Kusa 30, in Krauñca and Salmali 50, in Gomeda 70, in Puskara 90.10&#xA;10 In the Purāņas, these numbers are much smaller.&#xA;CHAPTER 3&#xA;Regions Not to be Inhabited by Brahmans&#xA;No Puranic equivalent for this chapter seems to exist. The names of the regions are also unknown from elsewhere (except for Bharatavarṣa), and there are many uncertainties in the text. Often it is difficult to divide the long compounds formed by the various names into their exact constituents.&#xA;The idea, that Brahmans should not enter certain regions, because they would be polluted by acting thus, is, however, by no means unknown. The Baudhayana Dharmasutra, 1,2,14-16, prescribes purification for Brahmans, when they have travelled to certain regions, e.g. Avanti and Kalinga-land. It is an often-recurring conviction that one does better not to leave his country; cf. already Jaiminiya-Brāhmaṇa 2,134-137 (ed. W. Caland, Das Jaiminiya-Brāhmaṇa in Auswahl, Verh. der Kon. Ak. v. Wet. te Amster- dam, Afd. Lett., Deel XIX, Nr. 4, Amsterdam 1919): sa esa padbhyām pāpam karoti, yo janam eti &amp;ldquo;that person commits a sin by means of his feet, who goes to foreign people&amp;rdquo;. See also Kane, DhŚ., Vol. II, Part 1, pp. 11 ff. (the limits of Āryavarta), esp. on p. 18.&#xA;In Bharatavarṣa there are regions for Piśācas, called Dardura-, Barbara-, Mālava-, Simhala-, and Śṛngika-land.1 They are not to be inhabited by Brahmans.&#xA;1&#xA;In Haimavata (the Pisaca-lands are): Sāla, Mudgandhika, Naidhāyaka, Kucumāra.2&#xA;Piśācas are evil demons of the lowest sort; the term is used also as a contemptuous name for people who are outside the Brahmanical or Sanskritized civilisation, or outside Vişnuite tradition (ch. 17). Dardura as the name of a mountain: Kirfel, o.c., p. 61 (located in the S. according to V.Brh. 14,11); Barbara as the name of a barbarous tribe in the N. (Kirfel, o.c., p. 73), or the S.W. of Bharata (idem, p. 86). The Barbaras were defeated by Sagara according to BhagPur. 9,8,5. Mālavas are the inhabitants of Malva-land (near Ujjain). This is exactly the region where the Prakrit dialect called Paiśācī was probably spoken, cf. S. Konow, The home of Paiśācī, ZDMG 64, 1910, pp. 95-118. Simhala is modern Ceylon.&#xA;2 L: Kṛcchramana.&#xA;28&#xA;A Book of Wisdom, proclaimed by Kasyapa&#xA;In Naiṣadha: Ghāṭa, Hāra, Hāṭaka, Musta, and Urvaya.3&#xA;In Daivika: Bhanuka and Apahāsya.&#xA;In Vaiḍūrya: Sākuṇḍa, Vāduka, Malpa, Dākṣiņaka, and Nila.&#xA;In Sveta: Sākundha, Aruṇa, Kapota, Piñjālabhāga, Śātana, Bhūtavāsa, Jelayaka, Vāna, Golaka, Variṣṭha, Pañcabhūmi, Musikāvāsa, and Rakṣoha.4&#xA;In Śṛnga: Taisya, Pramarda, Lambha, and Unmattastrīvāsa.5&#xA;In Gandharva: the regions called Śāṇḍilya, Dhundhumāra, Kāpota, and Vadavamukha.6&#xA;The following regions on the continents are uninhabitable for Brah-&#xA;mans:&#xA;On Sāka: Kākanika. On Kuśa: Padma and Apahārita. On Krauñca: Mukha, Tulaka, Śāṇḍilya, Kaiṭabha, and Sphoṭāmukha. On Śālmala: Kāsīsa and Vairagya. On Gomeda: Kākāvāsa and Bhujāvāsa. On Puşkara: Dāruṇa.&amp;rsquo;&#xA;3&#xA;Or: Ghāţahāra, Hāṭaka, and Mustorvaya. Piśāca-regions are wanting in the Meru- land. Cf. the description of the ground-plan in ch. 17, where the outermost part, far from the centre, is called after the Pisacas. The centre is supposed to be free from demons and bad influences. We need not assume a lacuna in the text, as the editor did. 4 A very confused list. &amp;ldquo;Pañcabhūmi&amp;rdquo; is especially uncertain. The text reads: -variṣṭhapañcabhūmikāvāsa-; L1: -paribhuvañcabhūmikāvāsa-; L2: -paribhuvañcamūşi-&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
