<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 The Formation of the Pāñcarātra Canon on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 The Formation of the Pāñcarātra Canon on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) Classifications of scripture in the Pārameśvarasaṃhitā and the Pādmasaṃhitā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/1_i_Classifications_of_scripture_in_the/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/1_i_Classifications_of_scripture_in_the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter I address the textual evidence which points to the formation of the Pāñcarātra canon as being the outcome of the decline of the sectarian culture I have referred to above. In this first part, I compare the &lt;em&gt;Pārameśvarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;’s (PārS) relatively early attempt to establish a scriptural canon with the substantially different approach to canon-formation that is found in the PādS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;statements&#34;&gt;Statements&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have seen in Chapter One, both the PārS and the *Īśvarasaṃhitā *(ĪS) employ a classificatory scheme in which the Pāñcarātra scriptures are divided into three groups, namely the celestial teachings ( &lt;em&gt;divyaśāstra&lt;/em&gt;), the teachings of sages ( &lt;em&gt;munibhāṣitaśāstra&lt;/em&gt;), and the teachings of men ( &lt;em&gt;pauruṣaśāstra&lt;/em&gt;).116&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) Appropriation and unification in the late Saṃhitās</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/2_ii_Appropriation_and_unification_in_th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/2_ii_Appropriation_and_unification_in_th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What can the classificatory innovations in such texts as the PādS and the PārS tell us about the Pāñcarātra traditions in South India? To what degree were these “canonical”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;schemes describing well-established exegetical principles and Pāñcarātrika identities, and to what degree were such systems modelled on the texts themselves? With regard to the four Siddhāntas the second question is very difficult to answer, though the Vaikhānasa literature, which contains various taxonomies of Pāñcarātra groups, may provide a clue that this system of classification did not long precede its earliest descriptions in the Pāñcarātra literature. For the earliest probable Vaikhānasa reference to the ‘Siddhānta’ system of classification occurs only in the &lt;em&gt;Ānandasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, which is among the latest of the Vaikhānasa “medieval corpus”.142 With regard to the organisation and classification of the Pāñcarātra scriptures, these processes are not yet evident in the earliest Pāñcarātra works, and the textual evidence suggests that they did not begin to gain importance until about the twelfth century, some time after Yāmuna’s composition of the ĀP.143 This is suggested by the fact that those works which classify and enumerate the Saṃhitās, such as the PādS and the PārS, do so as part of an overall attempt, that is absent in the earlier scriptures, to provide scriptural authority for a Pāñcarātra system of temple-worship.144 Although his &lt;em&gt;modus operandi&lt;/em&gt; and his intended audience are clearly different, this is also one of Yāmuna’s main objectives in the ĀP. However, despite the fact that he names and quotes several Saṃhitās, Yāmuna does not refer to any scriptural system of text-classification, or to any “canonical” list, and this indicates that such strategies were indeed not yet “well-established” within the Pāñcarātra context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/3_iii_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/4_The_Formation_of_the_pAncharAtra_Canon/3_iii_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The canonical list of scriptures contained in the PārS is probably one of the earliest attempts in a South Indian Saṃhitā to enumerate and classify the Pāñcarātra scriptural corpus. It is directly based on the hierarchy of teachings found in the SS, and the fact that it grades specific scriptures according to this hierarchy suggests that it is not derived from another canonical list. It is almost certainly older than the lists of Saṃhitās contained in other South Indian texts such as the PādS and the ViśS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
