<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/01/</guid>
      <description>Everywhere; because there is taught what is known. We read in the Cḥāndogya, &amp;lsquo;Man is made of thought; according to what his thought is in this world, so will he be when he has departed this life. Let him form this thought: he who consists of mind, whose body is breath, whose form is light,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (III, 14). We here understand that of the meditation enjoined by the clause &amp;rsquo;let him form this thought&amp;rsquo; the object is the being said to consist of mind, to have breath for its body, &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/02/</guid>
      <description>And because the qualities meant to be stated are possible (in Brahman). The qualities about to be stated can belong to the highest Self only. &amp;lsquo;Made of mind, having breath for its body,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. &amp;lsquo;Made of mind&amp;rsquo; means to be apprehended by a purified mind only. The highest Self can be apprehended only by a mind purified by meditation on that Self, such meditation being assisted by the seven means, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/03/</guid>
      <description>But, on account of impossibility, not the embodied soul. Those who fully consider this infinite multitude of exalted qualities will recognise that not even a shadow of them can belong to the individual soul&amp;ndash;whether in the state of bondage or that of release&amp;ndash;which is a thing as insignificant as a glow-worm and, through its connexion
with a body, liable to the attacks of endless suffering. It is not possible therefore to hold that the section under discussion should refer to the individual soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/04/</guid>
      <description>And because there is (separate) denotation of the object and the agent. The clause &amp;lsquo;When I shall have departed from hence I shall obtain him&amp;rsquo; denotes the highest Brahman as the object to be obtained, and the individual soul as that which obtains it. This shows that the soul which obtains is the person meditating, and the highest Brahman that is to be obtained, the object of meditation: Brahman, therefore, is something different from the attaining soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/05/</guid>
      <description>On account of the difference of words. The clause &amp;lsquo;That is the Self of me, within the heart&amp;rsquo; designates the embodied soul by means of a genitive form, while the object of meditation is exhibited in the nominative case. Similarly, a text of the Vājasaneyins, which treats of the same topic, applies different terms to the embodied and the highest Self, &amp;lsquo;Like a rice grain, or a barley grain, or a canary seed, or the kernel of a canary seed, thus that golden Person is within the Self&amp;rsquo; (Śat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/06/</guid>
      <description>And on account of Smr̥ti. &amp;lsquo;I dwell within the hearts of all, from me come memory and knowledge, as well as their loss&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;He who free from delusion knows me to be the highest Person&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;The Lord, O Arjuna, is seated in the heart of all Beings, driving round by his mysterious power all beings as if mounted on a machine; to him fly for refuge&amp;rsquo; (Bha. Gi. XV, 15, 19; XVIII, 61).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/07/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that (the passage does) not (refer to Brahman) on account of the smallness of the abode, and on account of the denotation of that (viz. minuteness of the being meditated on); we say no, because (Brahman) has thus to be meditated upon, and because (in the same passage) it is said to be like ether.
It might be contended that, as the text &amp;lsquo;he is my Self within the heart&amp;rsquo; declares the being meditated on to dwell within a minute abode, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/08/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that there is attainment of fruition (of pleasure and pain); we reply, not so, on account of difference. But, if the highest Brahman is assumed to dwell within bodies, like the individual soul, it follows that, like the latter, it is subject to the experience of pleasure and pain, such experience springing from connexion with bodies!&amp;ndash;Of this objection the Sūtra disposes by remarking &amp;rsquo;not so, on account of difference (of reason).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/09/</guid>
      <description>The eater (is the highest Self) on account of there being taken all that is movable and immovable. We read in the Kaṭḥavallī (I, 3, 25), &amp;lsquo;Who then knows where he is to whom the Brahmans and Kshattriyas are but food, and death itself a condiment? &amp;lsquo;A doubt here arises whether the &amp;rsquo;eater&amp;rsquo;, suggested by the words &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;condiment,&amp;rsquo; is the individual soul or the highest Self.&amp;ndash;The individual soul, the Pūrvapakshin maintains; for all enjoyment presupposes works, and works belong to the individual soul only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/10/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the topic of the whole section. Moreover the highest Brahman constitutes the topic of the entire section. Cp. &amp;lsquo;The wise who knows the Self as great and omnipresent does not grieve&amp;rsquo; (Ka. Up. I, 2, 22); &amp;lsquo;That Self cannot be gained by the Veda, nor by understanding, nor by much learning. He whom the Self chooses, by him the Self can be gained; the Self chooses him as his own&amp;rsquo; (I, 2, 23).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/11/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;rsquo;two entered into the cave&amp;rsquo; are the two Selfs; on account of this being seen. The two, entered into the cave and drinking their reward, are neither the embodied soul together with the vital breath, nor the embodied soul together with the buddhi; it is rather the embodied Self and the highest Self which are designated by those terms. For this is seen, i.e. it is seen that in that section the individual Self and the highest Self only are spoken of as entered into the cave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/12/</guid>
      <description>And on account of distinctive qualities. Everywhere in that section we meet with statements of distinctive attributes of the two Selfs, the highest Self
being represented as the object of meditation and attainment, and the individual Self as the meditating and attaining subject. The passage &amp;lsquo;When he has known and understood that which is born from Brahman, the intelligent, to be divine and venerable, then he obtains everlasting peace&amp;rsquo; (I, 1, 17) refers to the meditating individual soul which recognises itself as being of the nature of Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/13/</guid>
      <description>(The Person) within the eye (is the highest Self) on account of suitability. The Cḥandogas have the following text: &amp;lsquo;The Person that is seen within the eye, that is the Self. This is the immortal, the fearless, this is Brahman&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. IV, 15, 1). The doubt here arises whether the person that is here spoken of as abiding within the eye is the reflected Self, or some divine being presiding over the sense of sight, or the embodied Self, or the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/14/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the statement as to abode, and so on. Abiding within the eye, ruling the eye, and so on are predicated by scripture of the highest Self only, viz. in Br̥. Up. III, 7, 18, &amp;lsquo;He who dwells within the eye, who rules the eye within.&amp;rsquo; We therefore recognise that highest Self in the text, &amp;lsquo;That Person which is seen within the eye.&amp;rsquo; The argument founded on reference to &amp;lsquo;something well known&amp;rsquo; thus suits the highest Self very well; and also the clause which denotes immediate perception (&amp;lsquo;is seen&amp;rsquo;) appears quite suitable, since the highest Self is directly intuited by persons practising mystic concentration of mind (Yoga).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/15/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the text referring only to what is characterised by pleasure. The Person abiding within the eye is the highest Person, for the following reason also. The topic of the whole section is Brahman characterised by delight, as indicated in the passage &amp;lsquo;Ka(pleasure) is Brahman, Kha(ether) is Brahman&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. IV,10, 5). To that same Brahman the passage under discussion (&amp;lsquo;The Person that is seen in the eye&amp;rsquo;) refers for the purpose of enjoining first a place with which Brahman is to be connected in meditation, and secondly some special qualities&amp;ndash;such as comprising and leading all blessings&amp;ndash;to be attributed to Brahman in meditation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/16/</guid>
      <description>For that very reason that (ether) is Brahman. Because the clause &amp;lsquo;What is Ka the same is Kha&amp;rsquo; speaks of ether as characterised by pleasure, the ether which is denoted by &amp;lsquo;Kha&amp;rsquo; is no other than the highest Brahman. To explain. On the Fires declaring &amp;lsquo;Breath is Brahman, Ka is Brahman, Kha is Brahman,&amp;rsquo; Upakośala says, &amp;lsquo;I understand that breath is Brahman, but I do not understand Ka and Kha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/17/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the statement of the way of him who has heard the Upanishads. Other scriptural texts give an account of the way&amp;ndash;the first station of which is light&amp;ndash;that leads up to the highest Person, without any subsequent return, the soul of him who has read the Upanishads, and has thus acquired a knowledge of the true nature of the highest Self. Now this same way is described by the teacher to Upakosala in connexion with the instruction as to the Person in the eye, &amp;lsquo;They go to light, from light to day,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/18/</guid>
      <description>Not any other, on account of non-permanency of abode, and of impossibility. As the reflected Self and the other Selfs mentioned by the Pūrvapakshin do not necessarily abide within the eye, and as conditionless immortality and the other qualities (ascribed in the text to the Person within the eye) cannot possibly belong to them, the Person within the eye cannot be any Self other than the highest Self. Of the reflected Self it cannot be said that it permanently abides within the eye, for its presence there depends on the nearness to the eye of another person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/19/</guid>
      <description>The internal Ruler (referred to) in the clauses with respect to the gods, with respect to the worlds, &amp;amp;c. (is the highest Self), because the attributes of that are designated. The Vājasaneyins, of the Kāṇwa as well as the Mādhyandina branch, have the following text: &amp;lsquo;He who
dwelling in the earth is within the earth, whom the earth does not know, whose body the earth is, who rules the earth within, he is thy Self, the ruler within, the Immortal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/20/</guid>
      <description>And not that which Smr̥ti assumes, on account of the declaration of qualities not belonging to that; nor the embodied one. &amp;lsquo;That which Smr̥ti assumes&amp;rsquo; is the Pradhāna; the &amp;rsquo;embodied one&amp;rsquo; is the individual soul. Neither of these can be the Ruler within, since the text states attributes which cannot possibly belong to either. For there is not even the shadow of a possibility that essential capability of seeing and ruling all things, and being the Self of all, and immortality should belong either to the non-sentient Pradhāna or to the individual soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/21/</guid>
      <description>For both also speak of it as something different. Both, i.e. the Mādhyandinas as well as the Kāṇvas, distinguish in their texts the embodied soul, together with speech and other non-intelligent things, from the Ruler within, representing it as an object of his rule. The Mādhyandinas read, &amp;lsquo;He who dwells in the Self, whom the Self does not know,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.; the Kāṇvas, &amp;lsquo;He who dwells
within understanding&amp;rsquo;, &amp;amp;c. The declaration of the individual Self being ruled by the Ruler within implies of course the declaration of the former being different from the latter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/22/</guid>
      <description>That which possesses the qualities of invisibility, &amp;amp;c., on account of the declaration of attributes. The Ātharvaṇikas read in their text, &amp;lsquo;The higher knowledge is that by which that Indestructible is apprehended. That which is invisible, unseizable, without origin and qualities, &amp;amp;c., that it is which the wise regard as the source of all beings&amp;rsquo;; and further on, &amp;lsquo;That which is higher than the high Imperishable&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. I, 1, 5, 6; II, 1, 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/23/</guid>
      <description>Not the two others, on account of distinction and statement of difference. The section distinguishes the indestructible being, which is the source of all, &amp;amp;c., from the Pradhāna as well as the individual soul, in so far, namely, as it undertakes to prove
that by the cognition of one thing everything is known; and it moreover, in passages such as &amp;lsquo;higher than the high Indestructible,&amp;rsquo; explicitly states the difference of the indestructible being from those other two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/24/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the description of its form. &amp;lsquo;Fire is his head, his eyes the sun and the moon, the regions his ears, his speech the Vedas disclosed, the wind his breath, his heart the universe; from his feet came the earth; he is indeed the inner Self of all things&amp;rsquo; (II, 1, 4)&amp;ndash;the outward form here described can belong to none but the highest Self; that is, the inner Self of all beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/25/</guid>
      <description>Vaiśvānara (is the highest Self), on account of the distinctions qualifying the common term. The Cḥandogas read in their text, &amp;lsquo;You know at present that Vaiśvānara Self, tell us that,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c., and further on, &amp;lsquo;But he who meditates on the Vaiśvānara Self as a span long,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Cḥ. Up. V, 11, 6; 18, 1). The doubt here arises whether that Vaiśvānara Self can be made out to be the highest Self or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/26/</guid>
      <description>That which the text refers to is an inferential mark&amp;ndash;thus. The text describes the shape of Vaiśvānara, of whom heaven, &amp;amp;c., down to earth constitute the several limbs; and it is known from Scripture and Smr̥ti that such is the shape of the highest Self. When, therefore, we recognise that shape as referred to in the text, this supplies an inferential mark of Vaiśvānara being the highest Self.&amp;ndash;The &amp;rsquo;thus&amp;rsquo; (iti) in the Sūtra denotes a certain mode, that is to say, &amp;lsquo;a shape of such a kind being recognised in the text enables us to infer that Vaiśvānara is the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/27/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that it is not so, on account of the word, &amp;amp;c., and on account of the abiding within; we say, no; on account of meditation being taught thus, on account of impossibility; and because they read of him as person. An objection is raised. Vaiśvānara cannot be ascertained to be the highest Self, because, on the account of the text and of the abiding within, we can understand by the Vaiśvānara in our text the intestinal fire also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/28/</guid>
      <description>For the same reasons not the divinity and the element. For the reasons stated Vaiśvānara can be neither the deity Fire, nor the elemental fire which holds the third place among the gross elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/29/</guid>
      <description>Jaimini thinks that there is no objection to (the word &amp;lsquo;Agni&amp;rsquo;) directly (denoting the highest Self). So far it has been maintained that the word &amp;lsquo;Agni,&amp;rsquo; which stands in co-ordination with the term &amp;lsquo;Vaiśvānara,&amp;rsquo; denotes the highest Self in so far as qualified by the intestinal fire constituting its body; and that hence the text under discussion enjoins meditation on the highest Self. Jaimini, on the other hand, is of opinion that there is no reasonable objection to the term &amp;lsquo;Agni,&amp;rsquo; no less than the term: &amp;lsquo;Vaiśvānara,&amp;rsquo; being taken directly to denote the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/30/</guid>
      <description>On account of definiteness; thus Āśmarathya opines. The teacher Āśmarathya is of opinion that the text represents the highest Self as possessing a definite extent, to the end of rendering the thought of the meditating devotee more definite. That is to say&amp;ndash;the limitation due to the limited extent of heaven, sun, &amp;amp;c. has the purpose of rendering definite to thought him who pervades (abhi) all this Universe and in reality transcends all measure (vimāna).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/31/</guid>
      <description>On account of meditation, Bādari thinks. The teacher Bādari thinks that the representation in the text of the supreme Self in the form of a man is for the purpose of devout meditation. &amp;lsquo;He who in this way meditates on that Vaiśvānara Self as &amp;ldquo;prādeśamātra&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;abhivimāna,&amp;rdquo; he eats food in all worlds, in all beings, in all Selfs.&amp;rsquo; What this text enjoins is devout meditation for the purpose of reaching Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/32/</guid>
      <description>On account of imaginative identification, thus Jaimini thinks; for thus the text declares. The teacher Jaimini is of opinion that the altar is stated to be the chest of Vaiśvānara, and so on, in order to effect an imaginative identification of the offering to Prāṇa which is daily performed by the meditating devotees and is the means of pleasing Vaiśvānara, having the heaven and so on for his body, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/2/33/</guid>
      <description>Moreover, they record him in that. They (i.e. the Vājasaneyins) speak of him, viz. Vaiśvānara who has heaven for his head, &amp;amp;c.&amp;ndash;i.e. the highest Self&amp;ndash;as within that, i.e. the body of the devotee, so as to form the abode of the oblation to Prāṇa; viz. in the text,&amp;lsquo;Of that Vaiśvānara Self the head is Sutejas,&amp;rsquo; and so on. The context is as follows. The clause &amp;lsquo;He who meditates on the Vaiśvānara Self as prādeśamātra,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
