<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 The Ekāntins in the Pāñcarātra Literature on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 The Ekāntins in the Pāñcarātra Literature on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) The terms ekānta and ekāntin in the Pāñcarātra scriptures</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/1_i_The_terms_ekAnta_and_ekAntin_in_the/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/1_i_The_terms_ekAnta_and_ekAntin_in_the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a contribution to the volume &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya-Studien&lt;/em&gt;, Reinhold Grünendahl (1997) discusses the “profile of ideas” ( &lt;em&gt;Ideenprofil&lt;/em&gt;) which many later works borrow from the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;. In particular, he draws attention to a large number of parallel passages that the &lt;em&gt;Viṣṇudharmottarapurāṇa&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Viṣṇurahasya&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;Vaiṣṇavakhaṇḍa&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Skandapurāṇa&lt;/em&gt; 349 share with the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;. In this later literature, as we would expect, events from Part A of the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, such as Nārada’s journey to Mount Meru and his vision of White Island there, are retold from the &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; perspective of Part B. In the following, I address the history of one of the most important borrowings from the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; in the Pāñcarātra scriptural literature, namely the descriptions of a class of worshipper called ‘Ekāntin’. Here too, as we will see, it is the perspective of Part B of the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt; that shapes the religious identities of these “later” Ekāntins. I intend to ask here, in particular, what the appropriation of the idea of the Ekāntins in these scriptural works can tell us about the religious identities of the authors who take up the term, and the worshippers to whom it is applied. As in the last chapter, I begin by focussing on the employment of the word &lt;em&gt;ekānta&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) Becoming Ekāntin in South India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/2_ii_Becoming_ekAntin_in_South_India/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/2_ii_Becoming_ekAntin_in_South_India/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is clear that, from the time of the composition of the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;, the word &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt; has been used as a general term of commendation, as a means of conferring authority and expertise upon deserving persons, whether real or imagined. As we have seen in 364 ĀP 142.16-17: &lt;em&gt;yadi paraṃ te paramapuruṣam evāśritā ekāntinaḥ, anye kṣudradaivatakāḥ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;sādhāraṇā iti&lt;/em&gt;/. See also the SanS ( *Ṛṣirātra * 3.111cd), where *ekāntacintanā * is explained as “never thinking of another god” ( &lt;em&gt;deve nānyacintā kadācana&lt;/em&gt;). As we have seen, the SanS is quoted by Yāmuna, and so predates him. [[215]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/3_iii_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/5_MERGING_IDENTITIES_INTEGRATING_TRADITI/3_The_ekAntins_in_the_pAncharAtra_Litera/3_iii_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of the scriptural sources available to me which do not appear to have been authored by sectarian Pāñcarātrikas who called themselves ‘Ekāyana’, the JS, the ViṣṇuS, the ParS and the LT contain the most uses of the terms *ekānta * and &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt;. In the ParS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and the LT, the designation &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt; is employed within mythical narratives to name the ideal devotees. In this sense, their use of the term is continuous with that found in the &lt;em&gt;Nārāyaṇīya&lt;/em&gt;. Contrarily, the JS and the ViṣṇuS use the term to designate one particular class of Vaiṣṇava among others. The sections of the JS which describe Ekāntins are very likely South Indian in origin, as is the ViṣṇuS. The fact that they do not use the word &lt;em&gt;ekāntin&lt;/em&gt;/ &lt;em&gt;ekāntika&lt;/em&gt; as a general term of commendation, but as a label for a specific religious identity may indicate that the relevant portions of these texts are later than the ParS and the LT, or that they were authored within a different South Indian context to those works. Both the JS and the ViṣṇuS present the Ekāntins or Ekāntikas as renunciants, and both hint that they do not belong to the twice-born social classes. Unfortunately, their descriptions are very brief, and they do not contain enough information to enable us to affirm that they are describing the Pāñcarātrikas who call themselves Ekāyanas or Āgamasiddhāntins. [[226]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
