<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>avyakta origin mythology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/2006-07-31_avyakta-origin-mythology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/2006-07-31_avyakta-origin-mythology/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The two tantric upaniShads, avyakta and nR^isiMha-tApini are clear in their pA~ncharAtra affinities. Yet the saMkhya origin mythology of the avyakta is a pretty remarkable piece that is worth considering, for it is a rather distinctive expression of earliest stages of the universe. While in general concepts is similar to the thoughts expressed in other pA~ncharatra sAMkhya origin mythologies, such as the lakShmi-tantra, it different in the details. Of course it does not go into the details of the ta~nmAtras and their ontology like the account in the viShNu purANa, but its clarification of the early events in just two paragraphs is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mahopaniShat-antiquity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/mahopaniShat-antiquity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/upaniShat/articles/MT/mahopaniShat-antiquity/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
The text known as mahopaniShat that come down to us has at least 2 layers. The first section has a notable overlap with the nArAyaNavallI - see in the mahAnArAyaNopaniShat whose recensions are attached to the YV-taittirIya and atharvan traditions. This section as expounds nArAyaNa-paratvam along side a 25 tattva sAMkhya. It is clearly a vaiShNava text with sAMkhyan philosophical foundations overlapping with the ideas presented in the nArAyaNIya section of the Mbh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
