<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;kalai-quarrel on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;kalai-quarrel on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AchArya idol removal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/AchArya-idol-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/AchArya-idol-removal/</guid>
      <description>deshika-removal श्रीदेशिकनिष्कासने दश हस्त्या अङ्गुलयो दश पद्या अपर्याप्ता:
काञ्च्यामेव पञ्चदश तिरूक्कोविलूर मायवरम् तिरुच्चेरै तिरुप्पुल्लानि &amp;hellip; अनुवर्तते shrIvilliputtUr 1816 15. In the year 1816, the Thenkalais interfered with the Vadakalais feeding Brahmins in the Vedanta Desikar shrine and even in this interference they were worstedvide Exhibits G1, XIV (b), G3, G2 and G4. These documents show that the Tenkalais even went so far as to spitting in the Desikar shrine so as to prevent completely the feast being given in it and that for this outrage they were tried and convicted by the Magistrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goShThi exclusivity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/goShThi-exclusivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/goShThi-exclusivity/</guid>
      <description> Some 25 years ago as a young boy, I was silenced when I joined the Purusha Sukta ghoshti in Sriperumbudur during Udayavar thirumanjanam. Even though I complied, my head/hand were still going up and down with svarita/anudAtta and I was told to not even recite mentally by one gentleman &amp;hellip; similar treatment is faced by Tenkalaiyars in Oppiliappan Sannidhi, Tiruvahindrapuram etc.
vijay </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravilochana context</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/ravilochana-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/ravilochana-context/</guid>
      <description>If you go through our history, I find these facts which are mostly unacceptable to many today:
The nAmams did not determine which sampradaya you belonged to - till 18th century. And despite what some tenkalais may claim, both namams have been in use since long before. The oldest representations of namam in stone is seen only from Vijayanagar and in those temples, you find both kinds of namams in the same temple (hazara rama, vijaya vitthala, krishna, anantasayana etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>श्रीरङ्गधाम्नि देशिकापचारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/shrI-ranga-dhAmni_deshikApachAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/paramparA/articles/kalai-quarrel/shrI-ranga-dhAmni_deshikApachAraH/</guid>
      <description>समस्या स्वामिना बहिरागन्तुम् न शक्यते ।
विष्णूत्सवेषु विधिवासव-सेवितेषु
वीथीषु रङ्गनगरे कृत-चङ्क्रमौ तौ वेदान्त-सूरि-चरणौ शरणं प्रपद्ये।।
अहोबिल-मठाधिपतिः The 44th Srimath Azhagiyasingar (adiyen’s Aachaarya) - Even though Bhagavaan Sri RanganaaTha Himself Asked for it and His Holiness duly completed the construction of Sri-Rangam Raaja-Gopuram, His Holiness Did-Not go inside the Temple to have Sri RanganaaTha dharSanam - all because of one and only one reason - where there is NO respect for Swaamy Sri Vedhaantha-DeSika, HH didn’t consider that Temple as good enough even to offer worship to that Bhagavaan at such a place -</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
