<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pre-rAmAnuja vedAnta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/pre-rAmAnuja-vedAnta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/pre-rAmAnuja-vedAnta/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Broadly Ramanuja&amp;rsquo;s school of Vedanta identifies two traditions:
a tradition of personal education including spritual initiation, and a tradition of Vedantic exegesis. The most important pre-Ramanujan Acharyas in the tradition of personal education are Nammazhvar, Nathamuni and Yamunacharya. Thir works are well known:
Nathamuni&amp;rsquo;s works are lost but some fragments are available in quotations and citations. Yamunacharya&amp;rsquo;s works are partially available; the Siddhitrayam and the AgamaPramanyam being his most important works that are extant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rAmAnuja harmony</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/rAmAnuja-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/rAmAnuja-harmony/</guid>
      <description>Source: Indica, IndiaFacts
Śrī Rāmānuja’s Vedāntic Harmony: Samanvaya As A Paradigm For Social Harmony
M A Alwar
Śrī Rāmānuja was a philosopher par excellence and the famous proponent of the philosophy called Viśiṣṭādvaita. The religious side of that philosophy is called Śrīvaiṣṇavism. It is often said that philosophy without religion is lame and religion without philosophy is blind. Hence philosophy and religion should go hand in hand for their survival. On the one hand, the religious aspects needed for spiritual progress are strengthened by theoretical foundations and, on the other hand, philosophy finds purpose in the practice of religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>simhAsanAdhipatis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/siMhAsanAdhipatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/siMhAsanAdhipatis/</guid>
      <description>Given below is the list of 74 simhasanAdhipathis of YathirAjar, as appointed by Him. This list is provided by Sri Anbil Ramaswamy and is available in Ramanujacharya Home page created by Sri Achutharaman. (under Acharya vamsavruksham)
BHAGAVAD RAMANUJA&amp;rsquo;S SISHYAS WHOM HE NOMINATED AS SIMHASANA ADHIPATHIS: Bhagavad Ramanuja installed 74 of his disciples as Simhasana Adhipathis.
Authorities mainly are: AVM, GLE and ATA:-
Chottai Nambi, son of Aalavandaar Pundarika, son of Mahapurna Yaamuna, son of Goshti purna Sundara bahu, son of Maalaa dhaara Raamaanuja, son of Saila purna PARAASARA BHATTAR (and his brother, sons of Aalvaan) विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्) Parasara Bhattar was the son of Kurathalwan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>जगन्नाथ-पुरी-प्रभावः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/jagannAtha-purI-prabhAvaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/meta/articles/jagannAtha-purI-prabhAvaH/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Shri Anantavarman Chodaganga Deva Maharaja. The first prominent Ramanujadasa of Odisha . Under him , Srimandira underwent some changes that are now the hallmark of it.
The Lakshmi temple ,Sridevi and Bhudevi with Bhagavan and the kitchen are his influence (neighbouring states have all Saraswati with Vishnu).
Also the chalanti pratima concept and the mock quarrel between Lakshmi and Narayana as Bachanika .
These are common in Pancharatrika temples of the South too .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
