<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;गद्यम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kAvyam/gadyam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;गद्यम् on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kAvyam/gadyam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#43;वेङ्कटेशेतिहासमाला</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kAvyam/gadyam/venkaTeshetihAsa-mAlA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/kAvyam/gadyam/venkaTeshetihAsa-mAlA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TODO: परिष्कार्यम्&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tirumalai-Tirupati Devastanam Series.&#xA;VENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;श्रीवेङ्कटेश इतिहासमाला&#xA;2116&#xA;35602&#xA;EDITED BY&#xA;Rajasevasakta&#xA;UR DR. S. KRISHNASWAMI AIYANGAR, M.A., PH.D.&#xA;ublished under the authority of&#xA;RANGANATHA MUDALIAR AvL., B.A., B.L.,&#xA;Commissioner&#xA;Tirumalai-Tirupati Devasthanar&#xA;Tirupati.&#xA;1937.&#xA;le.&#xA;it reserved.)&#xA;35602&#xA;か&#xA;free fees देवस्थान ग्रन्थावलिः&#xA;श्रीः&#xA;श्रीवेंकटाचलेतिहासमाला श्रीमदनन्तार्यगुम्भिता |&#xA;THE PHINDIFAL S&#xA;10&#xA;राजसेवासक्तैः दिवानबहदुर डाक्टर शाखोट्टै कृष्णस्वाम्यय्यङ्गायैः परिशोधिता&#xA;देवस्थान सभाध्यक्षैः रङ्गनाथमुदलियैः&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;प्रकाशिता&#xA;Ar Heata V&#xA;*J JAYA33&#xA;3T13D HA&#xA;१९३७ (संवत्सरे)&#xA;ITARURITACED ON THE SHEL&#xA;SRI VENKATESWARA CENTRAL LIBRARY &amp;amp; RESEARCH CENTRE,&#xA;Acs. No&amp;hellip;&#xA;Date.&#xA;TIRUPATI.&#xA;FOREWORD.&#xA;The following, work was available only in a Telugu edition, copies of which have become rare. Manuscripts of the work do not seem to be available in Madras. An elabor- ate search may fetch a copy, possibly in Mysore. But even that seems doubtful so far. It has had therefore to be pub- lished from the Telugu edition, which, it is said, had the benefit of the learning of MM. Srirangacharya, the widely res- pected scholar of Tirupati.&#xA;The work is of considerable importance incorporating reliable tradition in regard to certain features of the temple organisation at Tirupati. The traditional information seems to have been collected from reliable sources, although we can- not as yet be certain as to the actual person who compiled the work, though the work states it, it was an Anantarya who did it. Notwithstanding this defect, the work deserves publication. Having had to look through the work for the purposes of a history of the holy shrine at Tirupati, which I have been commissioned to write for the Devastanam Com- mittee, I found the matter too valuable to be lost, and recom- mended its publication by the Devastanam Committee.&#xA;I have great pleasure in acknowledging the courtesy of Mr. A. Ranganatha Mudaliar, B.A.,B.L., Commissioner, Tiru- malai-Tirupati Devastanam, in agreeing to its publication among the Devastanam Series. I also acknowledge with pleasure here the assistance rendered by Sahitya Siromani S. Rajagopalacharyar, who has been working with me throughout.&#xA;S. KRISHNASWAMI AIYANGAR.SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;The Garland of Historical Tales of the Hill of&#xA;Venkata (Tirupati)&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;This is a work which professes to be a historical account of the various arrangements that were made from time to time for the conduct of worship in the temple on the hill at Vengaḍam. It is not a regular history of the temple in the sense that it gives an account of the temple from its origin down to the time of writing of this account, but is more or less a record of certain important incidents in its history. The whole account consists of seven chapters dealing with the topics connected with the contesting claims of Saivas and Vaishnavas to the temple, the settlement arrived at as a result of the discussion between the contesting claimants, the arrangements ordered in consequence thereof by the Vaishnava teacher Rāmānuja through the local ruler Yadava Raja. This is followed by the further arrangements that were called for and made subsequent to this, but all of them more or less during the life and under the commands of Rāmānuja. It may therefore be taken to be an account of what was done to the temple by Rāmānuja and does not purport to give the history of the shrine either in the period previous to Rāmā- nuja regarding which some allusions could be found here and there, and naturally nothing for the subsequent period. The work therefore deals as it were with one particular period of its history, which is comprised perhaps in the century after Christ, 1050 to 1150.4&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;THE SAIVA CLAIM&#xA;They said that the God who manifested himself in the temple on the south bank of the tank of Svami Pushkariņi was no other than the worshipful Skanda. They gave as a reason for this that the name Svāmi is peculiarly applicable to him as forming part of Kumārasvami which is the acknowledged name of Subrahmanya. The holy tank near the temple goes also by his name as belonging to him. There is nothing strange about it, they urged, as other names are similarly attributed in use, such as Bhimasēna being generally called Bhima and Satyabhama being generally called Bhāma.&#xA;They quoted for authority the Vamana Purāṇa which contains a section illustrative of the holiness of Vēnkaṭāchalā. Skanda is said to have consulted his father in regard to a place peculiarly holy to Vishnu, for performing a penance and getting rid of the sin of killing the Asura Taraka. The father, Siva, advised the son to go to Vēnkaṭāchala as the holiest of the holy places of Vishnu. Skanda went to Venkaṭāchala and per- formed his penance on the bank of a tank, according to Vāmana Purāņa, part ii. He there found Vayu (god of the air) also similarly performing penance, and, having paid his respects to him, he also set up there to do likewise. Therefore they urged that the God there ought to be regarded as God Kumārasvāmi. Being in the position of one performing a penance, they said, the God is there exhibited without his extra hands and characteristic weapons. For these and for many other good reasons they urged the place is really a holy place of Skanda, not Vishņu.&#xA;They pointed out further that for some time past some Vaishnavas took possession of the place and having there set up some of the Vaishnava images which did not exist in the témple before, took possession of the temple and conducted worship there as though it were a Vaishnava shrine, thus making people believe that it was a Vishņu temple; but in place without a doubt owing to the merits of the penance that Skanda had performed there,&#xA;actual truth that was a Saiva hol. ✨&#xA;ANY&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;5&#xA;Therefore they urged that in this temple everything would have to be conducted according to the prescription for worship laid down in the Saiva Agamaş.&#xA;Having heard this, the Yadavarāja began to ponder seriously over the matter, and, having known that for some considerable period of time the place was regarded as a Vaish- nava holy place and that worship was being conducted by the Vaishnavas according to the Vaikhānasa Āgama, he thought he should not commit himself to any course of action without proper investigation, notwithstanding what the Saivas urged.&#xA;The Vaishnavas that were left in Tirupati feeling themselves not competent to discuss with the Saivas on equal terms gave a detailed report of what took place to Rāmānuja then in residence in Srirangam.&#xA;On receipt of this information Rāmānuja set forward immediately from Śrirangam. Having reached Tirupati, he intimated the Yadavarāja of his arrival and offered to explain satisfactorily all the objections that the Saivas put forward against Tirupati being regarded a Vaishnava shrine, and prove to the satisfaction of the Yādavarāja, on the autho- rity of the Sastras, that Vēnkaṭāchala was the hill of Vishņu, and remove his doubt in regard to the matter. He informed the Raja he undertook the journey from Srirangam specially with a view to this.&#xA;Having been thus assured, the Yadavarāja brought together a great assembly of learned men both from among the Saivas and from the Vaishnavas, and having brought them together proposed the subject for their discussion in the proper form.&#xA;The Saivas stated that Kumārasvāmi obtained his father&amp;rsquo;s (Śiva&amp;rsquo;s permission and arrived at Venkatagiri (Tirupati). and set up to perform his penance on the bank of a holy tank, according to Vamana Purāṇa. There standing, with his feet touching the ground, on the south bank of the Svāmi Pushkariņi wearing a coiffure of matted locks and keeping aside the warlike weapons as unsuitable to an ascetic, Skanda shows himself in the form of an image to enable people to offer him worship and thus fulfil their cherished&#xA;76&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIĦASAMALA&#xA;wishes. Therefore they stated that the place where Skanda performed penance in the hill Vẽngaḍam must be regarded as a Saiva holy place.&#xA;They further asserted that this image of God can- not be said to be Vishnu. The weapons characteristic of Vishnu, such as the conch and the discus were not seen in the image; while the matted locks and nāga (serpent) orna- ments characteristic of other Gods are seen on the image. Therefore the image cannot be regarded as that of Vishnu.&#xA;Rāmānuja&amp;rsquo;s Answer: Before God Śrīnivāsa appeared on this hill, Brahma, Rudra and the other gods besides several Rishis are stated to have already begun performing penance there. If so, would it not be madness to state that one of those performing penance should be singled out as being exclusively associated with this hill and as giving it sanctity? Further than this, in the self-same Vāmana Purāņa, in chapter 14, Vēnkaṭāchalam is held up as a very holy place dedicated to Vishņu, whose temple was on the south bank of the Svāmi Pushkarņi. In the same Vamana Purāņa, in seve- ral other contexts, the place is described as the residence of Vishņu in the form of Varaha, and in the form of Śrīnivāsa. It is further stated to be a place fit for the residence of those devoted to Vishnu. Therefore it is clear that it was regarded as a place holy to Vishņu and not to any other.&#xA;In the same manner, the Varaha Purāņa states that Venkatachalam was the temple of Varaha-Vasudeva in the colloquy between Dharani (the earth) and Varaha in the first chapter of the Venkatachala Mahātmya section. There is an equally clear statement to this effect in the Padma Purana in chapter 24.1, and in the Garuda Purāņa in the colloquy between Arundati and Vasishța, in chapter 63. Simi- larly this hill is stated to be a Vishņu-kshētra in the Brah- mandapurāņa in the colloquy between Bhrigu and Nārada. So also other Purāņas make similar statements.&#xA;In addition to these clear statements, all the Purāņas state that this hill was the Krida-parvata, (sporting hill) in Vaikuntha wherefrom it was brought down by Garuda. In consequence, this hill is called the Vaikuntha-&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;7&#xA;giri, Garuḍāchalam and by other similar names. These would make it clear that the hill was sacred to Vishņu: More than this Vaidika Brahmans on occasions of the performance of ceremonies prescribed in the Śrutis and Smritis indicate this place as Varāha Kshētra. There is not much use in repeating the statement again and again. Even the Veda which is acknowledged to have no beginning, speaks of this `hill as a hill holy to Vishņu in the Rig-Veda (Eighth Ashṭaka,&#xA;eighth chapter and section 13).&#xA;On this clear exposition by Rāmānuja that the hill Venkatachala was a hill dedicated to Vishnu, the Yadava Rāja became quite clear in his mind that there was no reason for regarding the Saiva contention as deserving of any serious consideration.&#xA;Second Stabaka&#xA;Rāmānuja : &amp;ldquo;The Saivas assert that the name Svāmi Pushkarini indicates clear association with Kumārasvāmi.&amp;rdquo; This name was given to it because Kumārasvāmi performed his penance on the bank of this tank. The statement that, for this reason, the tank belongs to Skanda is not worthy of acceptance.&#xA;The meaning of the term Svami Pushkarini is that this tank is the lord of all similar tanks in the world. It is a term indicative of leadership or excellence. It is so explained in the Purāņas, and the Sanskrit compound is so explained. There- fore the term Svāmi cannot be held to apply to Kumārasvāmi as an abbreviation.&#xA;Moreover the term Svāmi can convey Śrīman Nārāyaṇa as he is the creator, protector and destroyer of all the worlds. Association with such an unparallelled leader&amp;rsquo;s name might as well be connoted by the term, if we make the first part of the compound a word in the genitive case which would not offend against Sanskrit grammar.&#xA;On the bank of that tank there are several beings engaged in the performance of penance. Kumārasvāmi is just one of them. The tank therefore cannot be the holy tank of Kumāra. Among the authorities quoted by my rivals in support of8&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;their contention, the following explain the name Svāmi Tirtha as the king among the holy waters or Tirthas. The authori- ties referred to are Vamana Puraṇa, chapter 40/25, Varāha Purāņa, First part, chapter 38, and chapter 50/18. So also the Venkatesa Sahasranāmāvali. Similarly, Varāha Purāṇa, part II, chapter i; Padma Purana, chapter 32. Further-in chapter 3 of the Mārkandēya Purāņa this tank is described as the king of similar holy tanks.&#xA;In the 2nd chapter of the Brahma Purāṇa, it is said that Sarasvati wished to be considered the holiest among the Tirthas, and obtained the boon from Brahma to the effect. She flowed as the river Sarasvati in consequence. Owing, however, to the curse of Pulastya, who found the flowing river inconvenient to him, she came down to Venkaṭāchalam as Svami Pushkariņi an unflowing tank. This implies that Svāmi Pushkariņi is the holiest of all holy tanks. Therefore in the Skanda Purāņa, part 11, chapter 1, and in part II of the same Purāṇa, the name Svāmi Pushkariņi for this tank is explained as being due to the presence on its banks of the two lords of the world Śrī Varāha and Śrīnivāsa. The name of the tank is explained as being due to their presence in such close proximity. This tank is described in the Varaha Purāṇa, part I, chapter 35, as the sporting tank of Vishņu in Vaikun- tha, and brought down to the earth along with Venkatachala.&#xA;On the basis of these authorities, it is clear that this tank is called Svämi Pushkarini for the following two reasons; First, a bath in it is capable of giving Sāyujya (union) with the deity, the lord (of the world) Nārāyaṇa; secondly it is called Svāmi Tīrtha because of its proximity to the Lord God of the world, Nārāyaṇa.&#xA;The holy Tirtha associated with Kumārasvāmi, however, is the one called Kumāra Dhāra. Even that is a Tīrtha holy to Vishnu because the whole of the hill Vēngaḍam has been described as the sporting ground of Vishnu. It is also regarded as the hill belonging to Vishņu-Varāha. Kumārasvāmi how- ever having found it necessary to perform a penance to Vishnu came to Vishnu&amp;rsquo;s hill and placed himself on the bank of the Vishnu Tīrtha in order that he might purify himsel&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;by a bath in that Tirtha, and perform his penance in the holy place. Since he chose that spot and that holy water, the stream there goes by the name Kumāra Dhāra. So Kumāra- svāmi has to be located not on the bank of the Svămi Push- kariņi, but near the Kumāra Dhāra or Kumāra Dhārikā.&#xA;When the Yadavarāja heard these arguments from Rāmā- nuja, he showed the greatest respect to Ramanuja and ac- cepted his conclusion as the only acceptable conclusion.&#xA;Third Stabaka&#xA;Seeing that the Yadava Rāja was feeling convinced by the arguments of Rāmānuja the Saivas grew jealous and addressed him as follows.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;O, King. In whatever manner the name Varāha Kshētra is appropriate to Vengaḍam by the fact of association with the deity Varaha, in the same manner the name could be derived from that of Kumāra Svāmi by association. Although it may be true that the Tīrtha Svāmi Pushkariņi may be the Tirtha par excellence, this fact does not debar the name being derived from association with Kumāra Svāmi. Therefore as the form of any other God than Vishnu cannot be got out of the image which adorns the southern bank, so the God represented by the image on the holy tank nearby could not be got rid of association with other. Gods than Vishnu.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Further we do not assert that the hill has no kind of a connection with Vishnu. We take it upon ourselves to state that the image of God on. the southern bank of the Svāmi Pushkariņi. is Skanda. We say further, by this fact, that this tank is associated with Skanda. The features of other Gods which are found in this image cannot possibly be hidden by anybody.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Having heard this, the Yadava Rāja said to the Saivas that what they stated did not appear to him appropriate. &amp;ldquo;It is stated in the Puranas &amp;ldquo;, he said, “that this hill Venkaṭāchala was the place sacred to Vishņu, and as such Kumāra Svāmi came there to make penance and get rid of the sin of having slain Därakasura. Further than this, since it is stated that the divine sporting-hill of God Vishnu was brought down by10&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;Garuda from Vaikuntha, it follows that the tank of divine holiness was also the same God&amp;rsquo;s sporting tank. If so, it cannot follow that the name Svāmi Pushkariņi was given to the tank because of Skanda performing his penance on the bank of this tank. &amp;ldquo;Therefore it is clear&amp;rdquo;, he said, &amp;ldquo;that you are in no position to give an effective reply to the arguments adduced by Rāmānuja Muni to establish that there was no manner of a connection between this tank and any other God, and there- före what Rāmānuja Muni had actually proved seemed quite adequate to establish his contention. What remains to be done therefore is only whether the God represented by the image on the south bank of the tank is Vishņu or Skanda. Even in regard to that, I shall ask Rāmānuja Muni to state what he may have to adduce as satisfactory reason.&amp;rdquo; So saying he addressed Rāmānuja with much attention and respect.&#xA;Yadava Rāja: Addressing sage Rāmānuja, the Yadava Rāja said:&amp;ldquo;It was clearly demonstrated, by what the sage had already urged as evidence, that the shrine on the south bank of the Svāmi Pushkariņi was a Vaishnava holy place, and that the tank itself was a Vaishnava holy tank. He said that he was prepared to accept that position; but wanted that Ramanuja should put it beyond a doubt by evidence that the deity on the south bank was Mahāvishņu, and no other god.&amp;rdquo; Thus addressed by the Rāja, Rāmānuja put forward his argu- ments as follows-&#xA;**&#xA;Rāmānuja: Bespeaking the Raja&amp;rsquo;s attention, Rāmā- nuja said It was well recognised by all that the deity on the south bank of the tank was Vishņu and no other, and there was little in it that required to be proved by him. That the lord on the hill Vēnkața was only Madhusudana without an equal, and there is not the slightest reason to sus- pect that the deity there is any other god. To say that he is Skanda is to assert that the light emitted by the fire-fly is sun- light. Proceeding to evidence, the Purāņas which are accepted and read as authoritative holy books, all of them declare with- out a doubt that the deity on the south bank is no other than Nārāyaṇa, the lord of Śri (goddess Lakshmi). In the first chapter of the second part of the Varaha Purāņa God Varāha himself is made to say that Śrīnivāsa appeared on the south&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;11&#xA;bank of the tank to grant the boon prayed for by Vāyu (god of the air) who was in penance for the purpose. He also stated that Śrīnivāsa was going to remain there to the end of the kalpa (one of the greater periods of time) and was going to be worshipped by Kumārasvāmi (Skanda or Subrahmanya). In the face of the statement, it cannot be argued that the Śrīnivāsa is Skanda. Further it is stated that Skanda per- formed a penance in the presence of Śrīnivāsa with a view to get rid of the evil attaching to him by his killing the Asura Tāraka. How then can Skanda the worshipper be transformed into Skanda the object of worship. It is not only in this Purāņa, but in several of the Purāņas describing the great merits of Venkaṭāchala, it is clearly stated that Śrīnivāsa and Varaha, both of them forms of Vishnu, were respectively on the south and west banks of the holy tank under reference. More than this the Bhavishyottarapurāṇa recounts a colloquy which took place between Śrīnivāsa and Varäha. When Śrīnivāsa married Padmavati, the daughter of Akāśa Rāja, it is stated in the Puranas that both Varaha and his consort Bhumi (the goddess of earth) were invited. Thus there are many stories in the Purāņas which state that both Srîni- vāsa and Varāha were separately enshrined on the south and west banks of the tank. Much more than this, as we stated already in the first stabaka, the term sirimbiḍasya used in the Rig Veda, Eighth Ashtaka, eighth chapter, 13th Varga (sec- tion) is explained as referring to Śrīnivāsa. The deity in this shrine has a single face and four arms, while it is stated that Skanda at birth had only one head and two hands; and that when it came to a question of being nursed by the Pleides (Krittika) he is said to have acquired six faces and twelve hands. Further than this when Skanda resolved to go to Vēnkatachala for performing penance, he is said, by the Šaivas, to have given up all his weapons. This is obviously an error, as others who went on a similar purpose, such as Raghava (Vishņu as Rama) and the Pāṇḍavas when they went to perform penance carried their weapons with them. The Vamana Purāņa in chapters 22 and 23 states clearly that when Skanda went to perform penance he carried all his weapons with him. It is not stated elsewhere in the work that he laid&#xA;·12&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;down the weapons. The deity that is present here, however, is shown with two hands in the posture of holding weapons, and the other two in the pose of granting people boons and giving them refuge. The right hand is in the posture of giving boons and the left hand is placed on the thigh just above the knee as if to indicate that that is the limit of suffering to all seeking salvation. It is clear therefore that the image here is intended to represent God Nārāyaṇa. For Skanda in Venkaṭā- chalam to which he had gone to perform penance, the image representing him ought to be that of a penitent devotee, not an image to be worshipped. It is hardly necessary to say any- thing further. This image has on its right chest the Srivatsa, the seat of Lakshmi, which is inappropriate to any other God. Therefore this is conclusive proof that the image is a represen- tation of Vishnu. Further, according to the Vamana Purāṇa, chapter 40/21, there is an account of Brahma and other gods having obtained a view of the deity in the divine Vimāna (sanctum) of this temple. On that occasion Vishnu is said to have appeared to human beings as the image of Śrīnivāsa in the sanctum built by man. It is clear from this account that. the deity enshrined in the temple was intended to be Śrīnivāsa and no other. In chapter 24/5 of the same work, it is stated clearly that Skanda who was in residence near the Kumāra Dhārikā came down daily, bathed in the Svāmi Pushkariņi and worshipped Śrīnivāsa. This is narrated to Parvati by God Paramasiva. From this account, it is clear that the deity on the south bank of the Svämi Pushkariņi was not regarded as Skanda, but Srinivasa daily worshipped there by Skanda. Further than this in the Varaha Purana, chapters 50/18, it is set down that Mahādēva, the father of Skanda made a request of God Vishņu that he himself might also have a place of residence allotted to him on the hill, and that he was directed in reply to have his residence at the foot of the hill. Therefore it becomes clear that God Mahādēva him- self had no kind of residence on this hill. In chapter III of the Brahmapurāņa, it is stated that Šankarāja built the temple and set up the image of Srinivasa in it as a result of Śrīnivāsa&amp;rsquo;s coming into his view. Again the Dravida saint Nammālvār refers to the god at Tirupati in his Tiruväymoli which is re-&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;13&#xA;garded as the Veda itself in Tamil. In that work the image in this holy place is clearly stated to be Vishņu and no other. This is confirmed by statements made by the other Alvārs in regard to this particular holy place.&#xA;The fact that the image of this god here is not in posses- sion of the conch and the discus is explained as follows. He had a great devotee in a ruler of the locality generally known as Tonḍaman Chakravarti. At one time when he had to carry on war against his enemies who had the better of him, Vishņu lent him his pair of weapons to secure him victory, as is generally well known. He had remained since then without these weapons for a considerable length of time at the Tonda- man&amp;rsquo;s request. This is stated in the 7th chapter of the Brahma- purāṇa, and is confirmed by the account found in the 11th chapter of the Brahmānḍa Purāņa as well.&#xA;There is no allusion anywhere to Skanda having lent his weapons to anybody, or of having laid them aside for purposes of penance. It is therefore clear that the deity here is not Skanda.&#xA;In regard to the other points brought out prominently by the Śaivas, namely, that on occasions, the pūja is performed with bilva in this temple, bilva (marmelos) which is a pecu- liar article with which to worship Śiva; the absence of wea- pons characteristic of Vishnu to support the conclusion that the image is that of Vishnu; the possession of features peculiar to other gods, such as the coiffure of matted locks of hair, the wearing of jewels of the pattern of cobras (nāgas); these could be satisfactorily met by the following arguments. The argu- ment of the absence of weapons has already been met above. In regard to the character of Śrīnivāsa as a manifestation of Vishnu, many Purāņas in several places state clearly that the Śrīnivāsa in Venkaṭāchalam is but an avatar of Vishnu in Vaikuntha. In offering proofs, it must be recognised that the authority of sacred texts is superior to that of inference. The texts referring to this deity, it was already pointed out, are quite clear in respect of its Vishnu character. The bilva is quite as acceptable to Devi (Lakshmi) as Tulasi (basil) is. Whatever is acceptable to his consort Lakshmi is equally14&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;acceptable to god Śrīnivāsa. Even in the $ästras, bilva (marmelos) is included among the articles with which pūja (worship) is to be performed on an equal footing with tulasi (basil). That bilva is acceptable to Lakshmi is stated clearly in the Śrīsūkta (prayer addressed to Lakshmi). The Hārīta- smrti mentions bilva as one of the principal objects of use for worship. Coming down to evidence, the Varāha Purāņa, in part i, chapter 45/13, describes the appearance of Śrīnivāsa on Venkatachalam to Dasaratha, and it is stated there that the rishis who were living on the south bank of the Svāmi Push- kariņi performing penance worshipped him on occasions with bilva. In the second part of the same Puräṇa, chapter 9, it is stated that Mahalakshmi generally resides in gardens where bilva is cultivated. Thus it is clear from the statements in the Śruti, Smrti, Itihasa and Purāņa that worship with bilva is appropriate to Vishnu.&#xA;Vishnu is stated to have allowed his hair to grow into matted locks in several of his avatars. The existence of the matted locks therefore need not be held to detract from the Vaishnava character of the image. In the Śrī Bhāgavata, book ii, chapter 5, in the colloquy between emperor Nimi and the sage Navayōgīśvara, it is laid down clearly that on special occasions worship may be offered to Vishnu wearing a coiffure of matted locks. Similarly in the 12th chapter of the Pancha- rātra, the Sātvata Samhita, one is advised to contemplate Vishnu as having a coiffure of matted locks and a beard, carry- ing in his one hand the danda (a stick of palāśa or aśvaka carried by Sanyāsis and Brahmacharis) and kamandala in an- other and as wearing a garland of lotus seeds. Similarly Vishnu is described to have worn matted locks in several avataras. It cannot therefore be held that the wearing of matted locks is the characteristic of other gods only. More than this the Skanda Purāņa in part I, chapter 10, states that Śrīnivāsa wore the matted locks when he appeared in Vēn- kaṭāchala. A similar statement is made in Vāmana Purāņa, chapter 34/15.&#xA;It is stated in Skanda, Vämana, Varaha, Pādma and other Puranas that, at the request of Brahma and of other Gods,&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;15&#xA;Vishnu suppressed his fearsome form and assumed a more pleasant looking shape. In the Padma Purāṇa, chapter 26/3, Vishnu is said to have been dressed up in cloth carrying figures of nāga. In chapter 27/4 of the same work he is said to be wearing matted locks. In chapter 33/10 a fearsome form and a pleasant form are both described as forms alike of Vishnu. In the Bhavishyottara Purāṇa, chapter 11, it is stated that Ākāśa Rāja presented jewels made in the form of cobras to Śrīnivāsa on the occasion of his marriage with the Raja&amp;rsquo;s daughter Padmavati. In the esoteric sections of the Bhavish- yottara Purāṇa, Śrīnivāsa is said to have worn jewels in the form of Nagas, where Paramēśvara expounds Śrīnivāsa to Parvati. The Brahmanda Purāņa, chapter 2, states that the great Nāga Adiśēsha serves as all kinds of dress and decorat- ive ornaments. In Pädma Purana, chapter 34/11, Śrīnivāsa is said to reside along with Lakshmi on the hill which was an incarnation of Adiśēsha. In the Brahmanḍa Purāṇa, in the chapter containing Vēnkaṭēśa Sahasranama, Vishnu is stated to have matted locks, the conch and the weapon sakti (a javelin or short double sword used as a throw weapon), and jewels in the form of cobras. It is further stated that God there appeared in both the forms. It is therefore clear that jewels in the shape of Nāga were always worn by Śrīnivāsa. It cannot therefore be said that that form of jewel is peculiar only to other gods. Further, since we have now offered proof, it is wrong to regard these features, the use of bilva, the absence of the conch and discus and the wearing of the matted locks and nāga jewels as necessarily peculiar to other gods. It would be equally clear that, if these are peculiar to Śiva as our opponents say, they could hardly be appropriate to Skanda. These contentions are therefore clearly baseless.&#xA;The image of god that appears before us has the mark of Śrīvatsa, and carries Lakshmi on his chest. These make it clear that He is God Nārāyaṇa and nobody else. Nārāyaṇa is stated to be the only primeval being. Brahma and Šiva and other gods sprang from him. Nārāyaṇa is again stated to be the creator of the universe, its protector and ultimate des- troyer. That it is from this primeval Supreme that Brahma, Siva and others arose is stated clearly in the Upanishads. If16&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITIHASAMALA&#xA;Nārāyaṇa is the cause of creation, protection and destruction, and, as the cause can contain features that appear in the con- sequence, the wearing of the matted locks and the nāga jewel is but an indication that Brahma and Śiva emanated from him. This form of Vishnu is described with the same features in the Satvata Samhita. In the Padma Purāṇa, chapters 27/3, these powers are ascribed to Vishnu, and he is also stated to be surrounded by the various powers to carry out these func- tions. It therefore becomes clear that the features pointed out by our opponents as peculiar to other gods become as much features of Vishnu.&#xA;The next point for consideration is what the quotation from the Padma Purāņa above conveys, namely, that Närä- yana is the primary cause of all that exists. Vamana Purāņa, chapter 24 (end of the chapter) states that the form of Srinivasa is the primal form of Nārāyaṇa himself. It is in conformity with this, that Pey Alvar describes him as exhi- biting the two forms, namely, that of Vishnu and Śiva. In chapter 21/2 of the same work, it is stated that Vayu made an incantation of the saving mantra Rama, and that Skanda did so also, having obtained the mantra from his father Śiva. The Brahmanda Purana, chapter 2, and Brahma Purāņa chapter 2 alike, state that it was Adisesha that became the sporting hill of God and thus gained the enjoyment of God&amp;rsquo;s perpetual presence on him. Both Varaha Purāņa, part II, chapter 3, and Padma Purana, chapter 32/10 state clearly that Śrīnivāsa came down to the earth at the commencement of Kritayuga. Therefore the god whose image is on the southern bank of the Svami Pushkariņi with all the features, such as the wearing of the matted locks, the cobra ornaments, worship with bilva, etc., is no other than Śrīnivāsa, the con- sort of Lakshmi, the lord of Vaikuntha, who came to reside in Venkatachalam, worshipped by Skanda, Mahādēva and others. It is thus clear that He is Sriman Nārāyaṇa and no other like Skanda or Śiva.&#xA;When Rämänuja thus concluded his arguments, the Yādava Räja told the Śaivas that he felt convinced that their arguments were all satisfactorily met by Ramanuja, and that,&#xA;INTRODUCTION&#xA;17&#xA;if they had anything further to urge, they might do so the next day, and requested Rāmānuja that further arguments will continue on the following day. When again they as- sembled, the Saivas urged that the deity on the south bank of Svami Pushkariņi is either Skanda or Mahādēva, and if not, it must be Harihara; but it never could be Vishnu. They urged in support that the emblems of Vishnu were not in- compatible with the deity being Skanda, as the Vamana Purāņa, chapter 21/2 where the origin of Skanda is recounted by Brhaspati, it is stated clearly that Skanda had a part of Vishnu in him. Since Skanda is said to have one head and two arms, or six heads and twelve arms, it may not be in- appropriate if sometimes he had one head and four arms. If, however, this is objected to, we claim the image to be that of Mahādēva on the same argument as the Vaishnavas who claim these peculiar features as not unsuitable to Vishnu, the primal cause of the universe, as we claim Mahādēva to be the primal cause. Even otherwise since the Vaishnavas claim that the god is Vishnu, because of some of the Vaish- ņava Agamas, so we call him Šiva because of the Saiva signs in the image. Again if it is inappropriate to regard him as Mahādēva, he is certainly Harihara, since the signs of both Vishnu and Śiva are found in the image, and even Vaishnava saints have so described them. Therefore in Skanda Purāna chapter 8, Śrīnivāsa is described as Mahādēva, as also in several other places, where the two terms are used together. Therefore we may be certain that it is Harihara and nobody else. Similarly in the Padma Purāņa, chapter 27/4 des: cribing the coming down of the God, he is said to have worn face mark resting upon a base resembling that of the eighth day moon. This part moon is a characteristic of Śiva, and is generally associated with him. Therefore the image must be regarded as that of Harihara. Any other contention beyond the three seems to us unacceptable.&#xA;The Yadava Rāja replied that he could not agree with the Saivas in respect of the image being regarded as either Skanda or Mahādēva, but whether it could be Harihara, he would ascertain from Rämänuja himself. Rāmānuja replied that all that was urged by the Saivas was wrong. In chapter18&#xA;SRIVENKATACHALA ITÍHASAMALA&#xA;10 of the Bhagavat Gita, Krishna says everything that exists has a part of Vishņu in it, and therefore even Skanda and Mahādēva must necessarily contain a part of Vishnu. It does not require much further argument. In the Vamana Purāṇa, chapter 21/2, it is stated that Skanda is said to have had his three baths daily and worshipped Nārāyaṇa in the presence of Vayu who was also there performing his penance. Since he is said to be contemplating upon Nārāyaṇa to get rid of the sin of killing Tārakāsura, and since, in chapter 24/5 of the same work, Vāyu is said to be performing penance long since to God Śrīniväsa in the same place, and since Skanda is said to have been worshipping Srinivasa ever since, it would be absurd to say that the worshipping Skanda and the worshipped Śrīnivāsa are one and the same.&#xA;Further, another question arises. It is admitted that on the south bank of the tank, there is an image of a god en- shrined in a temple. It is stated equally clearly in the same Purāņas that Skanda came there to perform penance to Vishnu to get rid of the sin of his having killed Tārakāsura in battle. These Purāņas again say that in the same place God Śrīnivāsa appeared for the benefit of Brahma and the other Devas, the Brahmarishis and Rajarishis and others who were performing penance there with the same object. The question therefore airses whether the God referred to as being on the south bank of the tank is, in the circumstances, Skanda or Srinivasa. It can hardly be Subrahmanya because he is said to have come there to get rid of his sin by penance, attracted towards the place for gaining the grace of Vishnu, and therefore one among the many like Brahma and others who were similarly engaged. How can Skanda then be regarded as the object of worship to the others? More than this, the same Purāņas assert that Skanda came daily from the Kumāra Dhärikā to offer worship to Śrīnivāsa, and there- fore it cannot be said, on their authority, that Skanda&amp;rsquo;s habi- tual residence was on the south bank of the Svāmi Pushkariņi. Nor is this fact of the establishment of Skanda in a shrine stated in any of our authorities. Moreover the same Pură- nas state that Šankarāja and Tondaman Chakravarti built a shrine to Vishnu who appeared in response to the penance of&#xA;शुद्धाशुद्धपत्रिका&#xA;शुद्धः 1. विशेषतो&#xA;अशुद्धः&#xA;Page&#xA;Line&#xA;विशषतो&#xA;3.&#xA;13&#xA;2. वैखानस&#xA;वैरवानस&#xA;do&#xA;14&#xA;3. नगरी&#xA;नगिरी&#xA;6&#xA;4&#xA;4. शास्त्रानुसारेण&#xA;शास्त्रानुसारेण&#xA;7&#xA;19&#xA;5. दृष्टवानसि&#xA;6. अम्बरीषादिभिः&#xA;7. उपोद्घाते&#xA;दष्टवानसि&#xA;8&#xA;24&#xA;अम्बरीपादिभिः&#xA;10&#xA;19&#xA;उपोद्घाते&#xA;12&#xA;24&#xA;8. शब्द&#xA;शब्द&#xA;21&#xA;17&#xA;9. विंशाङ्क&#xA;विशाङ्क&#xA;29&#xA;3&#xA;10. पद्मनाभोऽन&#xA;पद्मनाभोऽथ&#xA;31&#xA;18&#xA;11. संप्रति&#xA;सप्रति&#xA;32&#xA;17&#xA;12. आराध्यत्वेन&#xA;अराध्यत्वेन&#xA;39&#xA;4&#xA;13. अद्याप्यत्र&#xA;अद्याष्यत्र&#xA;do&#xA;2222&#xA;14. शङ्खचक्र&#xA;शाङ्खचक&#xA;41&#xA;24&#xA;15. शक्तयायुध&#xA;16. क्षितीशेन&#xA;शक्यायुध क्षिताशेन&#xA;58&#xA;. 1&#xA;64&#xA;13&#xA;17. नासौ&#xA;18. किंचित्पुरस्तत्&#xA;नासा&#xA;20&#xA;70&#xA;1&#xA;किचिन्तरस्वात्&#xA;.do&#xA;16&#xA;19. रुद्रस्य&#xA;रुद्रस&#xA;75&#xA;2&#xA;20. -दिष्विति&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
