<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०० on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०० on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>१ FOREWORD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/1_FOREWORD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/1_FOREWORD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is my pleasant privilege to announce the fifth edition of&#xA;“KRIYADHIKARA” which is widely read by the Pandits of&#xA;Vaikhanasa Agama and followed in the temples where the tradition&#xA;of Vaikhanasa is in vogue.&#xA;This book was published first in 1953 under the editorship of&#xA;“Vaikaranapancanana” Sri R. Parthasarathi Bhattacarya, recipient&#xA;of President Award.  Subsequently it was reprinted in 1981, 1998&#xA;and 2018.&#xA;“KRIYADHIKARA” is the creation of sage Bhrugu who is&#xA;instrumental for the incarnation of Sri Maha Vishnu as Sri&#xA;Venkateswara of Seven Hills. This book which is also known as&#xA;Bhrugu Samhita covers the entire spectrum of rites ranging from&#xA;“Karshana” (digging the earth) to “Prathishta” (placing the idol) in&#xA;39 chapters.&#xA;I record my thanks to Prof. S. Sudarsana Sarma, Vice-&#xA;Chancellor of TTD Sponsored S.V. Vedic University and his team&#xA;for taking the pains of editing the book and preparing the press&#xA;copy.  I believe that also this edition will be received well by the&#xA;Pandits and Archakas of Vaikhanasa Agama as the previous ones.&#xA;Tirupati&#xA;06.09.2021&#xA;Om Namo Venkatesaya.&#xA;Dr. K.S. JAWAHAR REDDY,  I.A.S&#xA;Executive Officer&#xA;T.T. Devasthanams&#xA;iv&#xA;v&#xA;vi&#xA;vii&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>२ INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/2_INTRODUCTION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/vaikhAnasaH/AgamaH/bhRgu-saMhitA/kriyAdhikAraH/v2021/00/2_INTRODUCTION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present work of Kriyadhikara of Bhrgu is the fourth&#xA;of the Samhitas of the Vaikhanasa Agama to be published by&#xA;the Oriental  Institute. With this the Institute would have&#xA;published the four Samhitas of the four Vaikhanasa Rsis -&#xA;Marici, Atri, Kasyapa and Bhrgu. Of these that by the last&#xA;named appears to be the most comprehensive and so the&#xA;most important. Although the general contents of all the&#xA;Samhitas are on the whole identical, still there are minor&#xA;details some of which will find a place in one while others&#xA;in the others. A comprehensive conspectus of the contents&#xA;of the four Samhitas so far published by the Institute will be&#xA;included in the proposed Introduction to Vaikhanasa&#xA;Literature in English. This introduction has been promised&#xA;in my Introduction to the Jnanakanda of Kasyapa which was&#xA;published in 1948 but owing to preoccupations I have not&#xA;been able to redeem my promise upto now. God willing, I&#xA;hope to present it to the public in the near future.&#xA;I consider Bhrugu as the most important of Vaikhanasa&#xA;authors because while the others contented themselves with&#xA;writing an elaborate account of the Kriya portion of the&#xA;Agama, leaving the Carya to be learnt from the Vaikhanasa&#xA;Kalpa Sutra, our author not only treated of the Kriya portion&#xA;but wrote an elaborate account of Carya also in the so called&#xA;Manusmrti. This fact is borne out by the many points of&#xA;contact between this Smrti and the Vaikhanasa literature.&#xA;More about this in my introduction to the Vaikhanasa&#xA;literature but I am referring to the point here to show the&#xA;importance of the present Samhita.&#xA;viii&#xA;Now that four of the important Samhitas have been&#xA;published by the Institute, it will hereafter take up the&#xA;publication of important commentaries and Manuals relating&#xA;to the School.&#xA;I am indebted to Mr. R. Parthasarathi Bhattachar, the&#xA;editor of this work, for the trouble he has taken in settling&#xA;the text of the Samhita and in securing a number of&#xA;manuscripts from his friends for the purpose. An account&#xA;of the material used in preparing the edition is given by him&#xA;in his Sanskrit Introduction.&#xA;P.V. RAMANUJASWAMI,&#xA;Director&#xA;Tirupati&#xA;Date : 25-2-1953&#xA;ix&#xA;x&#xA;xi&#xA;xii&#xA;xiii&#xA;80&#xA;xiv&#xA;1-155-1&#xA;xv&#xA;1118&#xA;xvi&#xA;xvii&#xA;xviii&#xA;xix&#xA;xx&#xA;101551&#xA;xxi&#xA;xxii&#xA;xxiii&#xA;xxiv&#xA;xxv&#xA;xxvi&#xA;xxvii&#xA;xxviii&#xA;xxix&#xA;xxx&#xA;xxxi&#xA;xxxii&#xA;xxxiii&#xA;xxxiv&#xA;xxxv&#xA;(Executive&#xA;Officer) B.A.,&#xA;M.A.,&#xA;xxxvi&#xA;xxxvii&#xA;xxxviii&#xA;xxxix&#xA;xl&#xA;xli&#xA;xlii&#xA;xliii&#xA;xliv&#xA;xlv&#xA;xlvi&#xA;xlvii&#xA;xlviii&#xA;xlix&#xA;l&#xA;li&#xA;lii&#xA;liii&#xA;liv&#xA;lv&#xA;श्रीः&#xA;श्री श्रीनिवासपरब्रह्मणे नमः&#xA;श्रीमते श्रीविखनसमहागुरवे नमः&#xA;श्रीवैखानसे भगवच्छास्त्रे भृगुप्रोक्तासु संहितासु&#xA;क्रियाधिकारः&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
