<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;govindAchArya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;govindAchArya on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/00/</guid>
      <description>Works by the same Author-In English. Bhagavad-gita with Rāmānuja&amp;rsquo;s com- Rs. A. P.
mentaries&amp;hellip; 5 0
Lives of the Draviḍa Saints (Azhvārs). I 8
Lives of Rāmānuja and other Sages
(with frontispiece etc.)&amp;hellip; 2 12
Divine Wisdom of the Dravida Saints.
Vade-Mecum of Vedanta
N
O
O
O
O
Artha-Pañçaka or Five Truths (JRAS) 0 12 O
Vedanta and Theosophy
Three Parts: Lectures on Inspira-
4 6
tion, Intuition and Ecstacy&amp;hellip; I O O</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 PERCEPTION (Pratyaksha)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/01_PERCEPTION_Pratyaksha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/01_PERCEPTION_Pratyaksha/</guid>
      <description>INVOCATORY VERSES.
Sri-Venkatesam Kari-Saila-natham Śri-Devarājam Ghatik-adri-simham Krshṇena sākam Yatirājam iḍe Svapne ca drshṭān mama Deśik-endrān. 2. Yatiśvaram praṇamya &amp;lsquo;ham Vedant-aryam Mahā-gurum Karomi bāla-bodhārtham
Yatindra-mata-dipikām.
1
The King of Yatis&amp;rsquo; or ascetics Ramanuja.
4
&amp;lsquo;I have adopted Advent&amp;rsquo; for the Samskṛt word Avatara.
⚫ Sri means Blessed, metaphorically She is Lakshmı or the Mediatrix, the Mother.
Nārāyaṇa is the All-N
God, and metaphorically He is the Father. Thus Śriman-Nārāyapa - The Universe&amp;rsquo;s Mother-Father Principle = God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 INFERENCE (Anumāna)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/02_INFERENCE_anumAna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/02_INFERENCE_anumAna/</guid>
      <description>Now, Anumana or Inference will be ex- pounded:
That knowledge (Pramiti) is Inferential knowledge (Anumiti), which is the particular knowledge of the pervading (Vyāpaka), obtained from the consideration of the pervaded- ness of the pervaded (Vyāpaka) &amp;ldquo;. The Instrument or Means by which such knowledge is obtained is Inference (Anumāna). (Illustra- tion): Knowing that smoke is pervaded by fire, the knowledge of the pervading is obtained, ie., fire.
The Pervaded (Vyāpya) is ruled by limit- edness of space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 THE WORD (Śabda)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/03_THE_WORD_shabda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/03_THE_WORD_shabda/</guid>
      <description>After the exposition of Inference (Anumāna), the word (Śabda)1 will be expounded.
111
Śabda-Pramāņa or the Instrument (or Means) viz, &amp;lsquo;Word&amp;rsquo;, is that which produces the know- ledge obtained from sentences non-uttered by the non-trustworthy (men) (An-āptā). Non-uttered by the Non-trustworthy&amp;rsquo; is (a characterisation advisedly) employed to controvert the opinion that &amp;rsquo;the Word&amp;rsquo; (Vedas) is of human origin. Or the Word&amp;rsquo; is that which is exempt from the sense-errors (Karana-dosha) and con-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 OBJECT OF KNOWLEDGE (Prameya)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/04_OBJECT_OF_KNOWLEDGE_Prameya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/04_OBJECT_OF_KNOWLEDGE_Prameya/</guid>
      <description>MATTER (Prakṛti.)
After the treatment of Pramāņa (or Means of knowledge) Prameya &amp;quot;&amp;quot; or Object of knowledge will be treated. Prameya (literally) means what is well (pra), measured (meya).
It (Object) is twofold: Dravya or Substance, and A-dravya or Non-Substance. Substance is the Upādāna or Substrate, Base or Receptacle; and the Receptacle is the Abode of States or Modes (Avasthâ-&amp;ldquo;śraya).
How, it may be asked, is this twofold division: Substance and Non-Substance to be maintained, when other schools enumerate a six-fold divi- sion:-Dravya or Substance, Guna or Quality, Karma or action, Sāmānya or Genus etc ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 TIME (Kāla)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/05_TIME_kAla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/05_TIME_kAla/</guid>
      <description>180
Now, the species of the Non-Conscient (Acit), viz., Time, will be treated. Time is (an) inert (substance) devoid of the triad of gunas. It is eternal and infinite. It is triply divisible as Past, Future and Present. It is the time (element) indicated by such terms as Simul- taneous, Immediate, Gradual etc; and is that which constitutes what is in vogue (as time- measures), viz., Nimesha, Kashṭhā, Tatparā, Vinādi, Kalā, Ghațikā, Muhurta,&amp;rsquo; Day, Half- month, Month, Season, Solstice, Year etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 SPIRITUAL UNIVERSE (Nitya-Vibhūti)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/06_SPIRITUAL_UNIVERSE_nitya-vibhUti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/06_SPIRITUAL_UNIVERSE_nitya-vibhUti/</guid>
      <description>108
Now (the Subject of the) Spiritual Universe (Nitya-Vibhuti) will be propounded. Non- inertness (Ajaḍatva) is a property common to (the Principles :) Pure Matter (Śuddha-satva),&amp;quot; the Attributive Consciousness (Dharma-bhūta- Jñāna), Soul (Jwa) and God (Iśvara). Non-inertness means Self-luminousness (Sva- yam-prakāśatva). Self-luminousness cum exte- riority (Paraktva), characterises both Pure Matter and Attributive Consciousness. Satvam or Lightness means that which, while self- luminous, is luminant to others. Suddha-Satvam
108
or Spiritual (Divine) Matter in the Spiritual Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 ATTRIBUTIVE CONSCIOUSNESS (Dharma-bhūta-jñāna)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/07_ATTRIBUTIVE_CONSCIOUSNESS_dharma-bhUta-jnAna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/07_ATTRIBUTIVE_CONSCIOUSNESS_dharma-bhUta-jnAna/</guid>
      <description>212
Consecutively, (the topic of) Attributive Consciousness will now be expounded. The nature of it is described thus:-
While it is self-luminous, non-sentient sub- stance, it is &amp;lsquo;objectivated&amp;rsquo; (sa-vishayatvam) (ie., some object always constituting its content);
While it is pervasive (Vibhu), it is of the nature of substance (Dravya), and attribute (Guna) like light;
It is the illuminant of objects;
It is Intellect or Intelligence (Buddhi) etc. Attributive Consciousness&amp;quot; is, to God and the Eternals (Nityas), ever eternal and pervasive (or diffusive); to the Bound (Baddha-souls) it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 THE SOUL (Jīva)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/08_THE_SOUL_jIva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/08_THE_SOUL_jIva/</guid>
      <description>The (category) Soul or Jiva will now be ex- plained. The characteristics common to Soul and God are: Interiority (pratyaktva), Cognos- citiveness (cetanatva), Spiritness (ātmatva), and Agency (kartṛtva).
Pratyaktua or Interiority means to be self- luminous. Cetanatva or Cognoscitiveness is to be the seat (or involucre) of consciousness. Atmatva or Spiritness is to be the antithesis to body (matter). Kartṛtva or Agency is to be the seat of consciousness, of the form of Will (sankalpa).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 GOD (Iśvara)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/09_GOD_ishvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/09_GOD_ishvara/</guid>
      <description>Now (the category of) God (Iśvara) will be inquired into. The characteristics of God are All-Lordship, All-Mastership, All-worshipfulness by work, All-fruit-givership, All-Support, All- energising, All-Word-indicated, All-knowledge- goal, All-bodiedness excepting His own body and consciousness.❤
God thus indicated is the Material (or Formal) Cause of the Universe by virtue of His aspect as the constituted of the Conscients and Non-cons- cients (cid-acid-viśishtaḥ); is the Efficient (or Spiritual) Cause by virtue of His aspect as the Willer; and is the Instrumental Cause by virtue of His immanence in Time etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 THE NON-SUBSTANCE (Adravya)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/10_THE_NON-SUBSTANCE_Adravya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/parichaya-sanxepAH/yatIndra-mata-dIpikA/en/govindAchArya/10_THE_NON-SUBSTANCE_Adravya/</guid>
      <description>After the treatment thus given to (the Cate- gory) Substance (Dravya), that of non-substance will now be taken up.
Non-substance is divisible into ten classes only vis. :—(1, 2, 3), the pure, motile or motive and dark (qualities inherent in matter), (4, 5, 6, 7, 8), Sound, Touch, Colour, Savour, Odour, (9) con- junction (Samyoga), and (10) Force (Śakti).
Satva or Pureness is the non-Substance (or Quality) which is the root-cause of brightness, happiness, buoyancy etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
