<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Divisions within the Pāñcarātra on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Divisions within the Pāñcarātra on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) Different kinds of Pāñcarātrika</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/1_i_Different_kinds_of_pAncharAtrika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/1_i_Different_kinds_of_pAncharAtrika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before turning to the classifications of different Pāñcarātra groups contained in several South Indian works belonging to the same religious context as the tradition of the supremacy of the *Jayākhyasaṃhitā *(JS), *Sātvatasaṃhitā *(SS) and &lt;em&gt;Pauskarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (PauṣS), it will be helpful here to summarise the additional textual evidence for there being distinct types of Pāñcarātrika.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are, from a period prior to our earliest Pāñcarātra scriptures, a number of textual sources which differentiate between Pāñcarātrikas and Bhāgavatas. I will refer to some of these below when I discuss Yāmuna’s &lt;em&gt;Āgamaprāmāṇya&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) Distinct Pāñcarātrika identities in the Āgamaprāmāṇya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/2_ii_Distinct_pAncharAtrika_identities_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/2_ii_Distinct_pAncharAtrika_identities_i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is clear that in his &lt;em&gt;Āgamaprāmāṇya&lt;/em&gt; (ĀP) Yāmuna distinguishes between several types of Bhāgavata or ‘Sātvata’/’Sāttvata’ (both spellings are used, the former more commonly) who accept the authority of the Pāñcarātra scriptures.[^78] The unsystematic manner in which these distinctions are made, however, means that the identity of each distinguishable “type” is not altogether obvious. Perhaps unsurprisingly, modern scholars have arrived at different interpretations with regard to precisely which distinct groups are recognised by Yāmuna. Neevel (1977: 30-37) contends that the ĀP distinguishes between four classes of Bhāgavata which he names as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) The four Pāñcarātra Siddhāntas according to the Pādmasaṃhitā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/3_iii_The_four_pAncharAtra_siddhAntas_ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/3_iii_The_four_pAncharAtra_siddhAntas_ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;siddhāntas&#34;&gt;Siddhāntas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The *Pādmasaṃhitā *(PādS) attempts to clearly delineate the divisions within the Pāñcarātra, while still preserving the “inclusivist” approach fostered by Yāmuna. It is one of several Saṃhitās which divides the Pāñcarātra tradition into four ‘Siddhāntas’, the others being the PauṣS (38.293-307b), the &lt;em&gt;Pārameśvarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (19.522-544), the *Īśvarasaṃhitā *(21.560-586), the &lt;em&gt;Śrīpraśnasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (16.31c-35b), the &lt;em&gt;Bhārgavatantra&lt;/em&gt; (22.87-94b) and, according to Vedāntadeśika, the &lt;em&gt;Hayagrīvasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (see PRR 8.5-8), the &lt;em&gt;Kālottara&lt;/em&gt; (PRR 31.14-18), and the &lt;em&gt;Śrīkarasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (PRR 30.18 &lt;em&gt;ff&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 iv \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/4_iv_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/3_THE_THREE_JEWELS_AND_THE_FORMATION_OF/3_Divisions_within_the_pAncharAtra/4_iv_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It will be useful, at this juncture, to tie together several summary conclusions from the foregoing. Firstly, the idea found in the PārS that three works, namely the SS, PauṣS and JS, are supreme among the Pāñcarātra Saṃhitās is, in the context of the Pāñcarātra corpus &lt;em&gt;in toto&lt;/em&gt;, a relatively late idea, probably no earlier than the twelfth century, and almost certainly originating in South India. The characterisation of these texts as the “three jewels” ( &lt;em&gt;ratnatraya&lt;/em&gt;) is later still, the earliest example being found in a work that is external to the Pāñcarātra scriptural corpus, namely Vedāntadeśika’s PRR, composed in Śrīraṅgam during the first quarter of the fourteenth century. In addition, the absence in the earlier literature of the division of the Pāñcarātra tradition into four Siddhāntas109 suggests that this too is a relatively late innovation, and the earliest extant articulations of this theory succeed several other works which also recognise the existence of distinct groups within the Pāñcarātra.110 Among these we can list at least the &lt;em&gt;Haravijaya&lt;/em&gt;, Bhaṭṭa Rāmakaṇṭha’s NPP, the SS, the SanS, the JS, a Vaikhānasa work called the &lt;em&gt;Samūrtārcanādhikaraṇa&lt;/em&gt;, and Yāmuna’s ĀP. The accounts of the different types of Vaiṣṇava or Pāñcarātrika contained in these texts are all markedly different from each other, but it is to be noted that none of them indicate that there was any sectarian animosity between these groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
