<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ekAnaMshA in nAstIka myth-making and implications for AstIka Paurano-Tantric history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
buddhagosha declared that the bauddha zealots should not listen to public narratives of the rAmAyaNa or mahAbhArata that the Astikas delight in. Yet, the nAstikas both jaina and bauddha have their own versions of several core narratives and branching AkhyAnas found in the canonical itihAsa and purANa literature of the Astikas. One striking feature is that their versions differ strikingly from the Astika versions. The bauddha ones, typically, are even more divergent than the jaina ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on the vaikhAnasa tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The vaikhAnasas appear to represent an archaic branch of vaiShNavas who are distinct from the more popular and numerous pA~ncharAtrins. The vaikhAnasas however were and are still influential in few south Indian temples including the world’s most famous shrine, venkaTAdri (Other examples being the viShNu temple of vANamAmalai). The vaikhAnasas belong to a kR^iShNa yajurvedic shAkhA founded by the descendent of the ancient R^iShi of the A~Ngirasa clan, vikhAnas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lineage of the viShNu tantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
oM ugraM vIraM mahAviShNuM jvalantaM sarvatomukhaM |
nR^isiMhaM bhIShaNaM bhadraM mR^ityu-mR^ityaM namAmyahaM ||
How did these mightiest mantras of viShNu come into being? Beyond pa~ncharAtra promulgated by the chitrashikaNDins are the tantras of viShNu made apparent by the shANDilyas. The root tantra of these is the glorious viShNu yAmala. From here stem the ugra viShNu, halAyudha, ugrachakra and other formulations. After bhairava had been quenched by the draught of viShNu’s blood he asked sadAshiva to narrate the glorious vidyAs of viShNu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kapilaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</guid>
      <description>The genesis of the kapila figure has a complex history to it &amp;amp; is associated with 3 distinct elements:
His early (probably very 1st mention in the shruti) is in the shaiva upaniShat shvetAshvatara -1 of the late upaniShat-s associated with the yajurveda : sAMkhya as “vedAnta” and a note on evolution of shaiva yoga. This memory continues down to the much later shaiva texts as noted in the article linked above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आखेटकम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</guid>
      <description>Both saiddhAntika shaiva-s &amp;amp; pA~ncharAtrika have a hunting ritual where the simulate either rudra or viShNu going out on an hunt (an old IA memory now lodged in a tAntrika tradition). 1 of the days recommended for it in the PR tradition is their equivalent of the dashamI following the autumnal navarAtrI which is termed the vIralakshmy-utsava. Like with the shaiva version the image of viShNu was borne on a horse &amp;amp; the procession was accompanied by an armed entourage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>वैष्णवाचमनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</guid>
      <description>In the आचमन routine, following names of विष्णु are invoked
केशव नारायण माधव गोविन्द विष्णु मधुसूदन
त्रिविक्रम वामन श्रीधर हृषीकेश पद्मनाभ दामोदर
When do they first occur in literature?
They are found in the viShNu-bAlI/viShNvarchana mantra of a number kR^iShNayajurvedic gR^ihyaparishiShTha-s: vaikhAnasa, agniveshya and baudhAyana. This suggests that it emerged in a branch of &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo;-taittirIyaka-s who were also early sectarian vaiShNava-s. I say &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo; because there is evidence that the vaikhAnasa-s had a now lost brAhmaNa distinct from the other taittirIyaka-s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
