<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ekAnaMshA in nAstIka myth-making and implications for AstIka Paurano-Tantric history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/11/01/ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;buddhagosha declared that the bauddha zealots should not listen to&#xA;public narratives of the rAmAyaNa or mahAbhArata that the Astikas&#xA;delight in. Yet, the nAstikas both jaina and bauddha have their own&#xA;versions of several core narratives and branching AkhyAnas found in the&#xA;canonical itihAsa and purANa literature of the Astikas. One striking&#xA;feature is that their versions differ strikingly from the Astika&#xA;versions. The bauddha ones, typically, are even more divergent than the&#xA;jaina ones. Examining them one gets the clear impression that some of&#xA;them were explicitly created in order to present their polemical view&#xA;point vis-a-vis the Astika-s. Others are not openly polemical, yet they&#xA;have subtle opposition to the Astika view point. Yet, the main point&#xA;that strikes one is their extreme divergence relative to the Astika&#xA;forms. Now, two theories can be proposed to explain this divergence:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A note on the vaikhAnasa tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/02/16/a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vaikhAnasas appear to represent an archaic branch of vaiShNavas who&#xA;are distinct from the more popular and numerous pA~ncharAtrins. The&#xA;vaikhAnasas however were and are still influential in few south Indian&#xA;temples including the world’s most famous shrine, venkaTAdri (Other&#xA;examples being the viShNu temple of vANamAmalai). The vaikhAnasas belong&#xA;to a kR^iShNa yajurvedic shAkhA founded by the descendent of the ancient&#xA;R^iShi of the A~Ngirasa clan, vikhAnas. The vaikhAnasas seem to have&#xA;adopted a form of vaiShnavism early on, and are probably even amongst&#xA;the earliest of the vaiShNavas alluded to in the nArAyaNIya section of&#xA;the mahAbhArata. They possess many unique tantras of their own. Another&#xA;unique collection associated with them is the vaikhAnasa mantra pATha,&#xA;which in addition to the yajurvedic gR^ihya mantras (cf. Apastamba&#xA;mantrapATha) includes a striking collection of mantras used in the&#xA;private vaikhAnasa ritual, especially in connection to viShNu. Even&#xA;their gR^ihya sUtra includes a section on the iconic worship of viShNu.&#xA;Their main tantras pertaining to the installation and worship of idols&#xA;are the bhR^igu, atri, kAshyapa and marIchi saMhitAs. The bhR^igu work&#xA;mainly convers temple rituals. atri too covers these topics at great&#xA;depth including the design of temples. kAshyapa’s Agama is mainly in&#xA;sutraic form. Like many other great traditions of India we notice&#xA;medieval historical references to the vaikhAnasa Agamas from both the&#xA;extreme north of India- kAshmIra and the drAviDa and Andhra countries to&#xA;the south. It finds mention in both the literary works of Sanskrit&#xA;writers from drAviDa, like daNDin and jayanta bhaTTa of kAshmIra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The lineage of the viShNu tantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/08/06/the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;oM ugraM vIraM mahAviShNuM jvalantaM sarvatomukhaM |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;nR^isiMhaM bhIShaNaM bhadraM mR^ityu-mR^ityaM namAmyahaM ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How did these mightiest mantras of viShNu come into being? Beyond&#xA;pa~ncharAtra promulgated by the chitrashikaNDins are the tantras of&#xA;viShNu made apparent by the shANDilyas. The root tantra of these is the&#xA;glorious viShNu yAmala. From here stem the ugra viShNu, halAyudha,&#xA;ugrachakra and other formulations. After bhairava had been quenched by&#xA;the draught of viShNu’s blood he asked sadAshiva to narrate the glorious&#xA;vidyAs of viShNu. The lineage goes thus:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sadAshiva-&amp;gt; kapAlabhairava-&amp;gt; svachChanda bhairava-&amp;gt;krodhabhairava-&amp;gt;&#xA;uchChuShma-&amp;gt; ruru-&amp;gt; chaNDabhairava-&amp;gt; unmatta-&amp;gt; vIrabhairava-&amp;gt;&#xA;anantanAga-&amp;gt; bhAskara -&amp;gt; manthAna -&amp;gt; nIlakaNTha -&amp;gt; bhIma -&amp;gt; vAmaka -&amp;gt;&#xA;mahAkAla. Asked by bhR^igu it was revealed to him by viShNu. And he&#xA;revealed it to shANDilya.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The core of the viShNu yAmala is made up of the following saMhitAs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kapilaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genesis of the kapila figure has a complex history to it &amp;amp; is associated with 3 distinct elements:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;His early (probably very 1st mention in the shruti) is in the shaiva upaniShat shvetAshvatara -1 of the late upaniShat-s associated with the yajurveda : &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2008/03/16/samkhya-as-vedanta-and-a-note-on-evolution-of-shaiva-yoga/&#34;&gt;sAMkhya as “vedAnta” and a note on evolution of shaiva yoga&lt;/a&gt;. This memory continues down to the much later shaiva texts as noted in the article linked above.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By the time of the rAmAyaNa we hear of a ferocious v1 dwelling in pAtAla who incinerated the 60000 sons of sagara. This kapila in the pA&lt;del&gt;ncharAtrika mantra tradition is identified with the fierce backward or 4th face of viShNu-chaturAtman, the 3 other faces being the regular viShNu or saumya face, nR^isiMha &amp;amp; varAha. That face can be seen in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/551451791528034304&#34;&gt;this Kashmirian image&lt;/a&gt; . By the time of the mahAbharata this kapila who burnt the sAgara-s is identified with viShNu &amp;amp; explicitly stated as his incarnation. Iconographic terms the 4th face takes the place of the nandin in equivalent tetracephalic shaiva imagery. It is attested in early pA&lt;/del&gt;ncharAtrika mantra, the viShNumAya.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then we have kapila the founder of sAMkhya.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several vaiShNava traditions tend to identify #2 and #3 and shaiva traditions identify #1 and #3 being not too interested in #2. Can we decouple history from mythology here? For that we have to consider the early history of yoga-sAMkhya. It seems to have begun as an ancient tradition that right from early on had both seshvara and nirIshvara flavors. It is possible that the figure seen in #1 &amp;amp; #3 was 1 of the early teachers or even the founder. What we do not know for sure was whether he was nirIshvara himself. We suspect that he was not insistent on the Ishvara-tattva. However, his philosophy was continued by those with early shaiva or vaiShNava inclinations who gave it an seshvara color &amp;amp; projected that onto kapila.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>आखेटकम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both saiddhAntika shaiva-s &amp;amp; pA~ncharAtrika have a hunting ritual where the simulate either rudra or viShNu going out on an hunt (an old IA memory now lodged in a tAntrika tradition). 1 of the days recommended for it in the PR tradition is their equivalent of the dashamI following the autumnal navarAtrI which is termed the vIralakshmy-utsava. Like with the shaiva version the image of viShNu was borne on a horse &amp;amp; the procession was accompanied by an armed entourage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>वैष्णवाचमनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the आचमन routine, following names of विष्णु are invoked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;केशव नारायण माधव गोविन्द विष्णु मधुसूदन&lt;br&gt;&#xA;त्रिविक्रम वामन श्रीधर हृषीकेश पद्मनाभ दामोदर&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When do they first occur in literature?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are found in the viShNu-bAlI/viShNvarchana mantra of a number kR^iShNayajurvedic gR^ihyaparishiShTha-s: vaikhAnasa, agniveshya and baudhAyana. This suggests that it emerged in a branch of &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo;-taittirIyaka-s who were also  early sectarian vaiShNava-s. I say &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo; because there is evidence that the vaikhAnasa-s had a now lost brAhmaNa distinct from the other taittirIyaka-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
