<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 The Ekāyanaveda on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 The Ekāyanaveda on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 i \) Descriptions of the Ekāyanaveda in the South Indian literature</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/1_i_Descriptions_of_the_ekAyanaveda_in_t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/1_i_Descriptions_of_the_ekAyanaveda_in_t/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will begin this section with a brief summary of the descriptions of the Ekāyanaveda and its followers that are found in several South Indian works. Since some of these descriptions have been addressed above, and Rastelli (2006) has provided a thorough analysis of the material relating to the Ekāyanaveda in its most important testament, the *Pārameśvarasaṃhitā *(PārS), I will limit myself here to some brief observations which I hope can provide a useful overview of the Pāñcarātrika tradition of the Ekāyanaveda in twelfth-fourteenth century South India. Subsequently, I will address the term &lt;em&gt;ekāyana&lt;/em&gt; itself, and explore what the textual evidence can tell us about this Pāñcarātra tradition in earlier centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ii \) The term ekāyana and its earlier uses</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/2_ii_The_term_ekAyana_and_its_earlier_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/2_ii_The_term_ekAyana_and_its_earlier_us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several modern scholars (e.g. Renou 1960: 8, Dyczkowski 1994: 293) have linked the Pāñcarātra tradition of the Ekāyanaveda to the &lt;em&gt;ekāyana&lt;/em&gt; which is listed as a branch of knowledge in the *Chāndogyopaniṣad *(7.1.2-4). As has been demonstrated by its various interpretations, the meaning of the term &lt;em&gt;ekāyana&lt;/em&gt; in this Upaniṣadic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[136]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse is not clear, though Śaṅkara’s understanding of it as “governance” or “statecraft” ( &lt;em&gt;nītiśāstra&lt;/em&gt;) is generally rejected by modern interpreters. Among recent translations, for instance, Roebuck (2003: 181, 424) follows Max Müller in taking &lt;em&gt;ekāyana&lt;/em&gt; to denote “ethics” i.e. “the one way [to live]”, while Olivelle (1996: 156, 351) follows Faddegon (1926: 52) in understanding it to mean literally “the going by oneself”, and therefore as referring to “uninterrupted speech” or “the monologues” (contrasted with &lt;em&gt;vākovākya&lt;/em&gt;, “dialogues”). Slaje (2009: 134, 188, 318), meanwhile, uniformly translates &lt;em&gt;ekāyana&lt;/em&gt; simply with “&lt;em&gt;Sammelpunkt&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 iii \) The Ekāyanas in the JS, SS and PauṣS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/3_iii_The_ekAyanas_in_the_JS_SS_and_pauS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/3_iii_The_ekAyanas_in_the_JS_SS_and_pauS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether a text called ‘Ekāyanaveda’ ever existed has been debated by modern scholars, with Renou (1947: 205), for instance, claiming that the tradition of the Ekāyanaveda is a late invention, and Rastelli (e.g. 2008: 265) arguing that, nonetheless, a text or texts known as ‘Ekāyanaveda’ must have once been extant. In support of this, Rastelli points to the PārS’s (17.451c) prescription to recite the &lt;em&gt;ekāyanī śākhā&lt;/em&gt;, and the JS’s (20.269cd-270a) prescription to recite mantras from the &lt;em&gt;ekāyanīyaśākhā&lt;/em&gt;. To these we can perhaps add the PādS’s ( &lt;em&gt;cp&lt;/em&gt; 13.66c-70b) decree that the “original recension based on the Ekāyana” should be studied alongside the various recensions of the Ṛc, Yajus and Sāman. However, although there are a number of Pāñcarātra works which refer to the Ekāyana as a Vedic &lt;em&gt;śākhā&lt;/em&gt;, it should be noted that none of these aforementioned verses refer precisely to an&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 iv \) Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/4_iv_Conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/leach_pAncharAtra_2013/4_THE_ORIGINAL_TEACHING_LOCATING_TEXTS_A/3_The_ekAyanaveda/4_iv_Conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although there are references in the JS, SS and PauṣS to Ekāyana mantras and to “twice born” ( &lt;em&gt;dvija&lt;/em&gt;) Ekāyanas and Ekāyana Brahmins ( &lt;em&gt;vipra&lt;/em&gt;), and despite there being an indubitable link between the Pāñcarātrika Ekāyana tradition and Kashmir, as well as a possible allusion to the idea of the ‘Ekāyanaveda’ in Bhaṭṭa Jayanta’s ĀḌ,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; the earliest clear Pāñcarātrika references to an &lt;em&gt;ekāyanaśruti&lt;/em&gt; or an &lt;em&gt;ekāyanaveda&lt;/em&gt; occur only in the later, South Indian works, namely the ĀP, the PādS and the PārS. Moreover, among the passages in the JS, SS and PauṣS which refer to the Ekāyana recension and the Ekāyana Brahmins, those in the JS and SS are demonstrably later additions to these texts. We can be fairly sure that the passage in the JS which refers to mantras belonging to the Ekāyana &lt;em&gt;śākhā&lt;/em&gt; is a product of South India, and it seems likely, owing to their many similarities, that SS 24-25 and PauṣS 42 were composed in similar environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
