<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tritonal recitations of vaiShNava-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2010-07-06_tritonal-recitations-of-vaishnava-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2010-07-06_tritonal-recitations-of-vaishnava-s/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
KRK astutely observed that the tritonal recitation of the nAlAyira divyaprabandhaM (DP4000) by the shrIvaiShNava-s might be a survival of an even earlier custom of the tritonal recitation of the pA~ncharAtra texts. The evidence from the AgamaDambara (AD) of jayanta bhaTTa in support of this seems rather clear. In the AD an orthodox smArta ritualist severely condemns the vaiShNava-s and shaiva-s in a conversation with a smArta teacher. In the 4th act of the play the R^itvik states:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of pA~ncharatra tantra-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2006-06-01_list-of-pancharatra-tantra-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2006-06-01_list-of-pancharatra-tantra-s/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
With the muni, the shrI vaiShNava and R’s father we have made a comprehensive list of pA~ncharAtra tantras that are supposed to have existed. We simply have little to no details of many of them and cannot say much about their existence. Of others only fragments are known from manuscripts or citations or prayoga traditions. Several purported saMhitA-s that are recorded based on citations are spurious and are seem to be vedic saMhitA-s or kalpa texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on early pAncharAtra vaiShNavism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2006-03-27_notes-on-early-pancharatra-vaishnavism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2006-03-27_notes-on-early-pancharatra-vaishnavism/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
It is likely that in the later period the vaiShNavas were ignorant on why the name pA~ncharatra came into being. This ignorance of the meaning of the name is plainly seen in the explanation provided by the prashna saMhitA and padma saMhitA of pA~ncharAtra, and the nAradIya pA~ncharAtra has only a vague memory regarding the cause of the name. The kashmirAcharyas of mahAbala paNDita’s school and vidyAraNya yati cite a number of formulae of pA~ncharAtra vaiShNavism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lakShmI tantraM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2004-02-09_lakshmi-tantram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/2004-02-09_lakshmi-tantram/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
One of the most lucid expositions of the foundational philosophy of pA~ncharatra is seen in the lecture given by lakShmI to indra in the lakShmI-tantraM (chapter 4):
1) Originally lakShmI and viShNu are conjoined in an undifferentiated form termed the “pure space”. This combination of viShNu and shrI is termed the homogeneous state which cannot be discerned and with out any fluctuations in it.
2) From time to time a minute particle comprising of a 10^-18 viShNu-shrI continuum state differentiates into action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एकायनशाखा</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/ekAyana-shAkHA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/articles/MT/ekAyana-shAkHA/</guid>
      <description>Source: MT
One of the enduring mysteries in the history of the vaiShNava mantra tradition is the ekAyana-shAkhA which the pa~ncharAtra affiliates itself with. It may be termed the rahasyAMnAya or the primal veda. Clearly, some exclusively focal pA~ncharAtra vaiShNava-s saw it as the root from which the &amp;ldquo;common veda&amp;rdquo; emerged. The reason they give for the secondary nature of the common veda is that it worships other deities in addition to viShNu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
