<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/mahAnubhAvaH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/mahAnubhAvaH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The cracks in the edifice.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/mahAnubhAvaH/articles/MT/2005-11-13_the-cracks-in-the-edifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/mahAnubhAvaH/articles/MT/2005-11-13_the-cracks-in-the-edifice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/13/the-cracks-in-the-edifice/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1326 the Army of Islam had completed the conquest of Hind and almost all of the old Hindu dynasties from the royal shishodias and ChAhamAnas in the north, the yAdavas and hoyasalas of Middle India and the Cholas and Pandyas of South India lay prostrate before the cresent banner. The great edifice of India, starting from the kuru and the pA~nchAla, through the mauryans, shungas, guptas and their successor states was destroyed. The last in this long line of India states in central India was the yAdava state that gained control of central India from the chAlukyas of mAnyakheta and kalyAni. They established their capital in devagiri and were blessed with 4 notable rulers singhana, kR^ishNadeva, mahAdeva and rAmadeva. Their long-lived brahmin minister was the illustrious hemAdri from the karNATa country whose enormous breadth of scholarship was illustrated in the encyclopaedic work chaturvarga chintAmaNi and its colophons. He developed a special type of temple architecture known as the hemadripantha style. He was a physician and agriculturist who developed the cultivation of bajra as a nutrious food for arid zones in Maharashtra. Above all he provided a legal and administrative scaffold for the yAdava kingdom much as the brahmin vij~nAneshvara had done for the chAlukyas before them. Other great scholars of the yAdava kingdom were keshava the physician, vopadeva the grammarian and physician and bhAskara II the mathematician. There were revolutions in Hindu medicine in the yAdava period, where the great scholars developed diagnosis of disease considerably over the earlier Hindu treatises. It also saw the rise of differential calculus in the work of bhAskara II.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
