<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;१ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/01/</guid>
      <description>THIRD ADHYĀYA. FIRST PĀDA. In obtaining another of that, it goes enveloped, (as appears) from question and explanation. That the Vedānta-texts establish as the proper object of meditation, on the part of all men desirous of Release, the highest Brahman, which is the only cause of the entire world, which is not touched by even a shadow of imperfection, which is an ocean, as it were, of supremely exalted qualities, and which totally differs in nature from all other beings&amp;ndash;this is the point proved in the two previous adhyāyas; there being given at the same time arguments to disprove the objections raised against the Vedānta doctrine on the basis of Smr̥ti and reasoning, to refute the views held by other schools, to show that the different Vedānta-texts do not contradict each other, and to prove that the Self is the object of activities (enjoined in injunctions of meditation, and so on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/02/</guid>
      <description>But on account of (water) consisting of the three elements; on account of predominance. Water alone could not produce a new body; for the text Cḥ. Up. VI, 3, 4, &amp;lsquo;Each of these he made tripartite,&amp;rsquo; shows that all the elements were&amp;rsquo; made tripartite to the end of producing bodies. That the text under discussion mentions water only, is due to the predominance of water; and that among the elements giving rise to a new body water predominates, we infer from the fact that blood and the other humours are the predominating element in the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/03/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the going of the prāṇas. That the soul goes embedded in the subtle rudiments of the elements follows therefrom also that when passing out of the old body it is said to be followed by the prāṇas, &amp;lsquo;when he thus passes out, the chief prāṇa follows after him,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Br̥. Up. V, 4, 2). Compare also Smr̥ti: &amp;lsquo;It draws to itself the organs of sense, with the mind for the sixth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/04/</guid>
      <description>If it be said (that it is not so) on account of scriptural statement as to going to Agni and the rest; we say no, on account of the secondary nature (of the statement). But the text, &amp;lsquo;when the speech of the dead person enters into fire,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. (Br̥. Up. III, 2, 13). declares that when a person dies his organs go into fire, and so on.; they cannot therefore accompany the soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/05/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said, on account of absence of mention in the first (reply); we say no, for just that (is meant), on the ground of fitness. An objection is raised to the conclusion arrived at under III, 1, 1; on the ground that in the first oblation, described in Cḥ. Up. V, 4, 2, as being made into the heavenly world, water is not mentioned at all as the thing offered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/06/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;On account of this not being stated by Scripture&amp;rsquo;; not so, on account of those who perform sacrifices and so on being understood. But, a further objection is raised, in the whole section under discussion no mention at all is made of the soul; the section cannot therefore prove that the soul moves, enveloped by water. The text speaks only of different forms of water śraddhā and the rest.&amp;ndash;This, the Sūtra points out, is not so, on account of those who perform sacrifices being understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/07/</guid>
      <description>Or it is metaphorical, on account of their not knowing the Self. For thus Scripture declares. He who performs sacrifices, and so on, and thus does not know the Self, is here below and in yonder world a mere
means of enjoyment for the devas. He serves them here, by propitiating them with sacrifices, and so on; and when the gods, pleased with his service, have taken him up into yonder world, he there is a common means of enjoyment for them (since they are gratified by the presence of a faithful servant).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/08/</guid>
      <description>On the passing away of the works, with a remainder, according to Scripture and Smr̥ti; as it went and not so. The text declares that those who only perform sacrifices and useful works ascend by the road of the fathers, and again return to the earth when they have fully enjoyed the fruit of their works, &amp;lsquo;having dwelt there yāvat saṁpātam, they return by the same way&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. V, 10, 5).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/09/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;On account of conduct&amp;rsquo;; not so, since (caraṇa) connotes works; thus Kārshṇājini thinks. In the phrases &amp;rsquo;those whose works were good&amp;rsquo; (ramaṇīya-caraṇāḥ), and &amp;rsquo;those whose works were bad&amp;rsquo; (kapūyā-caraṇāḥ), the word caraṇa does not denote good and evil works (i.e. not such works as the Veda on the one hand enjoins as leading to certain rewards, and on the other prohibits, threatening punishment), for, in Vedic as well as ordinary language, the term caraṇa is generally used in the sense of ācāra, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;There is purposelessness&amp;rsquo;; not so, on account of the dependence on that. But if conduct has no result, it follows that good conduct,
as enjoined in the Smr̥tis, is useless!&amp;ndash;Not so, we reply; for holy works enjoined by the Veda depend on conduct, in so far as a man of good conduct only is entitled to perform those works. This appears from passages such as the following: &amp;lsquo;A man who is not pure is unfit for all religious work,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Him who is devoid of good conduct the Vedas do not purify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/11/</guid>
      <description>But only good and evil works, thus Bādari thinks. As the verb ā-car takes karman for its object (puṇyaṁ karmā carati, &amp;amp;c.), and as the separate denotation (i.e. the use of apparently equivalent words, viz. ācar and karman) can be accounted for on the ground that one of them refers to works established by manifest texts, and the other to texts inferred from actually existing rules of good conduct; and as, when the primary meaning is possible, no secondary meaning must be adopted; nothing else but good and evil works (in the Vedic sense) are denoted by the word caraṇa: such is the opinion of the teacher Bādari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/12/</guid>
      <description>Of those also who do not perform sacrifices (the ascent) is declared by Scripture. It has been said that those who perform only sacrifices, and so on, go to the moon and thence return with a remainder of their works. The question now arises whether those also who do not perform sacrifices go to the moon. The phrase &amp;lsquo;who do not perform sacrifices&amp;rsquo; denotes evil-doers
of two kinds, viz. those who do not do what is enjoined, and those who do what is forbidden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/13/</guid>
      <description>But of the others having enjoyed in Saṁyamana, there is ascent and descent; as such a course is declared. Of the others, i.e. those who do not perform sacrifices, and so on, there is ascent to the moon and descent from there, only after they have in the kingdom of Yama suffered the punishments due to their actions. For the text declares that evil-doers fall under the power of Yama, and have to go to him, &amp;lsquo;He who thinks, this is the world there is no other, falls again and again under my sway&amp;rsquo; (Ka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/14/</guid>
      <description>Smr̥ti texts also declare this. That all beings are under the sway of Yama, Parāśara also and other Smr̥ti writers declare, &amp;lsquo;And all these pass under the sway of Yama.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/15/</guid>
      <description>Moreover there are seven. The Smr̥tis moreover declare that there are seven hells, called Raurava, and so on, to which evil-doers have to go.&amp;ndash;But how do they, if moving about in those seven places, reach the palace of Yama?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/16/</guid>
      <description>On account of his activity there also, there is no contradiction. As their going to those seven places also is due to the command of Yama, there is no contradiction.&amp;ndash;Thus those also who do not perform sacrifices, and so on, after having gone to the world of Yama, and there undergone punishments
according to the nature of their works, later on ascend to the moon and again descend from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/17/</guid>
      <description>But, of knowledge and work&amp;ndash;as these are the leading topics. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; sets aside the view developed so far. It cannot be admitted that those also who do not perform sacrifices, and so on, reach the moon; because the path of the gods and the path of the fathers are meant for the enjoyment of the fruits &amp;lsquo;of knowledge and work.&amp;lsquo;That is to say&amp;ndash;as those who do not perform sacrifices cannot ascend by the path of the gods, since they are destitute of knowledge; so they also cannot go by the path of the fathers, since they are destitute of meritorious works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/18/</guid>
      <description>Not in the case of the third (place), as it is thus perceived. The third &amp;lsquo;place&amp;rsquo; does not, for the origination of a new body, depend on the fifth oblation. The term,&amp;rsquo;the third
place,&amp;rsquo; denotes mere evil-doers. That these do not, for the origination of a new body, depend on the fifth oblation, is seen from Scripture. For, in answer to the question &amp;lsquo;Do you know why that world never becomes full?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/19/</guid>
      <description>It moreover is recorded, in the world. Smr̥ti, moreover, states that the bodies of some specially meritorious persons, such as Draupadī, Dhr̥shṭadyumna and others, were formed independently of the fifth oblation&amp;rsquo; (i.e. sexual union).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/20/</guid>
      <description>And on account of its being seen. And it is seen in Scripture also, that the bodies of some beings originate independently of the fifth oblation: &amp;lsquo;Of all beings there are indeed three origins only, that which springs from an egg, that which springs from a living being, that which springs from a germ&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. VI, 3, 1). It is observed that from among these beings those springing from a germ and those springing from heat originate without that fifth oblation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/21/</guid>
      <description>The third term includes that which springs from heat. Creatures sprung from heat are included in the third term&amp;ndash;viz. that which springs from a germ&amp;ndash;which is exhibited in the text quoted. The settled conclusion therefore is that the evil-doers do not go to the moon.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;those who do not perform sacrifices.&#39;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/22/</guid>
      <description>There is entering into similarity of being with those, there being a reason. The text describes the manner in which those who perform sacrifices, and so on, descend from the moon as follows: &amp;lsquo;They return again that way as they came, to the ether, from the ether to the air. Then having become air they become smoke, having become smoke they become mist,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. The doubt here arises whether the soul when reaching ether, and so on, becomes ether in the same sense as here on earth it becomes a man or other being, or merely becomes similar to ether, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/23/</guid>
      <description>Not very long; on account of special statement. Does the soul in its descent through ether, and so on, stay at each stage for a not very long time, or is there nothing to define that time?&amp;ndash;It stays at each stage for an indefinite time, there being nothing to define the time.&amp;ndash;
Not so, the Sūtra decides. For there is a special statement, i.e. the text says that when the soul has become rice or grain or the like, the passing out of that stage is beset with difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/24/</guid>
      <description>Into (plants) animated by other souls, because the statement is as in the previous cases. The text declares that (he descending souls are born as rice, corn, &amp;amp;c., &amp;rsquo;they are born here as rice, corn, herbs, trees,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c. The question here is whether the souls cling to plants animated by other souls which have those plants for their bodies; or whether the descending souls themselves are born with those plants for their bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/25/</guid>
      <description>It is unholy. Not so, on the ground of Scripture. The conclusion arrived at above cannot be accepted, since there is a reason why the descending soul should enter on the condition of an enjoying soul. Such works as sacrifices, the fruit of which is the enjoyment of the heavenly world, are mixed with evil, for they imply injury to living beings as in the case of the goat offered to Agnīshomau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/26/</guid>
      <description>After that conjunction with him who performs the act of generation. The declaration that the descending souls become rice plants, and so on, cannot be taken literally for that reason also, that the text afterwards declares them to become those who perform the act of generation: &amp;lsquo;Whoever the being may be that eats the food and begets offspring, that being he (i.e. the soul that has descended) becomes.&amp;rsquo; Now the meaning of this latter text can only be that the soul enters into conjunction with the creature which eats the grain; and hence we have to interpret the previous text, as to the soul&amp;rsquo;s becoming a plant, in the same way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/3/1/27/</guid>
      <description>From the yoni the body. Only after having reached a yoni the soul, affected with a remnant of its works, obtains a new body, and only in a body there can be the enjoyment of pleasure and pain. When, therefore, previous to that the soul is said to reach ether, wind, and so on, this can only mean that it enters into conjunction with them.&amp;ndash;Here terminates the adhikaraṇa of &amp;rsquo;that animated by another soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
