<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ अन्त्य on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ अन्त्य on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Śrīla Rūpa Gosvāmī’s Second Meeting with the Lord</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the first chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu returned to Jagannātha Purī from Vṛndāvana, all His devotees from other parts of India, upon receiving the auspicious news, came to Puruṣottama-kṣetra, or Jagannātha Purī. Śivānanda Sena took a dog with him and even paid fees for it to cross the river. One night, however, the dog could not get any food and therefore went directly to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu at Jagannātha Purī. The next day, when Śivānanda and his party reached Jagannātha Purī, Śivānanda saw the dog eating some coconut pulp offered to it by Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. After this incident, the dog was liberated and went back home, back to Godhead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 The Chastisement of Junior Haridāsa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purport of this chapter is explained by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. Kṛṣṇadāsa Kavirāja Gosvāmī, the author of &lt;em&gt;Śrī Caitanya-caritāmṛta,&lt;/em&gt; wanted to explain direct meetings with Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, meetings with those empowered by Him, and His &lt;em&gt;āvirbhāva&lt;/em&gt; appearance. Thus he described the glories of Nṛsiṁhānanda and other devotees. A devotee named Bhagavān Ācārya was exceptionally faithful to the lotus feet of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Nevertheless, his brother, Gopāla Bhaṭṭa Ācārya, discoursed upon the commentary of impersonalism (Māyāvāda). Śrīla Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī, the secretary of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, forbid Bhagavān Ācārya to indulge in hearing that commentary. Later, when Junior Haridāsa, following the order of Bhagavān Ācārya, went to collect alms from Mādhavīdevī, he committed an offense by talking intimately with a woman although he was in the renounced order. Because of this, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu rejected Junior Haridāsa, and despite all the requests of the Lord’s stalwart devotees, the Lord did not accept him again. One year after this incident, Junior Haridāsa went to the confluence of the Ganges and Yamunā and committed suicide. In his spiritual body, however, he continued to sing devotional songs, and Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu heard them. When the Vaiṣṇavas of Bengal went to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, these incidents became known to Svarūpa Dāmodara and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 The Glories of Śrīla Haridāsa Ṭhākura</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THREE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the third chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura as follows. A beautiful young &lt;em&gt;brāhmaṇa&lt;/em&gt; girl in Jagannātha Purī had a very handsome son who was coming every day to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. This was not very much to the liking of Dāmodara Paṇḍita, however, who therefore told Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, “If You display so much love for this boy, people will doubt Your character.” Hearing these words from Dāmodara Paṇḍita, the Lord sent him to Navadvīpa to supervise the affairs of His mother, Śacīdevī. He also especially requested Dāmodara Paṇḍita to remind His mother that He was sometimes going to her home to accept the food she offered. Thus, following the order of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, Dāmodara Paṇḍita went to Navadvīpa, taking with him all kinds of &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; from Lord Jagannātha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Sanātana Gosvāmī Visits the Lord at Jagannātha Purī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fourth chapter is summarized by Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. Śrīla Sanātana Gosvāmī came alone from Mathurā to Jagannātha Purī to see Lord Caitanya. Because of bathing in bad water and not getting enough food every day while traveling on the path through Jhārikhaṇḍa (Jharkhand) Forest, he developed a disease that made his body itch. Suffering greatly from this itching, he resolved that in the presence of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu he would throw himself under the wheel of Jagannātha’s car and in this way commit suicide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 How Pradyumna Miśra Received Instructions from Rāmānanda Rāya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of the fifth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Pradyumna Miśra, a resident of Śrīhaṭṭa, came to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu to hear from Him about Lord Kṛṣṇa and His pastimes. The Lord, however, sent him to Śrīla Rāmānanda Rāya. Śrīla Rāmānanda Rāya was training the &lt;em&gt;deva-dāsī&lt;/em&gt; dancing girls in the temple, and when Pradyumna Miśra heard about this, he returned to Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The Lord, however, elaborately described the character of Śrīla Rāmānanda Rāya. Then Pradyumna Miśra went to see Rāmānanda Rāya again to hear about the transcendental truth from him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Meeting of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of this chapter is given by Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu went into transcendental fits of ecstatic love, Rāmānanda Rāya and Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī attended to Him and satisfied Him as He desired. Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī had been attempting to come to the lotus feet of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu for a long time, and finally he left his home and met the Lord. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu had gone to Śāntipura on His way to Vṛndāvana, Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī had offered to dedicate his life at the Lord’s lotus feet. In the meantime, however, a Muslim official became envious of Hiraṇya dāsa, Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī’s uncle, and induced some big official court minister to have him arrested. Thus Hiraṇya dāsa left his home, but by the intelligence of Raghunātha dāsa the misunderstanding was mitigated. Then Raghunātha dāsa went to Pānihāṭi, and following the order of Nityānanda Prabhu, he observed a festival (&lt;em&gt;ciḍā-dadhi-mahotsava&lt;/em&gt;) by distributing chipped rice mixed with yogurt. The day after the festival, Nityānanda Prabhu gave Raghunātha dāsa the blessing that he would very soon attain the shelter of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. After this incident, Raghunātha dāsa, with the help of his priest, whose name was Yadunandana Ācārya, got out of his house by trickery and thus ran away. Not touching the general path, Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī secretly went to Jagannātha Purī. After twelve days, he arrived in Jagannātha Purī at the lotus feet of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Meeting of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Vallabha Bhaṭṭa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of chapter seven is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; In this chapter, Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s meeting with Vallabha Bhaṭṭa is described. There was some joking behavior between these two personalities, and finally Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu corrected Vallabha Bhaṭṭa and sympathetically accepted an invitation from him. Before this, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu saw that Vallabha Bhaṭṭa was greatly attached to Gadādhara Paṇḍita. Therefore He acted as if displeased with Gadādhara Paṇḍita. Later, when Vallabha Bhaṭṭa became intimately connected with the Lord, the Lord advised him to take instructions from Gadādhara Paṇḍita. Thus the Lord expressed His feelings of love for Gadādhara Paṇḍita.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Rāmacandra Purī Criticizes the Lord</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of the eighth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; This chapter describes the history of the Lord’s dealings with Rāmacandra Purī. Although Rāmacandra Purī was one of the disciples of Mādhavendra Purī, he was influenced by dry Māyāvādīs, and therefore he criticized Mādhavendra Purī. Therefore Mādhavendra Purī accused him of being an offender and rejected him. Because Rāmacandra Purī had been rejected by his spiritual master, he became concerned only with finding faults in others and advising them according to dry Māyāvāda philosophy. For this reason he was not very respectful to the Vaiṣṇavas, and later he became so fallen that he began criticizing Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu for His eating. Hearing his criticisms, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu reduced His eating, but after Rāmacandra Purī left Jagannātha Purī, the Lord resumed His usual behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Deliverance of Gopīnātha Paṭṭanāyaka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ninth chapter is summarized as follows. Gopīnātha Paṭṭanāyaka, the son of Bhavānanda Rāya, was engaged in the service of the government, but he misappropriated some funds from the treasury. Therefore the &lt;em&gt;baḍa-jānā,&lt;/em&gt; the eldest son of King Pratāparudra, ordered that he be punished by death. Thus Gopīnātha Paṭṭanāyaka was raised on the &lt;em&gt;cāṅga&lt;/em&gt; to be killed, but by the mercy of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu he was delivered. Moreover, he was even promoted to a higher post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu Accepts Prasādam from His Devotees</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of chapter ten is given by Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Before the Ratha-yātrā ceremony, all the devotees from Bengal started for Jagannātha Purī as usual. Rāghava Paṇḍita brought with him various kinds of food for Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. The food had been cooked by his sister, Damayantī, who then packed it in bags (&lt;em&gt;jhāli&lt;/em&gt;). Thus the stock of food was generally known as &lt;em&gt;rāghavera jhāli,&lt;/em&gt; “the bags of Rāghava*.*” Makaradhvaja Kara, an inhabitant of Pānihāṭi who accompanied Rāghava Paṇḍita, was the secretary in charge of accounting for the &lt;em&gt;rāghavera jhāli&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Passing of Haridāsa Ṭhākura</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The summary of this chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. In this chapter it is described how Brahmā Haridāsa Ṭhākura gave up his body with the consent of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, and how the Lord Himself personally performed the funeral ceremony and carried the body to the sea. He personally entombed the body, covered it with sand and erected a platform on the site. After taking a bath in the sea, He personally begged &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; of Jagannātha from shopkeepers and distributed &lt;em&gt;prasādam&lt;/em&gt; to the assembled devotees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Loving Dealings Between Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu and Jagadānanda Paṇḍita</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the twelfth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya&lt;/em&gt; as follows. This chapter discusses the transformations of ecstatic love that Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu exhibited day and night. The devotees from Bengal again journeyed to Jagannātha Purī to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. As usual, the leader was Śivānanda Sena, who traveled with his wife and children. Because arrangements were delayed en route and Lord Nityānanda did not have a suitable place to reside, He became somewhat disturbed. Thus He became very angry with Śivānanda Sena, who was in charge of the affairs of the party, and kicked him in loving anger. Śivānanda Sena felt highly favored to have been kicked by Nityānanda Prabhu, but his nephew Śrīkānta Sena became upset and therefore left their company. He met Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu at Jagannātha Purī before the rest of the party arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Pastimes with Jagadānanda Paṇḍita and Raghunātha Bhaṭṭa Gosvāmī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the thirteenth chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Thinking Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was uncomfortable sleeping on bark of plantain trees, Jagadānanda made a pillow and quilt for Him. The Lord, however, did not accept them. Then Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī made another pillow and quilt from finely shredded plantain leaves, and after strongly objecting, the Lord accepted them. With the permission of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, Jagadānanda Paṇḍita went to Vṛndāvana, where he discussed many devotional subjects with Sanātana Gosvāmī. There was also a discussion about Mukunda Sarasvatī’s garment. When Jagadānanda returned to Jagannātha Purī, he presented Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu with some gifts from Sanātana Gosvāmī, and the incident of the &lt;em&gt;pīlu&lt;/em&gt; fruit took place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s Feelings of Separation from Kṛṣṇa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the fourteenth chapter*.* Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu’s feelings of separation from Kṛṣṇa resulted in highly elevated transcendental madness. When He was standing near the Garuḍa-stambha and praying to Lord Jagannātha, a woman from Orissa put her foot on the Lord’s shoulder in her great eagerness to see Lord Jagannātha. Govinda chastised her for this, but Caitanya Mahāprabhu praised her eagerness. When Caitanya Mahāprabhu went to the temple of Lord Jagannātha, He was absorbed in ecstatic love and saw only Kṛṣṇa. As soon as He perceived this woman, however, His external consciousness immediately returned, and He saw Jagannātha, Baladeva and Subhadrā. Caitanya Mahāprabhu also saw Kṛṣṇa in a dream, and He was overwhelmed with ecstatic love. When He could no longer see Kṛṣṇa, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu compared Himself to a &lt;em&gt;yogī&lt;/em&gt; and described how that &lt;em&gt;yogī&lt;/em&gt; was seeing Vṛndāvana. Sometimes all the transcendental ecstatic symptoms were manifest in Him. One night, Govinda and Svarūpa Dāmodara noticed that although the three doors to the Lord’s room were closed and locked, the Lord was not present inside. Seeing this, Svarūpa Dāmodara and the other devotees went outside and saw the Lord lying unconscious by the gate known as Siṁha-dvāra. His body had become unusually long, and the joints of His bones were loose. The devotees gradually brought Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu back to His senses by chanting the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mantra,&lt;/em&gt; and then they took Him back to His residence. Once Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu mistook a sand dune known as Caṭaka-parvata for Govardhana Hill. As He ran toward it, He became stunned, and then the eight ecstatic transformations appeared in His body due to great love for Kṛṣṇa. At that time all the devotees chanted the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mantra&lt;/em&gt; to pacify Him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Transcendental Madness of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is a summary of the fifteenth chapter*.* After seeing the &lt;em&gt;upala-bhoga&lt;/em&gt; ceremony of Lord Jagannātha, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu once more began to feel ecstatic emotions. When He saw the garden on the beach by the sea, He again thought that He was in Vṛndāvana, and when He began to think of Kṛṣṇa engaging in His different pastimes, transcendental emotions excited Him again. On the night of the &lt;em&gt;rāsa&lt;/em&gt; dance, the &lt;em&gt;gopīs,&lt;/em&gt; bereaved by Kṛṣṇa’s absence, searched for Kṛṣṇa from one forest to another. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu adopted the same transcendental thoughts as those of the &lt;em&gt;gopīs&lt;/em&gt; and was filled with ecstatic emotion. Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī recited a verse from the &lt;em&gt;Gīta-govinda&lt;/em&gt; just suitable to the Lord’s emotions. Caitanya Mahāprabhu then exhibited the ecstatic transformations known as &lt;em&gt;bhāvodaya, bhāva-sandhi, bhāva-śābalya&lt;/em&gt; and so on. The Lord experienced all eight kinds of ecstatic transformations, and He relished them very much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu Tastes Nectar from the Lips of Lord Śrī Kṛṣṇa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sixteenth chapter is summarized by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; When the Bengali devotees of the Lord returned to Jagannātha Purī, a gentleman named Kālidāsa, who was an uncle of Raghunātha dāsa Gosvāmī, went with them to see Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu. Kālidāsa had tasted the remnants of food of all the Vaiṣṇavas in Bengal, even Jhaḍu Ṭhākura. Because of this, he received the shelter of Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu at Jagannātha Purī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The Bodily Transformations of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVENTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura gives the following summary of the seventeenth chapter in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Absorbed in transcendental ecstasy, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu went out one night without opening the doors to His room. After crossing over three walls, He fell down among some cows belonging to the district of Tailaṅga. There He remained unconscious, assuming the aspect of a tortoise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-1&#34;&gt;Text 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-text&#34;&gt;Verse text&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;likhyate śrīla-gaurendor&lt;br&gt;&#xA;aty-adbhutam alaukikam&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yair dṛṣṭaṁ tan-mukhāc chrutvā&lt;br&gt;&#xA;divyonmāda-viceṣṭitam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Rescuing the Lord from the Sea</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHTEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary of the eighteenth chapter is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; On an autumn evening when the moon was full, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu walked along the seashore near the Āiṭoṭā temple. Mistaking the sea for the Yamunā River, He jumped into it, hoping to see the water pastimes Kṛṣṇa enjoyed with Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī and the other &lt;em&gt;gopīs.&lt;/em&gt; As He floated in the sea, however, He was washed away to the Koṇārka temple, where a fisherman, thinking that the Lord’s body was a big fish, caught Him in his net and brought Him ashore. Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu was unconscious, and His body had become unusually transformed. As soon as the fisherman touched the Lord’s body, he became mad in ecstatic love of Kṛṣṇa. His own madness frightened him, however, because he thought that he was being haunted by a ghost. As he was about to seek a ghost charmer, he met Svarūpa Dāmodara Gosvāmī and the other devotees on the beach, who had been looking everywhere for the Lord. After some inquiries, Svarūpa Dāmodara could understand that the fisherman had caught Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu in his net. Since the fisherman was afraid of being haunted by a ghost, Svarūpa Dāmodara gave him a slap and chanted Hare Kṛṣṇa, which immediately pacified him. Thereafter, when the devotees chanted the Hare Kṛṣṇa &lt;em&gt;mahā-mantra&lt;/em&gt; loudly, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu came to His external consciousness. Then they brought Him back to His own residence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The Inconceivable Behavior of Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/gauDIyaH/kAvyam/chaitanya-charitram/kRShNa-dAsaH_chaitanya-charitAmRtam/sarva-prastutiH/03_antya/19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINETEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following summary of chapter nineteen is given by Śrīla Bhaktivinoda Ṭhākura in his &lt;em&gt;Amṛta-pravāha-bhāṣya.&lt;/em&gt; Every year, Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu asked Jagadānanda Paṇḍita to visit His mother in Navadvīpa with gifts of cloth and &lt;em&gt;prasādam.&lt;/em&gt; After one such visit, Jagadānanda Paṇḍita returned to Purī with a sonnet that Advaita Ācārya had written. When Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu read it, His ecstasy was so great that all the devotees feared that the Lord would very soon pass away. The Lord’s condition was so serious that at night He would bruise and bloody His face by rubbing it against the walls. To stop this, Svarūpa Dāmodara asked Śaṅkara Paṇḍita to stay at night in the same room with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
