<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 FOREWORD</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/00_FOREWORD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/00_FOREWORD/</guid>
      <description>It is an honour to be assigned the task of welcoming and introducing this massive work by the renowned scholar, Dr. V. Varadacharya. He has been working on this theme for decades with admirable thoroughness and the present publication embodies his lectures under the noble Trust in Honour of the memory of the great savant, Prof. M. Rangacharya. The Trust was brought into existence by the highly accomplished and venerated son of the professor, the late lamented Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/01_PREFACE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/01_PREFACE/</guid>
      <description>The following pages contain an account of the origin, growth and development of the Agamas with special reference to the Vaisnava kind. They are written after a deep study of the original texts of the Vaikbanasa and Pancaratra.
Interest was aroused in me for a study of the Vaisnava Agamas, when I went through Otto Schrader&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to the Pancaratra and Ahırbudhnyasamhita and the Sanskrit introduction to the Lakshmitantra edition of the Adyar Library written by my revered father Pandit V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 PUBLISHER&#39;S NOTE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/02_PUBLISHERS_NOTE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/02_PUBLISHERS_NOTE/</guid>
      <description>The printing of this book, Agamas and South Indian Vaiṣṇavism, had almost been completed when a cruel fate intervened and snatched away Prof. M. R. Sampatkumaran. It is amidst the gloom of his demise that I am compelled to write this note
Three lectures on this subject were delivered during February 1974 by Dr. V. Varadacharı, currently of Institut Francaise D&amp;rsquo;Indologic, Pondicherry, under the auspices of Prof. M Rangacharya Memorial Trust (endowed by his dutiful son, the late Prof M R Sampatkumaran).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/03_CONTENTS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/articles/Agamas-SI-vaiShNavism/00/03_CONTENTS/</guid>
      <description>Foreword
Preface
Publisher&amp;rsquo;s Note
Contents
INTRODUCTORY
PAGES ill-v
V
-IX
XI-XII
XIII-XVI
CHAPTER I
1-42
Vedas as records of the various aspects of the Hindu way of life in ancient India-Purposes served by them (1), Religious aspect of life, nature of the deity, mantras, social and cultural aspects-supernaturalism, performance of the rituals (2-8); rise of the Agamas, which satisfied the yearnings of people to visualise the deity and offer worship (9-10), Agama and tantra, derivative significance, concept of God, as a supreme deity (11-16), Sankhya influence and concept of sakti and cosmology, liberation and the means for it (17-21), the four divisions of the Agama, Jnana, Yoga, Kriya and Carya, the purposes served by each finitized form of God, concept of idol and idol worship and construction of temples to house it (22-26); mantra, yantra, matrka, diksa, antaryaga, bahiryaga, bhuta- suddhi, mandala, nyasa, mudra-forming part of the kriya and carya divisions (27-35), exotic and endemic influences for the rise of the Agamas, home and date of the Agamas (36-42)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
