<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;४ on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/01/</guid>
      <description>FOURTH PĀDA. If it be said that some (mention) that which rests on Inference; we deny this because (the form) refers to what is contained in the simile of the body; and (this the text) shows. So far the Sūtras have given instruction about a Brahman, the enquiry into which serves as a means to obtain what is the highest good of man, viz. final release; which is the cause of the origination, and so on, of the world; which differs in nature from all non-sentient things such as the Pradhāna, and from all intelligent beings whether in the state of bondage or of release; which is free from all shadow of imperfection; which is all knowing, all powerful, has the power of realising all its purposes, comprises within itself all blessed qualities, is the inner Self of all, and possesses unbounded power and might.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/02/</guid>
      <description>But the subtle (body), on account of its capability. The elements in their fine state are what is called the &amp;lsquo;Unevolved,&amp;rsquo; and this entering into a particular condition becomes the body. It is the &amp;lsquo;Unevolved&amp;rsquo; in the particular condition of the body, which in the text under discussion is called the &amp;lsquo;Unevolved.&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;On account of its capability,&amp;rsquo; i.e. because Unevolved non-sentient matter, when assuming certain states and forms, is capable of entering on activities promoting the interest of man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/03/</guid>
      <description>To this the next Sūtra replies&amp;ndash;
(Matter in its subtle state) subserves an end, on account of its dependence on him (viz. the Supreme Person). Matter in its subtle state subserves ends, in so far only as it is dependent on the Supreme Person who is the cause of all. We by no means wish to deny unevolved matter and all its effects in themselves, but in so far only as they are maintained not to have their Self in the Supreme Person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/04/</guid>
      <description>And on account of there being no statement of its being an object of knowledge. If the text meant the Non-evolved as understood by the Sānkhyas it would refer to it as something to be known; for the Sānkhyas, who hold the theory of Release resulting from the discriminative knowledge of the Evolved, the
Non-evolved, and the soul, admit that all these are objects of knowledge. Now our text does not refer to the Un-evolved as an object of knowledge, and it cannot therefore be the Pradhāna assumed by the Sānkhyas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/05/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that (the text) declares (it); we say, not so; for the intelligent Self (is meant), on account of subject-matter. &amp;lsquo;He who has meditated on that which is without sound, without touch, without form, without decay, without taste, eternal, without smell, without beginning, without end, beyond the Great, unchangeable; is freed from the jaws of death&amp;rsquo; (Ka. Up. II, 3,15), this scriptural text, closely following on the text under discussion, represents the &amp;lsquo;Unevolved&amp;rsquo; as the object of knowledge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/06/</guid>
      <description>And of three only there is this mention and question. In the Upanishad under discussion there is mention
made of three things only as objects of knowledge&amp;ndash;the three standing to one another in the relation of means, end to be realised by those means, and persons realising,&amp;ndash;and questions are asked as to those three only. There is no mention of, nor question referring to, the Unevolved.&amp;ndash;Naciketas desirous of Release having been allowed by Death to choose three boons, chooses for his first boon that his father should be well disposed towards him&amp;ndash;without which he could not hope for spiritual welfare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/07/</guid>
      <description>And as in the case of the &amp;lsquo;Great.&amp;rsquo; In the case of the passage &amp;lsquo;Higher than the intellect is the Great Self,&amp;rsquo; we conclude from the co-ordination of &amp;rsquo;the Great&amp;rsquo; with the Self that what the text means is not the &amp;lsquo;Great&amp;rsquo; principle of the Sankhyas; analogously we conclude that the &amp;lsquo;Unevolved,&amp;rsquo; which is said to be higher than the Self, cannot be the Pradhāna of Kapila&amp;rsquo;s system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/08/</guid>
      <description>On account of there being no special characteristic; as in the case of the cup. In the discussion of the following passages also we aim only at refuting the system of the Sankhyas; not at disproving the existence and nature of Prakr̥ti, the &amp;lsquo;great&amp;rsquo; principle, the ahaṁāra, and so on, viewed as dependent on Brahman. For that they exist in this latter relation is proved by Scripture as well as Smr̥ti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/09/</guid>
      <description>But she begins with light; for thus some read in their text. The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; has assertory force. &amp;lsquo;Light&amp;rsquo; in the Sūtra means Brahman, in accordance with the meaning of the term as known from texts such as &amp;lsquo;On him the gods meditate, the light of lights&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. X, 4, 16); &amp;lsquo;That light which shines beyond heaven&amp;rsquo; (Cḥ. Up. III, 13, 7). &amp;lsquo;She begins with light&amp;rsquo; thus means &amp;lsquo;she has Brahman for her cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/10/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the teaching of formation (i.e. creation) there is no contradiction; as in the case of the honey. The &amp;lsquo;and&amp;rsquo; expresses disposal of a doubt that had arisen. There is no contradiction between the Prakr̥ti being ajā and originating from light. On account of instruction being given about the formation (kalpana), i.e. creation of the world. This interpretation of &amp;lsquo;kalpana&amp;rsquo; is in agreement with the use of the verb klip in the text, &amp;lsquo;as formerly the creator made (akalpayat) sun and moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/11/</guid>
      <description>Not from the mention of the number even, on account of the diversity and of the excess. The Vājasaneyins read in their text &amp;lsquo;He in whom the five &amp;ldquo;five-people&amp;rdquo; and the ether rest, him alone I believe to be the Self; I, who know, believe him to be Brahman&amp;rsquo; (Br̥. Up. IV, 4, 17). The doubt here arises whether this text be meant to set forth the categories as established in Kapila&amp;rsquo;s doctrine, or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/12/</guid>
      <description>The breath, and so on, on the ground of the complementary passage. We see from a complementary passage, viz. &amp;lsquo;They who know the breath of breath, the eye of the eye, the ear of the ear, the food of food, the mind of mind,&amp;rsquo; that the &amp;lsquo;five-people&amp;rsquo; are the breath, and eye, and so on, all of which have their abode in Brahman.
But, an objection is raised, while the mantra &amp;lsquo;in whom the five five-people,&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp;c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/13/</guid>
      <description>By light, food not being (mentioned in the text) of some. In the text of some, viz. the Kāṇvas, where food is not mentioned, the five-people are recognised to be the five senses, owing to the phrase &amp;lsquo;of lights&amp;rsquo; which is met with in another complementary passage. In the mantra, &amp;lsquo;him the gods worship as the light of lights,&amp;rsquo; which precedes the mantra about the &amp;lsquo;five-people,&amp;rsquo; Brahman is spoken of as the light of lights, and this suggests the idea of certain lights the activity of which depends on Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/14/</guid>
      <description>And on account of (Brahman) as described being declared to be the cause with regard to Ether, and so on. Here the philosopher who holds the Pradhāna to be the general cause comes forward with another objection. The Vedānta-texts, he says, do not teach that creation proceeds from one and the same agent only, and you therefore have no right to hold that Brahman is the sole cause of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/15/</guid>
      <description>From connexion. The fact is that Brahman intelligent, consisting of bliss, &amp;amp;c., connects itself also with the passage &amp;lsquo;Non-being was this in the beginning&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 7). For the section of the text which precedes that passage (viz. &amp;lsquo;Different from this Self consisting of understanding is the Self consisting of Bliss;&amp;ndash;he wished, may I be many;&amp;ndash;he created all whatever there is. Having created he entered into it; having entered it he became sat and tyat&amp;rsquo;) clearly refers to Brahman consisting of Bliss, which realises its purposes, creates all beings, and entering into them is the Self of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/16/</guid>
      <description>Because it denotes the world. The Sānkhya comes forward with a further objection. Although the Vedānta-texts teach an intelligent principle to be the cause of the world, they do not present to us as objects of knowledge anything that could be the cause of
the world, apart from the Pradhāna and the soul as established by the Sānkhya-system. For the Kaushītakins declare in their text, in the dialogue of Bālāki and Ajātaśatru, that none but the enjoying(individual) soul is to be known as the cause of the world, &amp;lsquo;Shall I tell you Brahman?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/17/</guid>
      <description>Should it be said that this is not so on account of the inferential marks of the individual soul and the chief vital air; we reply that this has been explained before. With reference to the plea urged by the Pūrvapakshin
that, owing to inferential marks pointing to the individual soul, and the circumstance of mention being made of the chief vital air, we must decide that the section treats of the enjoying individual soul and not of the highest Self, the Sūtra remarks that this argumentation has already been disposed of, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/18/</guid>
      <description>But Jaimini thinks that it has another purport, on account of the question and answer; and thus some also.
The &amp;lsquo;but&amp;rsquo; is meant to preclude the idea that the mention made of the individual soul enables us to understand the whole section as concerned with that soul.&amp;ndash;The teacher Jaimini is of opinion that the mention made of the individual soul has another meaning, i.e. aims at conveying the idea of what is different from the individual soul, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/19/</guid>
      <description>On account of the connected meaning of the sentences. In spite of the conclusion arrived at there may remain a suspicion that here and there in the Upanishads texts are to be met with which aim at setting forth the soul as maintained in Kapila&amp;rsquo;s system, and that hence there is no room for a being different from the individual soul and called Lord. This suspicion the Sūtra undertakes to remove, in connexion with the Maitreyi-brāhmaṇa, in the Br̥hadaraṇyaka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/20/</guid>
      <description>(It is) a mark indicating that the promissory statement is proved; thus Āśmarathya thinks. According to the teacher Āśmarathya the circumstance that terms denoting the individual soul are used to denote Brahman is a mark enabling us to infer that the promissory declaration according to which through the knowledge of one thing everything is known is well established. If the individual soul were not identical with Brahman in so far as it is the effect of Brahman, then the knowledge of the soul&amp;ndash;being something distinct from Brahman&amp;ndash;would not follow from the knowledge of the highest Self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/21/</guid>
      <description>Because (the soul) when it will depart is such; thus Auḍulomi thinks. It is wrong to maintain that the designation of Brahman by means of terms denoting the individual soul is intended to prove the truth of the declaration that through the knowledge of one thing everything is known, in so far namely as the soul is an effect of Brahman and hence one with it. For scriptural texts such as &amp;rsquo;the knowing Self is not born, it dies not&amp;rsquo; (Ka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/22/</guid>
      <description>On account of (Brahman&amp;rsquo;s) abiding (within the individual soul); thus Kāśakr̥tsna (holds). We must object likewise to the view set forth in the preceding Sūtra, viz. that Brahman is denoted by terms denoting the individual soul because that soul when departing becomes one with Brahman. For that view cannot stand the test of being submitted to definite alternatives.&amp;ndash;Is the soul&amp;rsquo;s not being such, i.e. not being Brahman, previously to its departure from the body, due to its own essential nature or to a limiting adjunct, and is it in the latter case real or unreal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/23/</guid>
      <description>(Brahman is) the material cause on account of this not being in conflict with the promissory statements and the illustrative instances. The claims raised by the atheistic Sānkhya having thus been disposed of, the theistic Sānkhya comes forward as an opponent. It must indeed be admitted, he says, that the Vedānta-texts teach the cause of the world to be an all-knowing Lord; for they attribute to that cause thought and similar characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/24/</guid>
      <description>And on account of the statement of reflection. Brahman must be held to be both causes for that reason also that texts such as &amp;lsquo;He desired, may I be many, may I grow forth,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;It thought, may I be many, may I grow forth,&amp;rsquo; declare that the creative Brahman forms the purpose of its own Self multiplying itself. The text clearly teaches that creation on Brahman&amp;rsquo;s part is preceded by the purpose &amp;lsquo;May I, and no other than I, become manifold in the shape of various non-sentient and sentient beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/25/</guid>
      <description>And on account of both being directly declared. The conclusion arrived at above is based not only on scriptural declaration, illustrative instances and statements of reflection; but in addition Scripture directly states that Brahman alone is the material as well as operative cause of the world. &amp;lsquo;What was the wood, what the tree from which they have shaped heaven and earth? You wise ones, search in your minds, whereon it stood, supporting the worlds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/26/</guid>
      <description>On account of (the Self) making itself. Of Brahman which the text had introduced as intent on creation, &amp;lsquo;He wished, may I be many&amp;rsquo; (Taitt. Up. II, 6), a subsequent text says, &amp;lsquo;That itself made its Self (II, 7), so that Brahman is represented as the object as well as the agent in the act of creation. It being the Self only which here is made many, we understand that the Self is material cause as well as operative one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/27/</guid>
      <description>Owing to modification. This means&amp;ndash;owing to the essential nature of modification (pariṇāma). The modification taught in our system is not such as to introduce imperfections into the highest Brahman, on the contrary it confers on it limitless glory. For our teaching as to Brahman&amp;rsquo;s modification is as follows.
Brahman&amp;ndash;essentially antagonistic to all evil, of uniform goodness, differing in nature from all beings other than itself, all-knowing, endowed with the power of immediately realising all its purposes, in eternal possession of all it wishes for, supremely blessed&amp;ndash;has for its body the entire universe, with all its sentient and non-sentient beings&amp;ndash;the universe being for it a plaything as it were&amp;ndash;and constitutes the Self of the Universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/28/</guid>
      <description>And because it is called the womb. Brahman is the material as well as the operative cause of the world for that reason also that certain texts call it the womb, &amp;rsquo;the maker, the Lord, the Person, Brahman, the womb&amp;rsquo; (Mu. Up. III, 1, 3); &amp;rsquo;that which the wise regard as the womb of all beings&amp;rsquo; (I, 1, 6). And that &amp;lsquo;womb&amp;rsquo; means as much as material cause, appears from the complementary passage &amp;lsquo;As a spider sends forth and draws in its threads&amp;rsquo; (I, 1, 7)&amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/rAmAnuja-sampradAyaH/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/thibaut/1/4/29/</guid>
      <description>Herewith all (texts) are explained, explained. Hereby, i.e. by the whole array of arguments set forth in the four pādas of the first adhyāya; all those particular passages of the Vedānta-texts which give instruction as to the cause of the world, are explained as meaning to set forth a Brahman all-wise, all-powerful, different in nature from all beings intelligent and non-intelligent. The repetition of the word &amp;rsquo;explained&amp;rsquo; is meant to indicate the termination of the adhyāya.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
