<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ekAnaMshA in nAstIka myth-making and implications for AstIka Paurano-Tantric history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-11-01_ekanamsha-in-nastika-myth-making-and-implications-for-astika-paurano-tantric-history/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
buddhagosha declared that the bauddha zealots should not listen to public narratives of the rAmAyaNa or mahAbhArata that the Astikas delight in. Yet, the nAstikas both jaina and bauddha have their own versions of several core narratives and branching AkhyAnas found in the canonical itihAsa and purANa literature of the Astikas. One striking feature is that their versions differ strikingly from the Astika versions. The bauddha ones, typically, are even more divergent than the jaina ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>avyakta origin mythology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-31_avyakta-origin-mythology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-31_avyakta-origin-mythology/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The two tantric upaniShads, avyakta and nR^isiMha-tApini are clear in their pA~ncharAtra affinities. Yet the saMkhya origin mythology of the avyakta is a pretty remarkable piece that is worth considering, for it is a rather distinctive expression of earliest stages of the universe. While in general concepts is similar to the thoughts expressed in other pA~ncharatra sAMkhya origin mythologies, such as the lakShmi-tantra, it different in the details. Of course it does not go into the details of the ta~nmAtras and their ontology like the account in the viShNu purANa, but its clarification of the early events in just two paragraphs is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of pA~ncharatra tantra-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-01_list-of-pancharatra-tantra-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-01_list-of-pancharatra-tantra-s/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
With the muni, the shrI vaiShNava and R’s father we have made a comprehensive list of pA~ncharAtra tantras that are supposed to have existed. We simply have little to no details of many of them and cannot say much about their existence. Of others only fragments are known from manuscripts or citations or prayoga traditions. Several purported saMhitA-s that are recorded based on citations are spurious and are seem to be vedic saMhitA-s or kalpa texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on early pAncharAtra vaiShNavism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-03-27_notes-on-early-pancharatra-vaishnavism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-03-27_notes-on-early-pancharatra-vaishnavism/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
It is likely that in the later period the vaiShNavas were ignorant on why the name pA~ncharatra came into being. This ignorance of the meaning of the name is plainly seen in the explanation provided by the prashna saMhitA and padma saMhitA of pA~ncharAtra, and the nAradIya pA~ncharAtra has only a vague memory regarding the cause of the name. The kashmirAcharyas of mahAbala paNDita’s school and vidyAraNya yati cite a number of formulae of pA~ncharAtra vaiShNavism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on the vaikhAnasa tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-16_a-note-on-the-vaikhanasa-tradition/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The vaikhAnasas appear to represent an archaic branch of vaiShNavas who are distinct from the more popular and numerous pA~ncharAtrins. The vaikhAnasas however were and are still influential in few south Indian temples including the world’s most famous shrine, venkaTAdri (Other examples being the viShNu temple of vANamAmalai). The vaikhAnasas belong to a kR^iShNa yajurvedic shAkhA founded by the descendent of the ancient R^iShi of the A~Ngirasa clan, vikhAnas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lineage of the viShNu tantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2005-08-06_the-lineage-of-the-vishnu-tantras/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
oM ugraM vIraM mahAviShNuM jvalantaM sarvatomukhaM |
nR^isiMhaM bhIShaNaM bhadraM mR^ityu-mR^ityaM namAmyahaM ||
How did these mightiest mantras of viShNu come into being? Beyond pa~ncharAtra promulgated by the chitrashikaNDins are the tantras of viShNu made apparent by the shANDilyas. The root tantra of these is the glorious viShNu yAmala. From here stem the ugra viShNu, halAyudha, ugrachakra and other formulations. After bhairava had been quenched by the draught of viShNu’s blood he asked sadAshiva to narrate the glorious vidyAs of viShNu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rAmAnujAchArya’s encounter with the chera magicians</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2005-04-26_ramanujacharyas-encounter-with-the-chera-magicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2005-04-26_ramanujacharyas-encounter-with-the-chera-magicians/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
A chera magician, who was well-versed in the bhUta and bhairava tantras had mentioned that his spells were often unable to penetrate anywhere near the vicinity of the anantapadmanAbha temple in the chera country.
Regarding this temple, one of my reliable sources offered a curious tale, though I have been unable to recover it from any other source. rAmAnuja, the arch-advocate of the qualified-advaita had gone to the regions of anantapadmanAbhA temple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lakShmI tantraM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-02-09_lakshmi-tantram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-02-09_lakshmi-tantram/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
One of the most lucid expositions of the foundational philosophy of pA~ncharatra is seen in the lecture given by lakShmI to indra in the lakShmI-tantraM (chapter 4):
1) Originally lakShmI and viShNu are conjoined in an undifferentiated form termed the “pure space”. This combination of viShNu and shrI is termed the homogeneous state which cannot be discerned and with out any fluctuations in it.
2) From time to time a minute particle comprising of a 10^-18 viShNu-shrI continuum state differentiates into action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kapilaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/kapilaH/</guid>
      <description>The genesis of the kapila figure has a complex history to it &amp;amp; is associated with 3 distinct elements:
His early (probably very 1st mention in the shruti) is in the shaiva upaniShat shvetAshvatara -1 of the late upaniShat-s associated with the yajurveda : sAMkhya as “vedAnta” and a note on evolution of shaiva yoga. This memory continues down to the much later shaiva texts as noted in the article linked above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>आखेटकम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/AkheTakam/</guid>
      <description>Both saiddhAntika shaiva-s &amp;amp; pA~ncharAtrika have a hunting ritual where the simulate either rudra or viShNu going out on an hunt (an old IA memory now lodged in a tAntrika tradition). 1 of the days recommended for it in the PR tradition is their equivalent of the dashamI following the autumnal navarAtrI which is termed the vIralakshmy-utsava. Like with the shaiva version the image of viShNu was borne on a horse &amp;amp; the procession was accompanied by an armed entourage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>एकायनशाखा</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/ekAyana-shAkHA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/ekAyana-shAkHA/</guid>
      <description>एकायनशाखा One of the enduring mysteries in the history of the vaiShNava mantra tradition is the ekAyana-shAkhA which the pa~ncharAtra affiliates itself with. It may be termed the rahasyAMnAya or the primal veda. Clearly, some exclusively focal pA~ncharAtra vaiShNava-s saw it as the root from which the &amp;ldquo;common veda&amp;rdquo; emerged. The reason they give for the secondary nature of the common veda is that it worships other deities in addition to viShNu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>वैष्णवाचमनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/vaiShNavAchamanam/</guid>
      <description>In the आचमन routine, following names of विष्णु are invoked
केशव नारायण माधव गोविन्द विष्णु मधुसूदन
त्रिविक्रम वामन श्रीधर हृषीकेश पद्मनाभ दामोदर
When do they first occur in literature?
They are found in the viShNu-bAlI/viShNvarchana mantra of a number kR^iShNayajurvedic gR^ihyaparishiShTha-s: vaikhAnasa, agniveshya and baudhAyana. This suggests that it emerged in a branch of &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo;-taittirIyaka-s who were also early sectarian vaiShNava-s. I say &amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo; because there is evidence that the vaikhAnasa-s had a now lost brAhmaNa distinct from the other taittirIyaka-s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
