<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 The Approach to the Vishnu-house on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 The Approach to the Vishnu-house on आगमे वैष्णवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 The Significance of the Temple</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/01_The_Significance_of_the_Temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/01_The_Significance_of_the_Temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The two temples of Kanchipuram mentioned in the Introduction dramatically illustrate the religious and political conflict of the time and place, each one built as the personal place of worship by an emperor. Rajasimha articulated his Maheshvara religion majestically in the architecture and sculptures of his palace for Shiva known today as the Kailasanatha Temple. About fifty years later, Nandivarman Pallavamalla responded with his more intimate Vaikuntha Perumal Temple, which is the focus of this study. But a proper understanding of either temple requires some understanding of the rich religious context of the Pallava capital as the eighth century began.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Six Concepts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/02_Six_Concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/02_Six_Concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to discuss the religious ideas that produced the emperor and his Vishnu-house, it will be helpful to examine six concepts basic to Bhagavata Dharma, as I understand it, by the eighth century. They are God as person, God as place, God as male and female, the doctrine of formation, the structure of the person, and inner vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;god-as-person&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God as Person&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who is God? Who becomes Krishna? According to Bhagavatas, God (&lt;em&gt;deva&lt;/em&gt;) has at least one thousand names. In this study six will be especially important: Narayana, Vasudeva, Bhagavan, Vishnu, Hari, and Krishna.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 The Poem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/03_The_Poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/03_The_Poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original impetus for this study was Tirumangai’s poem about the Parameccuravinnagaram (&lt;em&gt;PT&lt;/em&gt; 2.9). His unique division between God in the first two lines of the stanza and emperor in the second two, and the complementary unique division in the temple between God as the vimana and king in the dynastic history on the prakara wall form the germ of this extended project. This chapter focuses on the poem, and the next chapter on Nandivarman Pallavamalla’s career. These two will prepare us for the Vishnu-house itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 The Emperor’s Career Portrayed on the Prakara Wall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/04_The_Emperors_Career_Portrayed_on_the/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_vaiShNavaH/pAncharAtrAgamaH/meta/articles/dennis-hudson_vaikuNTha-permual-kAnchI/01_The_Approach_to_the_Vishnu-house/04_The_Emperors_Career_Portrayed_on_the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-career-of-nandivarman-pallavamalla&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Career of Nandivarman Pallavamalla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 731 the “emperor of Pallava kings in the Pallava lineage” died after a three-year reign. He has been identified as Parameshvaravarman II (728–731), a descendent of Paramesvaravarman I (672–700) through Narasimhavarman Rajasimha (700–728). His death may have been connected to the invasion of Kanchipuram by the Chalukya crown prince Vikramaditya II.1 The Sanskrit praise poem (&lt;em&gt;prashasti&lt;/em&gt;) of a grant by Nandivarman ca. 752 says the deceased ruler’s father was Rajasimha, an emperor famous as a Supreme Maheshvara (&lt;em&gt;paramamaheshvara&lt;/em&gt;) piously devoted to Brahmins (&lt;em&gt;parabrahmanyah&lt;/em&gt;) (&lt;em&gt;SII&lt;/em&gt; 2: 366, line 17). This title means Rajasimha had received consecration (&lt;em&gt;diksha&lt;/em&gt;) according to the branch of Shaiva Agama known in his time as Shaiva Siddhanta. Rajasimha’s sons did not leave an undisputed lineal descendant, and political anarchy followed. Since no Pallavan in Kanchipuram could claim undisputed succession, some members of the court went a long distance to find one to restore the “pure” line descending from Simhavarman II, who had reigned ca. 535–580. They found such a person in a twelve-year-old boy, the youngest son of Hiranyavarman, who had descended from Simhavarman II through his second son, Bhima. Bhima had left Kanchipuram to establish his own court, and Hiranya was his descendent in the fifth generation. He was considered “pure” on his father and mother’s sides and was a worshiper of Vishnu. Hiranya could not take up the position in Kanchipuram, however, but he allowed the fourth of his four Malla sons to assume the position. Hiranya’s Malla sons, it appears, were those born to his first wife; they continued the “purity” of lineage signified by the title of Malla, which means “wrestler.” This Malla son was named Pallava, or Pallavamalla. As a descendent of Simhavarman, the boy qualified as “purified” (&lt;em&gt;parisuddha&lt;/em&gt;) in both his paternal and maternal clans and, in addition, he was willing to leave his father’s court and go to Kanchipuram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
